1
00:02:30,940 --> 00:02:35,050
沒有汽油

2
00:03:29,760 --> 00:03:31,840
小姑娘
Little girl?

3
00:03:32,880 --> 00:03:34,590
我是警察
I'm a policeman.

4
00:03:34,880 --> 00:03:36,870
小姑娘
Little girl.

5
00:03:40,660 --> 00:03:43,650
不要怕　好嗎
Don't be afraid, OK?

6
00:03:45,970 --> 00:03:48,170
小姑娘
Little girl.

7
00:04:23,820 --> 00:04:25,480
YYeTs人人影視誠意奉獻

8
00:04:27,620 --> 00:04:29,290
翻譯 海因裡希

9
00:04:30,900 --> 00:04:32,720
翻譯 Tiberius

10
00:04:32,730 --> 00:04:34,590
翻譯 NaryKing

11
00:04:37,950 --> 00:04:39,150
時間軸 之間

12
00:04:39,150 --> 00:04:40,250
校對 海因裡希

13
00:04:40,250 --> 00:04:41,380
後期/特效 WiLL

14
00:04:41,380 --> 00:04:42,550
監製 海因裡希

15
00:04:42,560 --> 00:04:45,560
CHD版個人美化微修：字幕雷哥

16
00:04:54,150 --> 00:04:59,000
走

17
00:04:54,900 --> 00:04:59,000
肉

18
00:04:55,250 --> 00:04:59,000
行屍

19
00:04:55,250 --> 00:04:59,000
『第一季 第一集』

20
00:05:01,050 --> 00:05:03,330
男女之間有什麼差別
What's the difference between men and women?

21
00:05:03,410 --> 00:05:06,660
-你開玩笑嗎　-不　認真的
- Is this a joke? - No, serious.

22
00:05:07,190 --> 00:05:10,100
我從沒見過一個女人懂得關燈
I never met a woman who knew how to turn off a light.

23
00:05:10,180 --> 00:05:13,230
她們生來只知道開燈　從來不懂關燈
They're born thinking the switch only goes one way.

24
00:05:14,930 --> 00:05:17,480
她們一離開一個房間就會被「閃瞎」
They're struck blind the second they leave a room.

25
00:05:17,480 --> 00:05:21,300
每個我曾給過家裡鑰匙的女人都這樣　我發誓
I mean every woman, I ever let have a key, I swear to God.

26
00:05:21,440 --> 00:05:24,320
比方說我一到家　整棟房子燈火通明
It's like I... come home, house all lit up,

27
00:05:25,440 --> 00:05:27,690
而我的任務呢　顯而易見…
and my job, apparently because...

28
00:05:28,200 --> 00:05:30,170
因為我是男性
because my chromosomes happen to be different

29
00:05:30,170 --> 00:05:32,140
所以我得跑遍整棟房子
cause I then gotta walk through that house,

30
00:05:32,230 --> 00:05:34,880
把所有她沒關的燈全關了
turn off every single light this chick left on.

31
00:05:34,940 --> 00:05:36,730
-是麼　-當然了　哥們
- Is that right? - Yeah, baby.

32
00:05:37,860 --> 00:05:40,600
好吧　肖恩神父要開始布道了
Alright, Reverend Shane's preaching to you now, boy.

33
00:05:41,980 --> 00:05:44,520
就是那個小妞
The same chick, mind ya.

34
00:05:44,600 --> 00:05:47,210
又在念叨全球變暖問題
She'll bitch about global warming.

35
00:05:47,300 --> 00:05:50,580
肖恩神父要開始
You see, this is -- this is when Reverend Shane wants to

36
00:05:50,580 --> 00:05:53,870
引用蓋伊福音了
quote from the Guy Gospel and say "Um, darling?"

37
00:05:54,100 --> 00:05:57,640
「親愛的　要是你和這星球上的其他小妞」
"maybe you, and every other pair of boobs on this planet

38
00:05:57,640 --> 00:06:00,930
「懂得開了燈就要關」
just figured out that the light switch see, goes both ways,"

39
00:06:00,930 --> 00:06:03,520
「那全球變暖可能就沒這麼嚴重了」
maybe we wouldn't have so much global warming."

40
00:06:03,570 --> 00:06:05,790
-你這麼說嗎　-對
- You say that? - Yeah.

41
00:06:05,830 --> 00:06:08,010
不管怎樣　還算很客氣
Anyway, uh... Polite version...

42
00:06:08,480 --> 00:06:11,260
但結果呢
Still man, that... that earns me this.

43
00:06:11,320 --> 00:06:14,920
她丟給你一副厭惡的嘴臉　你肯定想像不到
This look and loathing you would not believe.

44
00:06:15,070 --> 00:06:17,120
驅魔人一般的聲音蹦出來
And that's when the exorcist voice pops out.

45
00:06:17,180 --> 00:06:19,950
「你怎麼跟我那該死的老爸似的」
"You sound just like my damn father.

46
00:06:20,210 --> 00:06:22,350
「總是嘮叨電費」
"Always,always yelling about the power bill,"

47
00:06:22,350 --> 00:06:24,500
「要我關燈」
"telling me to turn off the damn lights."

48
00:06:24,760 --> 00:06:25,820
你怎麼說
What do you say to that?

49
00:06:25,890 --> 00:06:27,440
我知道我想說什麼
You know what I wanna say.

50
00:06:27,520 --> 00:06:29,120
我想說　「賤人」
I wanna say,"Bitch, you mean to tell me

51
00:06:29,120 --> 00:06:30,720
「原來早就有人和你說過了」
you've been hearing this your entire　life

52
00:06:30,770 --> 00:06:33,960
「你卻還是蠢到學不會關燈」
"and you are still too damn stupid to learn how to turn off a switch?

53
00:06:36,020 --> 00:06:39,050
其實我沒有這麼說
You know... I don't actually say that,tho.

54
00:06:39,350 --> 00:06:42,440
-那樣就慘了　-用那種
- That would be bad. - Yeah, go with the uh...

55
00:06:42,520 --> 00:06:43,570
客氣的說法
the polite version there...

56
00:06:43,640 --> 00:06:46,560
-還真明智　-可不是　長官
- Very wise. - Yes, sir.

57
00:06:51,240 --> 00:06:53,000
你和洛莉怎麼樣了　夥計
So how's it with Lori, man?

58
00:06:54,220 --> 00:06:56,580
她很不錯　懂得關燈
She's good. She's good at turning off lights.

59
00:06:56,660 --> 00:06:57,870
真不錯
Really good.

60
00:06:58,010 --> 00:07:00,310
不知道為何我們還是會懷疑
I don't know why sometimes we guess.

61
00:07:00,470 --> 00:07:02,350
我也不想
Not what I meant.

62
00:07:05,680 --> 00:07:07,080
我們處得不太好
We didn't have a great night.

63
00:07:07,150 --> 00:07:12,430
聽著　夥計　我可能是缺乏幽默感　但我會盡力
Look, man, I may have a... fail to amuse with my sermon, but I did try.

64
00:07:12,930 --> 00:07:15,380
至少你能說說話
The least you could do is speak.

65
00:07:16,460 --> 00:07:20,180
她總這麼說　「說話」
That's what she always says: "Speak".

66
00:07:20,450 --> 00:07:22,830
「說話」
"Speak".

67
00:07:23,300 --> 00:07:25,380
她這麼說我還保持緘默
You think I was the most closed mouth

68
00:07:25,380 --> 00:07:27,470
你大概覺得我遜斃了
son of a bitch you'd ever hear to hear her tell it.

69
00:07:29,850 --> 00:07:32,710
你有說過你的想法麼
Do you express your thoughts?

70
00:07:32,790 --> 00:07:35,940
有分享過你的感受之類的麼
You share your feelings and that kind of stuff?

71
00:07:37,320 --> 00:07:38,790
問題是
The thing is...

72
00:07:41,230 --> 00:07:43,630
不管我怎麼嘗試
lately whenever I try...

73
00:07:43,920 --> 00:07:48,430
她都很不耐煩　好像她根本不想聽
everything I say makes her impatient,like she didn't want to hear it after all.

74
00:07:49,840 --> 00:07:51,380
感覺就好像…
It's like she's...

75
00:07:51,770 --> 00:07:54,940
她總會無緣無故地生我氣
pissed at me all the time, and I don't know why.

76
00:07:56,090 --> 00:07:58,690
聽著　夥計　夫妻間都會這樣
Look, man, that's just shit couples go through.

77
00:07:58,810 --> 00:08:01,250
總得經歷這段時期
Nah, it's... It's a phase.

78
00:08:05,410 --> 00:08:07,590
知道她今早說的最後一句話嗎
Last thing she said this morning?

79
00:08:08,070 --> 00:08:11,640
她說「有時我甚至懷疑你根本不在乎我們」
Sometimes I wonder if you even care about us at all.

80
00:08:13,350 --> 00:08:16,550
她當著孩子的面就這麼說
She said that in front of our kid.

81
00:08:17,750 --> 00:08:20,090
想想看他去學校後會怎麼想
Imagine going to school with that in your head.

82
00:08:24,080 --> 00:08:26,710
男女之間的區別嗎
Difference between men and women?

83
00:08:28,070 --> 00:08:30,970
我絕不會對她說這麼殘酷的話
I would never say something that cruel to her.

84
00:08:31,620 --> 00:08:34,480
尤其是在卡爾面前
Certainly not in front of Carl.

85
00:08:40,000 --> 00:08:42,200
所有空閒單位　林肯縣發生高速追捕
All available units, high speed pursuit

86
00:08:42,200 --> 00:08:44,410
請即刻到現場增援
in progress Lincoln county units request local assistance.

87
00:08:44,640 --> 00:08:48,840
18號公路以南　GTAAD記錄 217 243以西
Highway 18 south GTAAD W217 243.

88
00:08:48,970 --> 00:08:51,190
高度戒備
Proceed with extreme caution.

89
00:09:03,320 --> 00:09:05,250
嫌犯為兩名高加索白人
Suspects are two male Caucasians.

90
00:09:05,360 --> 00:09:07,140
通知各單位　嫌犯已向警方開火
Be advised, they have fired on police officers.

91
00:09:07,210 --> 00:09:10,030
一位林肯縣警受傷
One Lincoln county officer is wounded.

92
00:09:19,780 --> 00:09:21,860
一組和三組注意
Unit 1, Unit 3.

93
00:09:22,020 --> 00:09:24,030
85州際公路以西2英里處
18, 2 miles west of Interstate 85

94
00:09:24,030 --> 00:09:26,050
使用林肯縣警無線電保持聯絡
and we'll patch in Linclon County Sheriff radio.

95
00:09:27,510 --> 00:09:30,530
收到　還有5分鐘趕到18號公路口
Roger that. We're 5 minutes out on the route 18 intersection.

96
00:09:31,580 --> 00:09:35,080
一組三組注意　到達現場後設立路障
Dispatch, Unit 1, Unit 3, we are 10-97 in code 100.

97
00:09:35,200 --> 00:09:38,050
85州際公路　18號公路　請下達指令
Highway 18, 85 Interstate, please advise.

98
00:09:54,960 --> 00:09:58,150
聽著像是那些蠢貨被追得東逃西竄
Sounds like they're chasing those idiots up and down every back road we got.

99
00:09:58,320 --> 00:10:00,160
我們可得拍個錄像傳網上去
Hey, we'll get them on one of those video shows, you know,

100
00:10:00,210 --> 00:10:02,040
弄個「最瘋狂警匪追逐」視頻　你覺得呢
like World's craziest police chases, what do you think?

101
00:10:02,100 --> 00:10:04,350
我覺得你該專心點　里昂
What I think, Leon, is that you need to stay focused.

102
00:10:04,420 --> 00:10:07,070
別被迎面來的子彈給崩了
Make sure you got a round in the chamber and your safety off.

103
00:10:14,520 --> 00:10:17,000
那樣視頻可就拉風得多了
Would be kind of cool to get on one of them shows.

104
00:11:04,280 --> 00:11:05,880
真他媽見鬼
Holy shit.

105
00:11:28,190 --> 00:11:30,210
-小心有槍　-放下槍
- Gun, gun, gun. - Put it down!

106
00:11:30,280 --> 00:11:31,540
快放下槍
Put the gun down!

107
00:12:05,210 --> 00:12:07,730
-瑞克　-我沒事
- Rick! - I'm alright!

108
00:12:12,950 --> 00:12:15,570
我看到你被擊中了　嚇死我了
I saw you get tagged, man, it scared the hell out of me.

109
00:12:16,210 --> 00:12:18,170
我也是
Me too.

110
00:12:18,240 --> 00:12:19,760
那見鬼丫的居然開槍打我
Son of a bitch shot me.

111
00:12:19,850 --> 00:12:21,280
你相信麼
You believe that?

112
00:12:21,330 --> 00:12:23,610
到時給你件新防彈衣
We'll get you a new vest.

113
00:12:23,690 --> 00:12:24,910
可不是
Yeah.

114
00:12:26,260 --> 00:12:28,710
肖恩　你可不能告訴洛莉
Shane, you do not tell Lori that happened.

115
00:12:28,810 --> 00:12:30,390
絕對不行
Ever.

116
00:12:30,480 --> 00:12:31,240
你明白嗎
You understand...

117
00:12:33,670 --> 00:12:36,210
瑞克　不　不要
Rick! Rick! No, no, no!

118
00:12:38,790 --> 00:12:41,920
不　他受傷了
No, no, no, no... He's hurt!

119
00:12:42,630 --> 00:12:43,860
里昂
Leon!

120
00:12:43,940 --> 00:12:45,700
快去叫救護車
You get that ambulance down here,

121
00:12:45,700 --> 00:12:47,470
快去叫救護車　說有警官受傷　快去
you tell them there's an officer down, you do it now!

122
00:12:47,640 --> 00:12:51,440
你看著我　保持清醒　好嗎
Shh, shh, shh, hey, you look at me, stay with me, you hear me?

123
00:12:51,550 --> 00:12:55,260
沒事　保持清醒　聽見了嗎
Okay. Shh, shh, stay with me, you hear me?

124
00:12:55,330 --> 00:12:59,160
好嗎　保持清醒
Shh, shh, ok? You stay with me, ok?

125
00:13:16,390 --> 00:13:20,360
夥計　我們還在這裡
Hey, bud... We're still here.

126
00:13:21,840 --> 00:13:23,990
每天都在
We're still hanging in.

127
00:13:27,620 --> 00:13:29,210
聽著　我很抱歉　夥計
Look, I'm sorry, man.

128
00:13:29,350 --> 00:13:32,410
我每次來你都是這副德行
I'm mean watching the same crap every time I come in here.

129
00:13:35,900 --> 00:13:38,810
這是大家一起買的…
Everybody pitched in on these. They uh...

130
00:13:38,880 --> 00:13:41,950
他們要我帶過來　致以他們的問候…
They wanted me to bring them down, they send their love and they just...

131
00:13:41,980 --> 00:13:44,710
他們希望你快點好起來
They hope you come back real soon.

132
00:13:47,840 --> 00:13:51,360
總台的琳達和戴安　這是她們選的
Linda and Diane from dispatch, they picked these out.

133
00:13:52,030 --> 00:13:54,340
你應該能看出來吧
You probably could tell, hmm?

134
00:13:55,850 --> 00:13:58,370
我就放在桌上了　好嗎
I'll just set this on your side table, ok?

135
00:14:08,220 --> 00:14:11,360
這還不是一般的花瓶
That vase has something special.

136
00:14:11,420 --> 00:14:12,490
老實說
Fess up.

137
00:14:12,710 --> 00:14:15,290
你是不是從吉恩奶奶家偷來的
Did you steal it from your Grandma Gene's house.

138
00:14:15,760 --> 00:14:18,910
但願你沒碰她收藏的湯匙
I hope you left her that spoon collection.

139
00:14:26,410 --> 00:14:28,000
肖恩
Shane?

140
00:14:31,710 --> 00:14:34,020
肖恩　你在廁所嗎
Shane, you in the john?

141
00:15:51,700 --> 00:15:53,900
護士　快來
Nurse, help.

142
00:15:55,190 --> 00:15:58,450
護士　來幫幫我
Nurse. Help!

143
00:18:29,190 --> 00:18:30,450
不要開門　裡面有殭屍

144
00:23:47,730 --> 00:23:50,060
洛莉
Lori!

145
00:23:52,020 --> 00:23:53,620
洛莉
Lori!

146
00:24:00,380 --> 00:24:04,710
卡爾　卡爾
Carl! Carl!

147
00:24:09,560 --> 00:24:12,230
洛莉　卡爾
Lori! Carl!

148
00:24:26,490 --> 00:24:29,330
洛莉　卡爾
Lori! Carl!

149
00:24:46,570 --> 00:24:48,550
這是真的嗎
Is this real?

150
00:24:48,870 --> 00:24:50,340
我真的在這嗎
Am I here?

151
00:24:56,680 --> 00:24:59,240
醒過來
Wake, wake up!

152
00:26:13,260 --> 00:26:14,490
爸爸
Daddy, daddy!

153
00:26:14,560 --> 00:26:17,050
卡爾
Carl... Carl?

154
00:26:17,300 --> 00:26:19,340
-我找到你了…　-爸爸　我搞定這混球了
- I found you... - Daddy, I got this sumbitch.

155
00:26:19,390 --> 00:26:21,320
我要敲死他
I'm gonna smack him dead.

156
00:26:28,550 --> 00:26:29,580
他說什麼了嗎
He say something?

157
00:26:29,670 --> 00:26:30,810
我好像聽見他說了什麼
I thought I heard him say something.

158
00:26:30,880 --> 00:26:33,370
-他叫我卡爾　-孩子　你也知道他們不說話
- He called me Carl. - Son, you know they don't talk.

159
00:26:33,590 --> 00:26:37,550
先生　你為什麼綁著繃帶
Hey, mister! What's that bandage for?

160
00:26:38,000 --> 00:26:41,040
-什麼　-你受了什麼傷
- What? - What kind of wound?

161
00:26:42,030 --> 00:26:44,510
快回答我　見鬼的
You answer me, damn you!

162
00:26:44,640 --> 00:26:46,500
你受了什麼傷
What's your wound?

163
00:26:47,420 --> 00:26:49,550
快說
You tell me!

164
00:26:49,690 --> 00:26:52,580
不然我就殺了你
Or I will kill you.

165
00:27:15,520 --> 00:27:17,810
我們幫你換了繃帶
Got that bandage changed out.

166
00:27:17,920 --> 00:27:20,060
已經髒得不行了
It was pretty rank.

167
00:27:20,310 --> 00:27:21,710
那個傷
What was?

168
00:27:21,820 --> 00:27:23,890
是什麼傷
The wound?

169
00:27:24,060 --> 00:27:25,980
-槍傷　-槍傷
- Gun shot. - Gun shot?

170
00:27:27,050 --> 00:27:29,910
還有其他什麼嗎
What else? Anything?

171
00:27:30,000 --> 00:27:32,510
光是槍傷還不夠慘嗎
Gun shot ain't enough?

172
00:27:33,730 --> 00:27:38,330
聽好了　我問你答　規矩知不知道
Look, I ask and you answer, It's common courtesy, right?

173
00:27:41,930 --> 00:27:44,890
你有沒被咬
Did you get bit?

174
00:27:46,770 --> 00:27:48,000
-咬　-咬
- Bit? - Bit.

175
00:27:48,070 --> 00:27:49,650
咬過　還是被抓過
Chewed. Maybe scratch?

176
00:27:49,680 --> 00:27:51,740
任何諸如此類
Anything like that.

177
00:27:52,160 --> 00:27:54,660
沒　我被槍打了
No,I got shot.

178
00:27:54,750 --> 00:27:57,250
就我所知　只有槍傷
Just shot, as far as I know.

179
00:28:01,530 --> 00:28:03,670
讓我量下
Hey... Just let me...

180
00:28:06,350 --> 00:28:07,930
感覺涼多了
Feels cooler now.

181
00:28:08,420 --> 00:28:10,960
發燒的話你這會就沒命了
Fever would have killed you by now.

182
00:28:11,210 --> 00:28:12,790
我覺得我沒有燒
I don't think I have one.

183
00:28:12,910 --> 00:28:15,780
那是你運氣好
Be hard to miss.

184
00:28:20,440 --> 00:28:23,970
好好看看這刀有多鋒利
Take a moment, eh? Look how sharp it is.

185
00:28:24,360 --> 00:28:29,510
你要做傻事　我就用這個殺了你　我說到做到
You try anything... I will kill you with it,and don't you think I won't.

186
00:28:41,030 --> 00:28:42,690
等你能動彈了就下床
Come on up when you're able.

187
00:28:46,650 --> 00:28:48,960
走
Come on.

188
00:29:18,570 --> 00:29:23,170
這裡是弗雷和辛迪·德雷克的家
This place... It's Fred and Cindy Drake's.

189
00:29:23,730 --> 00:29:25,400
從沒見過
Never met them.

190
00:29:25,480 --> 00:29:28,290
我來過　這是他們的家
I've been here.This is their place

191
00:29:28,450 --> 00:29:31,040
我們到時就沒人
It was empty when we got here.

192
00:29:33,690 --> 00:29:35,400
別動它
Don't do that.

193
00:29:35,500 --> 00:29:37,410
他們被光引過來
They'll see the light.

194
00:29:37,500 --> 00:29:39,990
他們的數量比平時更多了
There's more of them out there than usual.

195
00:29:40,080 --> 00:29:43,010
之前我真不該開槍
I never should have fired that gun today.

196
00:29:43,370 --> 00:29:46,590
槍聲把他們都引來了　現在滿大街都是
The sound draws them,now they're all over the street.

197
00:29:47,040 --> 00:29:49,620
真蠢啊　居然用槍
Stupid... using a gun...

198
00:29:50,830 --> 00:29:53,310
一切都發生得太快
It all happened so fast...

199
00:29:53,630 --> 00:29:57,130
-我都沒想　-你今天槍殺了個人
- I didn't think. - You shot that man today.

200
00:29:57,390 --> 00:29:58,670
人
Man?

201
00:29:58,740 --> 00:29:59,540
不系淫
No man...

202
00:29:59,600 --> 00:30:02,290
你剛說的那是什麼渾話
What the hell was that out of your mouth just now?

203
00:30:02,340 --> 00:30:04,360
-那不是個人　-你用槍打了他
- It wasn't a man. - You shot him.

204
00:30:04,440 --> 00:30:06,230
就大街上　門口　有個人
In this street,out front,a man.

205
00:30:06,270 --> 00:30:09,560
看來你要戴眼鏡了　那是行屍
For him, you need glasses, that was a walker.

206
00:30:09,640 --> 00:30:11,410
得
Come on.

207
00:30:11,690 --> 00:30:14,170
坐下　別摔了
Sit down,before you fall down.

208
00:30:15,750 --> 00:30:17,940
給　吃吧
Here. Eat.

209
00:30:20,150 --> 00:30:23,750
爸爸　禱告
Daddy... Blessing...

210
00:30:25,150 --> 00:30:26,650
哦對
Yeah.

211
00:30:39,430 --> 00:30:43,360
天上的父　我們衷心讚美您賜予我們食物…
Father,we thank thee for this food... Thy blessings...

212
00:30:43,650 --> 00:30:46,780
祈求您在天上　庇佑我們熬過這瘋狂的時日
We ask you to watch over us in these crazy days.

213
00:30:46,850 --> 00:30:48,310
-阿門　-阿門
- Amen. - Amen.

214
00:30:55,030 --> 00:30:57,600
這位先生　你究竟知不知道外面發生了什麼
Hey, mister, do you even know what is going on?

215
00:30:57,750 --> 00:31:00,070
我今天剛醒
I woke up today.

216
00:31:00,440 --> 00:31:02,550
在醫院裡
In a hospital.

217
00:31:03,570 --> 00:31:05,740
然後回到家　就這些
Came home, that's all I know.

218
00:31:09,210 --> 00:31:12,530
-但你不知道那些死人吧　-不　我看見很多
- But you know about the dead people, right? - Yeah, I saw a lot of that.

219
00:31:13,330 --> 00:31:15,830
裝卸區遍地都是　還有卡車上
Out on the loading dock, hauling trucks.

220
00:31:16,090 --> 00:31:19,810
不不不　不是這些死了的　是那些還在走的
No... Not the one's they put down... The one's they didn't.

221
00:31:19,910 --> 00:31:22,080
行屍
The walkers.

222
00:31:22,170 --> 00:31:24,290
就像我今天開槍放倒的那個
Like the one I shot today.

223
00:31:24,350 --> 00:31:26,140
因為他就要扒了你
Cause he would have ripped into you.

224
00:31:26,210 --> 00:31:29,800
要吃了你　至少從你身上挖塊肉
Try to eat you, take him some flesh at least.

225
00:31:29,980 --> 00:31:34,870
如果這是你頭一回聽說　我知道聽起來肯定很…
But I guess if this is the first you're hearing, I know how it must sound...

226
00:31:37,690 --> 00:31:40,980
-他們都在外面的大街上嗎　-對
- They're out there now, in the street? - Yeah.

227
00:31:41,140 --> 00:31:43,600
有時他們在夜裡反而更活躍
They're even more active after dark sometimes.

228
00:31:44,030 --> 00:31:47,950
或許是氣溫低了　該死　估計還是我白天拿槍惹得禍
Maybe it's the cool air or... Hell, maybe it's just me firing up that gun today.

229
00:31:48,770 --> 00:31:51,870
但只要我們保持安靜就很安全
But we'll be fine long as we stay quiet.

230
00:31:51,920 --> 00:31:55,060
到早上就應該都走光了
Probably wander off by morning.

231
00:31:56,560 --> 00:31:58,830
聽好
Well,listen...

232
00:31:58,900 --> 00:32:02,750
我就說一件事　別被咬
One thing I do know... Don't you get bit!

233
00:32:03,340 --> 00:32:06,520
我們那會看見你的繃帶　所以才怕的
We saw your bandage and that's why we were afraid of.

234
00:32:07,300 --> 00:32:09,200
咬一口就能要你的命
Bites kill you.

235
00:32:09,280 --> 00:32:11,120
那燒　能直接把你給燒化了
The fever... burns you out.

236
00:32:11,210 --> 00:32:14,120
可再過那麼一會
But then after a while...

237
00:32:14,720 --> 00:32:16,830
你就又活過來了
You come back.

238
00:32:21,880 --> 00:32:23,950
親眼見過
Seen it happen...

239
00:32:29,110 --> 00:32:30,170
好了
Come on...

240
00:32:38,590 --> 00:32:41,890
卡爾　是你兒子嗎
Carl... He your son?

241
00:32:42,980 --> 00:32:46,180
威廉　他今天說過這名字
William. He said his name today...

242
00:32:47,700 --> 00:32:51,100
他還小　比你兒子還小
He's a little younger... than your boy.

243
00:32:51,380 --> 00:32:53,840
跟他媽媽在一起嗎
And he's with his mother?

244
00:32:54,960 --> 00:32:57,110
我希望是
I hope so.

245
00:32:57,960 --> 00:33:00,180
-爸　-嗯
- Dad? - Yeah?

246
00:33:01,890 --> 00:33:03,750
問過他了沒
Did you ask him?

247
00:33:06,420 --> 00:33:09,270
你的槍傷　我跟我兒子打了個小賭
Your gun shot... We got a little bet going.

248
00:33:09,330 --> 00:33:13,340
我兒子說你是個搶銀行的
My boy say you're a... bank robber...

249
00:33:13,890 --> 00:33:16,490
還真猜中了
Yeah...That's me.

250
00:33:16,810 --> 00:33:19,820
著名美國公敵　銀行搶劫犯

251
00:33:16,810 --> 00:33:19,820
就像狄靈傑·卡普一樣
Deadly as Dillinger Kapow.

252
00:33:20,470 --> 00:33:22,600
其實我是縣警
Sheriff's deputy

253
00:33:28,620 --> 00:33:30,480
沒事的　爸爸在
Hey, it's ok, daddy's here.

254
00:33:30,570 --> 00:33:32,500
沒什麼
It's nothing.

255
00:33:32,590 --> 00:33:35,390
肯定是當中一個撞到了輛車
One of them must've bumped a car...

256
00:33:35,470 --> 00:33:37,170
你肯定嗎
You sure?

257
00:33:37,250 --> 00:33:39,480
以前出過這事
Happened once before.

258
00:33:39,700 --> 00:33:42,470
響了一陣
Went off a few minutes.

259
00:33:43,780 --> 00:33:46,350
熄燈去　德韋恩
Get the light,Dwayne.

260
00:33:59,340 --> 00:34:01,940
就那輛藍的　街那頭
It's the blue one, down the street.

261
00:34:02,040 --> 00:34:04,200
跟上次一樣
Same one as last time.

262
00:34:04,280 --> 00:34:06,480
我覺得我們沒事
I think we're ok.

263
00:34:09,150 --> 00:34:12,000
那個動靜　會不會把他們都招來
That noise... Will it bring more of them?

264
00:34:12,480 --> 00:34:14,610
現在什麼都做不了
Nothing to do about it now.

265
00:34:15,290 --> 00:34:18,820
只有等到明天他們都散了
Just have to wait 'em out till morning.

266
00:34:22,050 --> 00:34:23,820
她在那兒
She's here.

267
00:34:24,190 --> 00:34:25,110
別看
Don't look.

268
00:34:25,190 --> 00:34:27,540
離窗子遠點
Get away from the windows.

269
00:34:28,230 --> 00:34:30,030
我說了趕緊走　快
I said go! Come on!

270
00:34:36,740 --> 00:34:38,750
好了 安靜
Come on, quiet.

271
00:35:01,900 --> 00:35:03,660
好了　給
It's ok, here.

272
00:35:04,020 --> 00:35:05,580
抱著枕頭哭吧
Cry into the pillow.

273
00:35:05,650 --> 00:35:07,030
記得不
Can you remember?

274
00:35:47,370 --> 00:35:50,200
她
She, uh...

275
00:35:50,400 --> 00:35:53,530
她在另一間屋裡死了　就在床上
She died in the other room, on that bed...

276
00:35:56,250 --> 00:36:00,780
我什麼都做不了　那個燒…
Nothin' I can do about it here... That fever, man...

277
00:36:02,500 --> 00:36:05,080
她的皮膚燙得跟火爐似的
Her skin gave off heat like a furnace...

278
00:36:10,720 --> 00:36:16,050
我早該放倒她的　但是…
Should have put her down, I should have put her down, I know that, but...

279
00:36:18,320 --> 00:36:21,130
我就是下不了決心…
You know what... I just didn't have it in me...

280
00:36:25,930 --> 00:36:28,100
她是我兒子他娘親啊
She's the mother of my child.

281
00:36:54,280 --> 00:36:56,480
你肯定嗎　他們都死了
You sure? They're dead.

282
00:36:56,620 --> 00:36:59,430
必須得問　至少得再問一次
They have to ask, at least one more time.

283
00:36:59,490 --> 00:37:01,360
他們都死了
They're dead.

284
00:37:01,430 --> 00:37:03,670
除了腦裡邊還有點東西
Except for something in the brain.

285
00:37:03,730 --> 00:37:06,160
這就是為什麼必須打頭
That's why it's gotta be the head.

286
00:37:30,420 --> 00:37:32,420
沒事吧
You alright?

287
00:37:33,570 --> 00:37:35,950
讓我喘口氣
Need a moment

288
00:37:40,740 --> 00:37:41,920
他們還活著
They're alive.

289
00:37:42,000 --> 00:37:43,610
我老婆和兒子 
My wife and son.

290
00:37:43,690 --> 00:37:45,640
至少走的時候還活著
At least they were when they left.

291
00:37:45,750 --> 00:37:47,560
你怎麼知道
How can you know?

292
00:37:47,700 --> 00:37:48,880
看看這地方
By the look of this place...

293
00:37:49,010 --> 00:37:51,500
臥室裡有空的抽屜
I found empty drawers in the bedroom.

294
00:37:51,580 --> 00:37:53,620
他們帶了衣服　不多
They packed some clothes.Not a lot.

295
00:37:53,710 --> 00:37:55,200
但是足夠路上用
But enough to travel.

296
00:37:55,270 --> 00:37:58,910
也可能是有人闖進來偷走了吧
You know anybody could've broken in here and stolen clothes, right?

297
00:37:59,170 --> 00:38:01,430
看見那些牆上的相框了麼
You see the framed photos on the walls?

298
00:38:02,530 --> 00:38:03,580
我就沒見
Neither do I.

299
00:38:03,660 --> 00:38:06,660
哪個小偷會要那個
Some random thief took those too, you think?

300
00:38:10,010 --> 00:38:12,820
我的照片簿　全家福　都沒了
My photo albums, family pictures, all gone.

301
00:38:14,690 --> 00:38:17,310
相冊
Photo albums...

302
00:38:22,270 --> 00:38:24,990
我老婆　也是一個樣
My wife... Same thing...

303
00:38:26,380 --> 00:38:30,490
我當時在收拾生存裝備　她卻拿什麼相冊
Here I am, packing survival gear, she's grabbing photo albums....

304
00:38:35,750 --> 00:38:37,640
我估計他們會在亞特蘭大
They're in Atlanta, I'll bet.

305
00:38:38,230 --> 00:38:39,750
對了
That's right.

306
00:38:40,730 --> 00:38:42,870
-為什麼是那　-避難所
- Why there? - Refugee settle.

307
00:38:42,950 --> 00:38:46,090
很大　至少廣播停掉前一直這麼說
Huge, when they said it, before the broadcast stopped.

308
00:38:46,170 --> 00:38:51,020
軍方保護　有吃　有住　他們讓人們去那
Military protection food, shelter... They told people to go there.

309
00:38:51,560 --> 00:38:53,140
說是最安全的地方
Said to be safest.

310
00:38:53,230 --> 00:38:55,280
加上他們還有看病的地方
Plus they got that disease place.

311
00:38:55,350 --> 00:38:56,960
疾控中心
Center for Disease Control.

312
00:38:57,040 --> 00:39:00,140
說他們正在想辦法解決問題
Said they were working on how to solve this thing.

313
00:39:27,320 --> 00:39:30,420
油和電大概一個月前就都停了
Gas and light have been down for maybe a month.

314
00:39:30,500 --> 00:39:32,520
警局有自備的丙烷系統
Station got its own propane system.

315
00:39:35,450 --> 00:39:37,460
設備還管用
Pilot's still on.

316
00:39:40,380 --> 00:39:41,900
哦上帝啊
Oh, my Lord.

317
00:39:41,980 --> 00:39:43,730
熱水耶
Hot water!

318
00:39:44,460 --> 00:39:46,220
感覺爽吧
That feels good, right?

319
00:39:46,570 --> 00:39:48,950
來啊　來啊　來啊　來
Bring it, bring it bring it around ahah

320
00:39:50,420 --> 00:39:51,980
你說啥
what did you say what

321
00:39:56,450 --> 00:39:59,910
德韋恩　去後面那間屋子換衣服
Dwayne... Dress in room back there.

322
00:40:01,250 --> 00:40:04,440
-你該說什麼　德韋恩　-謝謝
- What would you say, Dwayne? - Thank you.

323
00:40:10,000 --> 00:40:12,260
看來亞特蘭大是個好去處
Atlanta sounds like a good deal.

324
00:40:12,780 --> 00:40:15,640
安全　還有人…
Safer anyway. People...

325
00:40:16,000 --> 00:40:18,270
我們原本就是要去那裡
That's where we were heading.

326
00:40:18,380 --> 00:40:19,730
一切都亂了套
Things got crazy.

327
00:40:19,780 --> 00:40:21,120
你根本就無法想像
Man, you won't believe.

328
00:40:21,170 --> 00:40:22,080
恐慌蔓延…
The panic...

329
00:40:22,080 --> 00:40:25,740
街上根本過不去　然後我們…
Streets won't fit to be on, and then we'll...

330
00:40:26,370 --> 00:40:28,790
我妻子　走不動
My wife... couldn't travel.

331
00:40:28,880 --> 00:40:32,360
跟不上隊伍　因此我們得找個藏身之處
No, not with our herds, so we had to find a place to lay low.

332
00:40:32,600 --> 00:40:35,180
她死了之後…
And then,after she died...

333
00:40:37,280 --> 00:40:39,900
我們就在這裡徘徊不前
We just stayed hunkered down.

334
00:40:41,620 --> 00:40:43,660
我想我們只是不捨得離開
I guess we just froze in place.

335
00:40:45,410 --> 00:40:47,330
有離開這裡的計劃嗎
Plan to move on?

336
00:40:50,860 --> 00:40:52,990
目前沒這打算
Haven't worked up to it yet.

337
00:41:01,020 --> 00:41:03,240
這裡的槍少了不少
A lot of it's gone missing.

338
00:41:04,090 --> 00:41:05,720
老爸　我能學習開槍嗎
Dad, can I learn to shoot?

339
00:41:05,860 --> 00:41:07,270
我已經不小了
I'm old enough.

340
00:41:07,330 --> 00:41:08,630
廢話　當然得學
Hell yes you're going to learn.

341
00:41:08,670 --> 00:41:11,060
我得好好教你　萬萬不能掉以輕心　
We gotta do it carefully, teach you to respect the weapon.

342
00:41:11,140 --> 00:41:13,160
沒錯　這可不是玩具槍
That's right. It's not a toy.

343
00:41:13,200 --> 00:41:14,990
扣動扳機是一件很嚴肅的事
You pull the trigger, you have to mean it.

344
00:41:14,990 --> 00:41:16,490
切記在心　德韋恩 
Always remember that, Dwayne.

345
00:41:16,520 --> 00:41:18,160
是　長官
Yes, sir.

346
00:41:20,160 --> 00:41:21,580
給
Here.

347
00:41:22,820 --> 00:41:25,050
拿著
Go on.

348
00:41:29,040 --> 00:41:30,380
帶著這把槍
Take that one.

349
00:41:30,460 --> 00:41:32,030
沒什麼特別之處
Nothing fancy.

350
00:41:32,090 --> 00:41:34,100
不過瞄準精確高
Scope's accurate.

351
00:41:46,420 --> 00:41:48,190
節約彈藥
Conserve your ammo.

352
00:41:48,230 --> 00:41:51,950
彈藥用起來比你想像得要快　尤其是打靶練習時
Goes faster than you think. Especially at target practice.

353
00:41:53,300 --> 00:41:54,410
德韋恩
Dwayne.

354
00:41:54,500 --> 00:41:56,760
-啥事　-把這個放車裡
- Yeah? - Take this to the car.

355
00:41:57,700 --> 00:41:59,920
你們真的不跟我一起走
You sure you won't come along?

356
00:42:00,130 --> 00:42:01,070
過些日子再說
A few more days...

357
00:42:01,720 --> 00:42:05,190
等德韋恩學會了開槍　我也振作了精神
By the end, Dwayne will know how to shoot and I won't be so rusty.

358
00:42:12,170 --> 00:42:13,970
你也帶著一個吧
You got one better.

359
00:42:14,200 --> 00:42:16,750
每天黎明時分　我的會開上幾分鐘
I'll turn mine on, a few minutes every day at dawn.

360
00:42:16,810 --> 00:42:19,450
你們到那時　通過這個聯繫我
You get up there, that's how you find me.

361
00:42:19,900 --> 00:42:21,110
你認為他們也在那裡嗎
You think they're here?

362
00:42:21,160 --> 00:42:23,380
以防萬一　小心不為過
Can't afford not to. Not anymore.

363
00:42:24,060 --> 00:42:25,690
聽著　記住這一點
Look, just one thing.

364
00:42:25,760 --> 00:42:28,300
他們一般不會單獨出動
They may not seem like much one at a time...

365
00:42:28,300 --> 00:42:30,670
而是一群群似餓虎般地蜂擁而來
but in a group all round up and hungry...

366
00:42:30,820 --> 00:42:32,420
兄弟　千萬要小心
Man, you watch your ass.

367
00:42:32,540 --> 00:42:34,160
你們也是
You too.

368
00:42:35,690 --> 00:42:37,270
瑞克　你真是個好人
You a good man, Rick.

369
00:42:37,330 --> 00:42:40,100
希望你們一家能團聚
I hope you find your wife and son.

370
00:42:41,840 --> 00:42:43,490
後會有期　德韋恩
Be seeing you, Dwayne.

371
00:42:43,790 --> 00:42:45,370
照顧好你老爸
Take care of your old man.

372
00:42:45,440 --> 00:42:47,060
是　長官
Yes, sir.

373
00:42:57,190 --> 00:42:58,560
里昂·貝西
Leon Bessi?

374
00:43:03,100 --> 00:43:04,830
他給我的印象不好
Didn't think much of him.

375
00:43:04,930 --> 00:43:10,190
又粗心又蠢　但我不能放任不管
Careless and dumb, but... can't leave him like this.

376
00:43:13,250 --> 00:43:15,440
你知道他們會聽到槍聲的吧
You know, if they hear the shot.?

377
00:43:15,560 --> 00:43:17,220
那就趁他們出現前　趕緊閃人
Let's not be here when they show up.

378
00:43:17,280 --> 00:43:19,660
我們走吧　兒子　快　
Let's go, son. Come on.

379
00:44:52,850 --> 00:44:54,940
你在這看會漫畫
Read your comic books a while.

380
00:44:55,000 --> 00:44:57,050
我去樓上
Daddy'll be upstairs.

381
00:46:58,660 --> 00:46:59,480
爸爸
Daddy?

382
00:46:59,540 --> 00:47:01,220
沒關係　德韋恩
It's alright, Dwayne.

383
00:47:01,290 --> 00:47:04,520
兒子　你待在下面　別上來
You stay there, son. Don't come up here.

384
00:47:32,960 --> 00:47:35,030
來啊　寶貝
Come on, baby.

385
00:48:05,840 --> 00:48:08,740
很遺憾你變成這樣
I'm sorry this happened to you.

386
00:49:02,480 --> 00:49:04,320
加油　你能行的　
Come on, come on.

387
00:49:56,720 --> 00:49:58,740
緊急頻道呼叫中
Broadcasting on emergency channel.

388
00:49:58,790 --> 00:50:01,720
我們正沿著85號洲際公路開往亞特蘭大
We'll be approaching Atlanta on Highway 85.

389
00:50:02,760 --> 00:50:04,910
收到請回話
Anybody reads, please respond.

390
00:50:06,850 --> 00:50:08,750
喂　有人嗎
Hello. Hello.

391
00:50:08,840 --> 00:50:11,330
有沒有人聽得到我的聲音
Can anybody hear my voice?

392
00:50:13,180 --> 00:50:17,130
有人在聽嗎　收到請回話　　
Anybody out there? Anybody hears me, please respond.

393
00:50:19,170 --> 00:50:21,140
喂　聽得到我的聲音嗎
Hello, can you hear my voice?

394
00:50:21,250 --> 00:50:24,240
有人嗎　可以聽到我的聲音嗎
Hello? Hello? Can anybody hear my voice?

395
00:50:25,680 --> 00:50:27,900
可以　我可以聽到
Yes, I can hear you.

396
00:50:27,960 --> 00:50:29,970
你要過來了　完畢　　
You're coming through. Over.

397
00:50:30,690 --> 00:50:32,890
聽到請回話
Anybody who reads, please respond.

398
00:50:33,280 --> 00:50:35,390
緊急頻道呼叫中
Broadcasting on emergency channel.

399
00:50:35,440 --> 00:50:38,260
我們正沿著85號洲際公路開往亞特蘭大
We'll be approaching Atlanta on Highway 85.

400
00:50:38,340 --> 00:50:40,650
收到請回話
Anybody reads, please respond.

401
00:50:43,800 --> 00:50:46,100
我們就在城外
We're just outside the city.

402
00:50:46,540 --> 00:50:48,110
該死
Damn it.

403
00:50:48,170 --> 00:50:50,700
喂　喂　
Hello? Hello?

404
00:50:51,090 --> 00:50:52,440
他聽不到我的聲音　我沒辦法提醒他
He couldn't hear me. I couldn't warn him.

405
00:50:52,500 --> 00:50:53,800
用無線電再聯繫他試試
Try to raise him again.

406
00:50:53,850 --> 00:50:56,190
過來　孩子　這玩意你最拿手了
Come on, son. You know best how to work this thing,

407
00:50:58,780 --> 00:51:01,320
喂　呼叫人還在嗎
Hello, hello, is the person who calls still on the air?

408
00:51:04,570 --> 00:51:05,660
我是肖恩·威爾士警官
This is officer Shane Walsh,

409
00:51:05,660 --> 00:51:08,310
呼叫不明人士　請回話
broadcasting a person unknown, please respond.

410
00:51:15,410 --> 00:51:16,940
他不在了
He's gone.

411
00:51:18,480 --> 00:51:19,670
還有人還活著
There are others.

412
00:51:19,740 --> 00:51:21,110
不只有我們
It's not just us.

413
00:51:21,160 --> 00:51:21,940
是啊　意料之中　
Yeah, We knew there would be, right,

414
00:51:21,940 --> 00:51:23,630
因此民用波段電台才一直開著
that's why we let the CB on.

415
00:51:24,160 --> 00:51:25,880
這電台的確挺有用處
A lot of good it's been doing.

416
00:51:26,100 --> 00:51:27,610
我們應該在85號公路上放些標誌
And I've been saying for a week,

417
00:51:27,610 --> 00:51:29,300
來提醒人們遠離城裡
we ought to put signs up on 85

418
00:51:29,300 --> 00:51:30,200
這話我都說了一星期了
to warn people away from the city.

419
00:51:30,650 --> 00:51:32,750
人們不知道如今城裡已是行屍的天下
Folks got no idea what they're getting into.

420
00:51:32,870 --> 00:51:35,470
我們沒有足夠的時間
We don't have enough time.

421
00:51:36,440 --> 00:51:38,410
我們得騰出時間來
I think we need to make time.

422
00:51:38,500 --> 00:51:42,240
這個…　這一點我們無能為力
Yeah, that, uh... That's a luxury we can't afford.

423
00:51:42,370 --> 00:51:45,000
我們有幸活下來　活一天算一天　
We are surviving here. We are day to day.

424
00:51:45,630 --> 00:51:47,580
那你建議派誰去
And who the hell would you propose to send?

425
00:51:47,630 --> 00:51:49,510
我去　給我輛車
I'll go. Give me a vehicle.

426
00:51:49,560 --> 00:51:51,840
你知道誰都不准單獨行動　
Nobody goes anywhere alone, you know that.

427
00:51:57,530 --> 00:51:58,800
是　長官
Yes, sir.

428
00:51:58,860 --> 00:52:00,730
停　別跟上　過去坐下　孩子
Hey, hey, hey, come on, take a sit, buddy.

429
00:52:00,780 --> 00:52:02,790
沒事　去吧　沒事的　
You're alright, go on, you're alright.

430
00:52:06,590 --> 00:52:08,000
怎麼　在生我的氣嗎
What, you're pissed at me?

431
00:52:10,560 --> 00:52:13,150
你再怎麼氣　也改變不了什麼
Well pissing me all you want won't gonna change anything.

432
00:52:15,100 --> 00:52:16,960
我不會讓你陷於險境
I'm not putting you in danger, okay?

433
00:52:17,030 --> 00:52:18,660
無論如何都不會
I'm not doing it for anything.

434
00:52:18,750 --> 00:52:19,760
我知道有時候
I make you feel like

435
00:52:20,020 --> 00:52:22,130
你很想扇我耳光…
sometimes you wanna slap me outside the head...

436
00:52:22,180 --> 00:52:22,860
我就直說了吧　美女 
I'll tell you what, girl.

437
00:52:22,860 --> 00:52:24,230
你想扇的話　別客氣　儘管扇　
You feel that need, you go right ahead.

438
00:52:24,280 --> 00:52:25,810
我人就在這
I'm right here.

439
00:52:28,340 --> 00:52:32,940
你不能總這樣氣衝衝地半路走掉　
You cannot walk off like that, all half-cocked.

440
00:52:33,130 --> 00:52:35,680
你若不想為你我放棄這念頭的話
Look, if you don't wanna do it for my sake or for your sake,

441
00:52:35,680 --> 00:52:36,140
這我管不著
that's fine.

442
00:52:36,140 --> 00:52:39,570
但是　為了他你就好好待著吧
But just... You do it for him.

443
00:52:40,600 --> 00:52:43,080
你兒子經歷了太多
That boy has been through too much.

444
00:52:43,260 --> 00:52:45,850
他不能再失去他的媽媽　好嗎
And he's not losing his mother too, ok?

445
00:52:46,450 --> 00:52:49,560
-好　-好　好吧
- Okay. - Ok, fine.

446
00:52:53,320 --> 00:52:55,040
你自己答應了
You tell me okay.

447
00:53:02,090 --> 00:53:03,470
不難吧
It's not hard.

448
00:53:22,610 --> 00:53:23,990
媽媽
Mom?

449
00:53:27,810 --> 00:53:29,520
小鬼　她在裡面　進去吧
What's up, buddy? She's in there, go on.

450
00:53:32,960 --> 00:53:34,270
我不想讓你擔心
I don't want you to worry.

451
00:53:34,350 --> 00:53:36,250
我哪兒也不去了　好嗎
Your mom is not going anywhere. Okay?

452
00:53:37,130 --> 00:53:39,420
好嗎　高興嗎
Yeah? Yeah?

453
00:53:39,480 --> 00:53:41,590
-去把活幹完　-好
- Go finish your chores. - Okay.

454
00:54:25,100 --> 00:54:25,800
有人嗎
Hello?

455
00:54:28,070 --> 00:54:29,920
我是警察
Police officer out here.

456
00:54:32,510 --> 00:54:34,940
能借點汽油嗎
Can I borrow some gas?

457
00:54:43,360 --> 00:54:44,520
有人嗎
Hello?

458
00:54:50,170 --> 00:54:53,320
有人嗎　有人在家嗎
Hello? Anybody home?

459
00:55:21,260 --> 00:55:24,900
上帝請寬恕我們

460
00:56:40,470 --> 00:56:42,240
放輕鬆　別緊張
Easy now, easy.

461
00:56:42,390 --> 00:56:44,270
我不會傷害你
I'm not gonna hurt you.

462
00:56:44,340 --> 00:56:46,370
不會動你一根汗毛
Nothing like that.

463
00:56:47,810 --> 00:56:50,920
咱們打個商量吧
More like a proposal.

464
00:56:51,200 --> 00:56:53,050
順路南下就能到亞特蘭大了
Atlanta's just down the road ways.

465
00:56:53,120 --> 00:56:54,410
那裡很安全
It's safe there.

466
00:56:54,490 --> 00:56:58,930
包吃包住　有人　還有你的同類
Food, shelter, people, other horses too, I bet.

467
00:57:00,890 --> 00:57:02,780
這主意怎麼樣
How's that sound?

468
00:57:03,280 --> 00:57:08,970
套上了　真乖　真聽話
There we go. Good boy. Good boy.

469
00:57:09,030 --> 00:57:11,830
現在跟我走吧　跟著我
Now come with me. Come with me.

470
00:57:22,740 --> 00:57:24,530
我們慢慢來　好嗎
Let's go easy, ok?

471
00:57:24,910 --> 00:57:27,090
我好幾年沒騎馬了
I haven't done this for years.

472
00:57:31,750 --> 00:57:38,090
別急　慢慢來　別急　慢點
Easy. Easy, boy. Easy, easy, easy.

473
00:59:44,770 --> 00:59:48,610
鎮定　幾個而已　咱們有無敵馬腿呢
Steady. It's just a few. Nothing we can't outrun.

474
00:59:57,920 --> 00:59:59,910
那好吧
Okay.

475
01:02:39,200 --> 01:02:41,200
洛莉　卡爾　對不起
Lori, Carl, I'm sorry.

476
01:05:06,240 --> 01:05:07,960
你好 
Hey, you.

477
01:05:09,750 --> 01:05:12,200
你個白癡
Dumb ass.

478
01:05:13,280 --> 01:05:15,320
就是你　躲坦克裡的你
Hey, you in the tank.

479
01:05:15,400 --> 01:05:17,340
裡面還舒服嗎
Cozy in there?

