1
00:00:04,000 --> 00:00:05,120
摩根
Morgan

2
00:00:06,490 --> 00:00:08,660
我不知道你還在不在
I don't know if you're out there.

3
00:00:08,700 --> 00:00:10,800
我不知道你能不能聽到
I don't know if you can hear me.

4
00:00:10,830 --> 00:00:13,170
也許你現在在聽
Maybe you're listening right now.

5
00:00:13,200 --> 00:00:14,730
希望如此
I hope so.

6
00:00:14,770 --> 00:00:17,570
我找到了其他人　我的家人
I found others-- my family,

7
00:00:17,600 --> 00:00:19,210
難以置信吧
If you can believe it.

8
00:00:21,240 --> 00:00:23,380
我的妻子和兒子
My wife and son,

9
00:00:24,080 --> 00:00:25,180
他們還活著
They're alive.

10
00:00:25,210 --> 00:00:27,580
我想告訴你這點
I wanted you to know that.

11
00:00:30,480 --> 00:00:32,280
還有一點你要知道
There's something else you need to know.

12
00:00:32,320 --> 00:00:34,190
亞特蘭大不是我們想的那樣
Atlanta isn't what we thought.

13
00:00:34,220 --> 00:00:36,620
不是他們保證的那樣　那座城市…
It's not what they promised. The city is--

14
00:00:38,290 --> 00:00:41,360
不要進入城市
Do not enter the city.

15
00:00:41,930 --> 00:00:43,930
裡面已是行屍的天下
It belongs to the dead now.

16
00:00:47,670 --> 00:00:50,500
我們在西北部幾英里外有營地
We're camped a few miles northwest,

17
00:00:50,540 --> 00:00:52,710
就在一座被遺棄的大型採石場邊上
Up by a big abandoned rock quarry.

18
00:00:52,740 --> 00:00:55,270
你可以在地圖上看到
You can see it on a map.

19
00:00:57,280 --> 00:00:59,110
希望你能找到我們
I hope you come find us.

20
00:00:59,150 --> 00:01:01,250
但你務必要小心
But be careful.

21
00:01:02,480 --> 00:01:05,150
昨晚有行屍從樹林裡出來襲擊我們
Last night walkers came out of the woods.

22
00:01:08,140 --> 00:01:09,590
我們傷亡慘重
We lost people.

23
00:01:11,860 --> 00:01:14,990
你自己小心　摩根　照顧好你兒子
Watch yourself, Morgan. Take care of your boy.

24
00:01:15,030 --> 00:01:17,030
明天凌晨我會再和你聯繫
I'll try you again tomorrow at dawn.

25
00:01:35,120 --> 00:01:36,850
安德莉亞
Andrea.

26
00:01:42,820 --> 00:01:44,820
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.

27
00:01:47,230 --> 00:01:49,300
她已經去了
She's gone.

28
00:01:49,330 --> 00:01:52,300
你得讓我們處理
You got to let us take her.

29
00:01:59,370 --> 00:02:00,740
我們都很關心她
We all cared about her

30
00:02:00,770 --> 00:02:03,910
我保證我們會儘量下手輕點
And I promise we'll be as gentle as we can.

31
00:02:41,720 --> 00:02:44,080
她還是一動不動嗎
She still won't move?

32
00:02:44,860 --> 00:02:46,490
她甚至連話都不說
She won't even talk to us.

33
00:02:47,850 --> 00:02:50,160
她都這樣一晚上了
She's been there all night.

34
00:02:51,090 --> 00:02:52,290
我們該怎麼辦
What do we do?

35
00:02:53,290 --> 00:02:55,390
不能讓艾米的屍體這麼留著
Can't just leave Amy like that.

36
00:02:55,430 --> 00:02:57,560
我們得像對其他人一樣
We need to deal with it

37
00:02:57,600 --> 00:02:59,500
把她處理掉
same as the others.

38
00:03:00,970 --> 00:03:02,940
我來和她說
I'll tell her how it is.

39
00:03:07,040 --> 00:03:09,010
安德莉亞
Andrea.

40
00:03:10,110 --> 00:03:12,180
這次我可開了保險了
I know how the safety works.

41
00:03:15,780 --> 00:03:18,280
好吧　行了
All right. Okay.

42
00:03:18,860 --> 00:03:20,450
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.

43
00:03:22,290 --> 00:03:25,220
我真的很抱歉
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.

44
00:03:37,950 --> 00:03:39,570
YYeTs人人影視誠意奉獻

45
00:03:41,710 --> 00:03:43,380
翻譯 海因裡希 點點點

46
00:03:44,990 --> 00:03:46,810
翻譯 Tiberius 憶

47
00:03:46,820 --> 00:03:48,680
翻譯 NaryKing

48
00:03:52,040 --> 00:03:53,240
時間軸 之間

49
00:03:53,240 --> 00:03:54,340
校對 海因裡希

50
00:03:54,340 --> 00:03:55,470
後期/特效 WiLL

51
00:03:55,470 --> 00:03:56,640
監製 海因裡希

52
00:03:56,650 --> 00:03:59,650
CHD版個人美化微修：字幕雷哥

53
00:04:08,240 --> 00:04:13,090
走

54
00:04:08,990 --> 00:04:13,090
肉

55
00:04:09,340 --> 00:04:13,090
行屍

56
00:04:09,340 --> 00:04:13,090
『第一季 第五集』

57
00:04:14,170 --> 00:04:15,810
你們大腦進水了吧
Y'all can't be serious.

58
00:04:15,840 --> 00:04:17,840
讓一個妞兒妨礙我們
Let that girl hamstring us?

59
00:04:17,880 --> 00:04:19,480
那死了的女孩就是個定時炸彈
The dead girl's a time bomb.

60
00:04:19,510 --> 00:04:21,680
你有什麼好主意
What do you suggest?

61
00:04:23,380 --> 00:04:24,920
一箭射過去
Take the shot.

62
00:04:25,460 --> 00:04:27,420
乾淨利落　直接命中腦子
Clean, in the brain from here.

63
00:04:27,450 --> 00:04:30,090
老子從這距離都能射中火雞腦門中央
Hell, I can hit a turkey between the eyes from this distance.

64
00:04:30,120 --> 00:04:33,160
不行　上帝啊　讓她一個人呆會
No. For god's sakes, let her be.

65
00:04:46,810 --> 00:04:49,540
別發愣了　小吉　我們還有活要幹
Wake up, Jimbo. We've got some work to do.

66
00:04:54,070 --> 00:04:55,810
多謝
Thanks.

67
00:04:55,850 --> 00:04:57,780
你們在搞什麼
What are you guys doing?

68
00:04:57,820 --> 00:05:00,650
這是堆殭屍的　我們的人堆在那兒
This is for geeks. Our people go over there.

69
00:05:00,690 --> 00:05:02,590
有什麼區別　他們都被感染了
What's the difference? They're all infected.

70
00:05:02,620 --> 00:05:04,860
我們的人得堆在那裡
Our people go in that row over there.

71
00:05:06,890 --> 00:05:08,790
我們不能燒了他們
We don't burn them!

72
00:05:09,810 --> 00:05:11,000
我們得埋葬他們
We bury them.

73
00:05:12,160 --> 00:05:13,630
明白了嗎
Understand?

74
00:05:17,800 --> 00:05:21,010
把我們的人堆去那邊
Our people go in that row over there.

75
00:05:26,950 --> 00:05:28,510
你們都活該
You reap what you sow.

76
00:05:28,550 --> 00:05:30,650
你少說句會死啊　哥們
You know what? Shut up, man.

77
00:05:30,680 --> 00:05:32,750
你們把我哥哥丟下等死
Y'all left my brother for dead.

78
00:05:34,220 --> 00:05:36,360
這是你們咎由自取
You had this coming.

79
00:05:46,630 --> 00:05:47,970
你在流血嗎
Are you bleeding?

80
00:05:48,000 --> 00:05:51,370
從屍體上沾到的
I just got some on me from the bodies.

81
00:05:51,400 --> 00:05:53,710
那是鮮血　你被咬了嗎
That blood is fresh. Were you bit?

82
00:05:54,240 --> 00:05:55,010
沒有
No.

83
00:05:55,440 --> 00:05:57,080
我在襲擊中被擦到了
I got scratched during the attack.

84
00:05:57,110 --> 00:05:58,740
-你被咬了　-我沒事
- You got bit. - I'm fine.

85
00:05:58,780 --> 00:06:00,380
那讓我看看
Then show me.

86
00:06:04,850 --> 00:06:07,120
-別告訴別人　求你了　-他被行屍咬了
- Don't tell, please. - A walker got him.

87
00:06:07,150 --> 00:06:09,220
他被行屍咬了
A walker bit jim.

88
00:06:13,420 --> 00:06:15,230
-我沒事　-讓我們看看
- I'm okay. I'm okay. - Show it to us.

89
00:06:15,820 --> 00:06:18,130
快讓我們看看
Show it to us.

90
00:06:18,160 --> 00:06:19,700
-別緊張　吉姆　-抓住他
- Easy, Jim. - Grab him.

91
00:06:19,730 --> 00:06:22,100
吉姆　放下那玩意
Jim, put it down. Put it down.

92
00:06:22,140 --> 00:06:24,500
我沒事　我沒事
I'm okay. I'm okay.

93
00:06:24,540 --> 00:06:27,410
我沒事
I'm okay. I'm okay.

94
00:06:28,280 --> 00:06:29,370
我沒事
I'm okay.

95
00:06:31,540 --> 00:06:33,350
我沒事
I'm okay. I'm okay.

96
00:06:33,380 --> 00:06:35,480
我沒事
I'm okay.

97
00:06:36,090 --> 00:06:37,780
我沒事
I'm okay.

98
00:06:41,260 --> 00:06:43,320
我沒事
I'm okay.

99
00:06:49,760 --> 00:06:51,930
我說直接給他腦門上來一下
I say we put a pickaxe in his head

100
00:06:51,970 --> 00:06:53,370
把那個死掉的女孩一起處理掉
And the dead girl's and be done with it.

101
00:06:53,400 --> 00:06:55,400
如果是你的話　你也想這樣嗎
Is that what you'd want if it were you?

102
00:06:55,440 --> 00:06:57,700
沒錯　我還要為此感謝你們
Yeah, and I'd thank you while you did it.

103
00:06:57,740 --> 00:06:59,740
我也沒想到我會這麼說
I hate to say it-- I never thought I would--

104
00:06:59,770 --> 00:07:01,370
但也許達裡爾說得對
But maybe Daryl's right.

105
00:07:01,410 --> 00:07:04,380
吉姆不是怪物或咬人的瘋狗　戴爾
Jim's not a monster, Dale, or some rabid dog.

106
00:07:04,410 --> 00:07:06,710
-我不是說…　-他病了　他是個病人
- I'm not suggesting-- - He's sick. A sick man.

107
00:07:06,750 --> 00:07:08,710
這事一開始就剎不了車了　我們的界限在哪裡
We start down that road, where do we draw the line?

108
00:07:08,750 --> 00:07:12,250
界限很清楚　絕不能允許殭屍的存在
The line's pretty clear. Zero tolerance for walkers,

109
00:07:12,290 --> 00:07:14,820
-准殭屍也不行　-如果我們能幫他呢
- Or them to be. - What if we can get him help?

110
00:07:14,850 --> 00:07:16,990
我聽說疾控中心在研製解藥
I heard the C.D.C. Was working on a cure.

111
00:07:17,020 --> 00:07:18,130
我也聽說了很多事
I heard that too. Heard a

112
00:07:18,140 --> 00:07:20,090
但世界末日了什麼都拉倒了
lot of things before the world went to hell.

113
00:07:20,130 --> 00:07:21,460
如果疾控中心還在運行呢
What if the c.D.C. Is still up and running?

114
00:07:21,460 --> 00:07:24,330
-哥們　這可有點勉強了　-為什麼
- Man, that is a stretch right there. - Why?

115
00:07:24,360 --> 00:07:28,270
如果還有政府機構　不管剩下什麼
If there's any government left, any structure at all,

116
00:07:28,300 --> 00:07:30,440
他們一定不惜一切代價保護疾控中心　是吧
They'd protect the C.D.C. At all costs, wouldn't they?

117
00:07:30,470 --> 00:07:33,170
這是我們最好的機會　穩定居所　安全保障
I think it's our best shot. Shelter, protection--

118
00:07:33,210 --> 00:07:36,240
得　瑞克　你想要那些　好　我也想要啊
Okay, Rick, you want those things, all right? I do too, okay?

119
00:07:36,280 --> 00:07:39,580
如果它們真的存在　肯定也是在軍事基地裡
Now if they exist, they're at the army base.

120
00:07:39,610 --> 00:07:41,780
-本寧堡　-那可是另一頭的100英里外
- Fort Benning. - That's 100 miles in the opposite direction.

121
00:07:41,810 --> 00:07:43,880
對　但那裡遠離危險區域
That is right. But it's away from the hot zone.

122
00:07:43,920 --> 00:07:45,780
聽我說　如果那些地方仍在運作
Now listen to me. If that place is operational,

123
00:07:45,820 --> 00:07:49,020
肯定是戒備森嚴　我們會很安全
It'll be heavily armed. We'd be safe there.

124
00:07:49,060 --> 00:07:51,290
軍隊肯定站在對抗殭屍的第一線
The military were on the front lines of this thing.

125
00:07:51,320 --> 00:07:53,560
他們被全滅了　我們都見到了
They got overrun. We've all seen that.

126
00:07:53,590 --> 00:07:56,660
疾控中心是我們最好的選擇　也是吉姆的唯一希望
The C.D.C. is our best choice and Jim's only chance.

127
00:07:59,300 --> 00:08:02,200
你去找阿司匹林去吧　愛咋咋地
You go looking for aspirin, do what you need to do.

128
00:08:02,240 --> 00:08:04,100
果然還是得靠有種的人來
Someone needs to have some balls to take care

129
00:08:04,140 --> 00:08:05,260
-處理這種爛攤子　-喂喂喂
- Of this damn problem! - Hey hey hey!

130
00:08:05,260 --> 00:08:07,670
我們不殺活人
We don't kill the living.

131
00:08:10,680 --> 00:08:14,280
一個拿槍頂著我腦袋的人這麼說可真諷刺
That's funny coming from a man who just put a gun to my head.

132
00:08:14,310 --> 00:08:16,780
我跟他很多事情上都不一致
We may disagree on some things,

133
00:08:16,820 --> 00:08:19,580
但這事不會　你把傢伙放下
Not on this. You put it down.

134
00:08:19,620 --> 00:08:21,050
快點
Go on.

135
00:08:25,560 --> 00:08:27,390
-跟我來　-要帶我上哪
- Come with me. - Where are you taking me?

136
00:08:27,430 --> 00:08:29,490
安全的地方
Somewhere safe.

137
00:08:37,940 --> 00:08:40,610
我來表示慰問
I came to pay my respects.

138
00:08:58,860 --> 00:09:01,160
我有沒有跟你提過
Did I ever mention

139
00:09:01,710 --> 00:09:04,130
我老婆是怎麼沒的
How I lost my wife?

140
00:09:08,180 --> 00:09:10,100
-癌症不是麼　-是
- Cancer, wasn't it? - Yeah.

141
00:09:11,200 --> 00:09:13,970
我拉著她看遍了醫生
I dragged her to every doctor,

142
00:09:14,010 --> 00:09:16,240
做遍了檢查
Every test.

143
00:09:17,340 --> 00:09:20,910
終於在無數手術和化療之後
And after all the surgeries and the chemos,

144
00:09:22,090 --> 00:09:23,720
她心裡準備好了
She was ready.

145
00:09:24,630 --> 00:09:26,180
她接受了事實　知道麼
She accepted it, you know?

146
00:09:28,670 --> 00:09:31,020
可我不能
But I never could.

147
00:09:31,460 --> 00:09:34,830
之後那幾年我一直過得
And I spent the last few years

148
00:09:35,650 --> 00:09:37,560
很是惱火
So angry.

149
00:09:38,510 --> 00:09:40,200
我覺得完全被人給耍了
I felt so cheated.

150
00:09:44,370 --> 00:09:46,940
自她去世之後
Since she passed,

151
00:09:47,820 --> 00:09:50,640
你們兩個姑娘
You girls were the first people...

152
00:09:52,510 --> 00:09:54,410
是我唯一在乎的人
that I cared anything for.

153
00:10:13,700 --> 00:10:15,770
今天是她生日嗎
This is her birthday?

154
00:10:18,940 --> 00:10:21,270
她的生日總是像
Her birthday was always like--

155
00:10:21,310 --> 00:10:24,210
像個七天的盛會
Like a week long affair.

156
00:10:24,240 --> 00:10:27,650
可惜我卻總是這樣那樣地錯過
But I somehow always missed it.

157
00:10:27,680 --> 00:10:29,750
我要麼在大學裡回不去
I was away at college

158
00:10:29,780 --> 00:10:32,480
或是太忙沒時間跟小孩子胡鬧
Or too busy for kid's parties.

159
00:10:33,720 --> 00:10:36,050
她總是會很興奮地打電話給我
She'd call all excited.

160
00:10:37,280 --> 00:10:39,620
而我總是說我肯定到家
I always said that I'd make it home

161
00:10:39,660 --> 00:10:42,790
說那話的時候我是真心的
And I really always meant to,

162
00:10:42,830 --> 00:10:47,100
可我沒有一次兌現了諾言
But I never made it past that phone call.

163
00:10:48,130 --> 00:10:50,470
我明白現實已經足夠殘酷
I know things are hard enough for you

164
00:10:50,500 --> 00:10:53,540
就不要再責怪自己了好麼
Without adding guilt into the mix, huh?

165
00:11:37,650 --> 00:11:41,490
我來好了　畢竟是我丈夫
I'll do it. He's my husband.

166
00:13:48,310 --> 00:13:50,920
艾米
Amy.

167
00:13:56,490 --> 00:13:58,690
艾米　對不起
Amy, I'm sorry.

168
00:14:05,400 --> 00:14:07,570
對不起
I'm sorry

169
00:14:08,350 --> 00:14:10,240
我總是沒能在你身邊
For not ever being there.

170
00:14:12,180 --> 00:14:14,970
我總覺得我們會有足夠的時間
I always thought there'd be more time.

171
00:14:37,060 --> 00:14:39,330
我現在在了　艾米
I'm here now, amy.

172
00:14:40,480 --> 00:14:41,930
我陪你
I'm here.

173
00:14:47,480 --> 00:14:49,370
我愛你
I love you.

174
00:15:14,910 --> 00:15:15,840
有話就說
Say it.

175
00:15:19,210 --> 00:15:21,210
行
Okay.

176
00:15:23,650 --> 00:15:25,620
我在想如果你當時留下了
I'm thinking if you'd of stayed here,

177
00:15:25,650 --> 00:15:27,760
選擇了自己家人
If you'd have looked after your own--

178
00:15:27,760 --> 00:15:31,200
而不是走出去　還帶走了一半人手
instead you went off. You took half our manpower with you.

179
00:15:32,490 --> 00:15:35,030
那我們的損失就不會這麼慘重了
I'm thinking maybe our losses wouldn't have been so bad.

180
00:15:35,060 --> 00:15:37,560
要不是我們出去把那袋槍撿了回來
If we hadn't gone off and brought those guns back

181
00:15:37,600 --> 00:15:40,500
我覺得我們的損失可能會更慘
when we did, I think our losses would have been a lot worse.

182
00:15:40,530 --> 00:15:42,870
沒準會是一個不留　
Maybe the entire camp.

183
00:15:57,120 --> 00:16:00,120
我還是覺得不燒了這些屍體是個錯誤
I still think it's a mistake not burning these bodies.

184
00:16:00,590 --> 00:16:02,320
我們不是說好了要這麼來的麼
It's what we said we'd do, right?

185
00:16:02,350 --> 00:16:05,010
燒個乾淨　一了百了不是
Burn 'em all, wasn't that the idea?

186
00:16:05,010 --> 00:16:06,690
最初是這樣
At first.

187
00:16:06,730 --> 00:16:08,430
這位中國仔感情用事了
The chinaman gets all emotional,

188
00:16:08,460 --> 00:16:11,400
說事不能那麼來　我們就這麼被牽著走了
Says it's not the thing to do, we just follow him along?

189
00:16:13,170 --> 00:16:16,130
人們該知道這他娘的是誰管事
These people need to know who the hell's in charge here,

190
00:16:16,170 --> 00:16:19,100
-規矩是什麼樣　-這沒有規矩
- What the rules are. - There are no rules.

191
00:16:19,140 --> 00:16:21,270
那就是個問題
Well, that's a problem.

192
00:16:21,310 --> 00:16:22,540
我們都沒有哪怕一分鐘時間
We haven't had one minute

193
00:16:22,540 --> 00:16:24,510
來給之前的自己告別
to hold onto anything of our old selves.

194
00:16:24,540 --> 00:16:28,950
我們要時間來哀悼死者　我們要埋葬他們
We need time to mourn and we need to bury our dead.

195
00:16:28,980 --> 00:16:30,880
是人就得這麼做
It's what people do.

196
00:16:33,720 --> 00:16:35,620
哦不
Oh no.

197
00:16:35,650 --> 00:16:37,990
不　不　不　不
No no no no.

198
00:16:39,100 --> 00:16:41,060
不要這樣　拜託
No, not this, please.

199
00:16:53,840 --> 00:16:56,210
不　不　不
No no no.

200
00:16:56,240 --> 00:16:58,840
不　不　不　不
Oh, no no no.

201
00:16:58,880 --> 00:17:01,810
不　不
No no.

202
00:17:11,290 --> 00:17:13,460
我能行　我能行
I can do it. I can do it.

203
00:17:13,490 --> 00:17:16,130
我能行　我能行
I can do it! I can do it.

204
00:17:58,470 --> 00:18:00,640
親手埋葬別人已經夠糟了
Burying other people is bad enough,

205
00:18:00,670 --> 00:18:02,870
-但是一想到我們當中　-噓
- But the thought of one of us-- - Shh.

206
00:18:03,680 --> 00:18:05,510
爸爸　我們現在安全了嗎　
Are we safe now, dad?

207
00:18:06,730 --> 00:18:08,350
我們現在都在一起了嗎
Now that we're together?

208
00:18:08,380 --> 00:18:10,480
我不會再走開了
I won't leave again.

209
00:18:10,520 --> 00:18:12,580
我保證　無論發生什麼都不走
I promise you that. Not for anything.

210
00:18:15,320 --> 00:18:18,190
現在你讓我和媽媽
Now give me a chance

211
00:18:18,220 --> 00:18:20,160
單獨談談話好麼
To discuss some things with your mom, okay?

212
00:18:20,790 --> 00:18:22,190
-好　-乖
- Yeah. - All right.

213
00:18:22,230 --> 00:18:24,000
乖
All right.

214
00:18:30,670 --> 00:18:33,970
肖恩怪我當時沒留下
Shane blames me for not being here.

215
00:18:34,010 --> 00:18:35,810
你呢
Do you?

216
00:18:41,550 --> 00:18:44,980
我們現在有槍了　我們強力了
We got guns now. We're stronger.

217
00:18:45,020 --> 00:18:46,920
人數也更少了
And we have fewer people.

218
00:18:46,950 --> 00:18:49,450
我們也更弱了
That makes us weaker.

219
00:18:49,490 --> 00:18:51,690
你想要我說你做對了
You want me to say I think you were right?

220
00:18:51,720 --> 00:18:53,830
我理解
I understand that.

221
00:18:56,860 --> 00:19:00,870
但我只能說你們都各有道理
All I can say is that neither one of you is entirely wrong.

222
00:19:01,690 --> 00:19:03,770
我只能這麼說了
It's the best I can do right now.

223
00:19:07,340 --> 00:19:09,540
那疾控中心呢
What about the C.D.C.?

224
00:19:11,110 --> 00:19:13,480
-瑞克　-我們現在進退兩難了
- Rick--　- We're at the ragged edge here.

225
00:19:13,510 --> 00:19:16,610
我們需要救援　還有傷員需要幫助
We need relief and we got a sick man who needs help.

226
00:19:16,650 --> 00:19:18,480
我不知道為什麼大家都視而不見
I don't know why people can't see that.

227
00:19:18,520 --> 00:19:20,450
看看大家的神情
Well, look at their faces.

228
00:19:20,490 --> 00:19:23,190
再看看我　大家都嚇壞了
Look at mine. We're all terrified.

229
00:19:23,600 --> 00:19:26,720
如果有人根據直覺做個決定
If one of us suggested, based on a hunch,

230
00:19:26,760 --> 00:19:28,960
讓我們到城市裡去
that we head toward that city,

231
00:19:29,260 --> 00:19:30,900
你就找不到我們了
you'd have no part of it.

232
00:19:33,370 --> 00:19:35,830
告訴我些千真萬確的話
Tell me something with certainty.

233
00:19:46,660 --> 00:19:47,780
我愛你
I love you.

234
00:19:52,620 --> 00:19:55,450
這是我唯一確定的東西
That's all I got.

235
00:19:57,390 --> 00:19:59,220
我也愛你
I love you too.

236
00:20:10,600 --> 00:20:13,240
他燒得更厲害了
His fever is worse.

237
00:20:14,080 --> 00:20:15,570
需要什麼嗎
You need anything?

238
00:20:17,240 --> 00:20:20,280
水　我要喝水
Water. Could use more water.

239
00:20:20,310 --> 00:20:21,750
-我去拿些來　-好
- I'll get some.　- Okay.

240
00:20:21,780 --> 00:20:24,180
卡蘿爾　過來幫忙
Carol, you help me?

241
00:20:36,460 --> 00:20:38,600
你給我留了條命嗎
You save a grave for me?

242
00:20:41,100 --> 00:20:42,800
誰都不想弄成那樣
Nobody wants that.

243
00:20:43,440 --> 00:20:45,500
你想不想這無所謂
It's not about what you want.

244
00:20:48,470 --> 00:20:51,240
就好比你想自作主張時
That, uh-- that sound you hear,

245
00:20:51,280 --> 00:20:54,280
上帝就會嘲笑你一樣
that's god laughing while you make plans.

246
00:21:01,090 --> 00:21:03,550
我的想法是　吉姆
What I want, Jim, if--

247
00:21:05,190 --> 00:21:06,490
要是上天允許
If god allows,

248
00:21:06,530 --> 00:21:09,260
你得尋求一些幫助
is to get you some help.

249
00:21:39,060 --> 00:21:41,130
小心紅樹林
Watch the mangroves.

250
00:21:41,780 --> 00:21:44,260
紅樹林的根會讓船擱淺
Their roots will gouge the whole boat.

251
00:21:45,260 --> 00:21:48,100
你也知道吧
You know that, right?

252
00:21:48,610 --> 00:21:52,200
艾米就在那裡游泳
Amy is there swimming.

253
00:21:54,710 --> 00:21:57,780
你會照看好這艘船的吧
You'll watch the boat, right?

254
00:21:57,810 --> 00:21:59,910
你說過的
You said you would.

255
00:22:02,280 --> 00:22:04,320
我會照看好這艘船
I'll watch the boat.

256
00:22:05,330 --> 00:22:06,520
放心吧
Don't worry.

257
00:22:10,590 --> 00:22:12,360
好吧
Okay.

258
00:22:23,540 --> 00:22:26,170
你得去和瑞克談談
I need you to help talk some sense into Rick.

259
00:22:28,900 --> 00:22:32,440
聽著　洛莉　去疾控中心是個錯誤
Look, this C.D.C. Thing, Lori, it's a mistake.

260
00:22:34,180 --> 00:22:35,540
這麼說你支持他咯
So you're backing him?

261
00:22:35,540 --> 00:22:37,680
我還能怎樣　他是我丈夫
What else would I do? He's my husband.

262
00:22:37,720 --> 00:22:40,220
聽著　也許你是該做個盡職的妻子
Look, it may be time for you to play the dutiful wife,

263
00:22:40,250 --> 00:22:42,020
但你要彌補自己的婚姻是你的事
but you can't tell me that fixing your marriage

264
00:22:42,050 --> 00:22:43,560
別把大伙的安全拿去冒險
is worth putting people's lives at risk.

265
00:22:43,560 --> 00:22:44,460
這和我的婚姻無關
I think folks around here can make up

266
00:22:44,460 --> 00:22:47,120
大伙能自己做出決定
their minds without bringing my marriage into it.

267
00:22:47,760 --> 00:22:49,760
你得改了這個習慣
It's a habit you need to break.

268
00:22:51,200 --> 00:22:54,570
我已經在努力了
I guess I'll just add it to the list of habits that I'm breaking

269
00:22:54,600 --> 00:22:56,100
這也由不得我
whether I like it or not.

270
00:22:58,730 --> 00:23:00,570
什麼習慣
What habits?

271
00:23:01,910 --> 00:23:04,680
我只是說要有個計劃　夥計
Just talking about my need for a plan, man.

272
00:23:06,210 --> 00:23:08,050
有結果了嗎　我們走還是不走
So what is it? Are we leaving or not?

273
00:23:08,080 --> 00:23:10,250
或許大夥兒只是想留下來
Maybe y'all just want to stay here.

274
00:23:10,280 --> 00:23:12,100
我們還有些罐頭食物
We could hang some more tin cans.

275
00:23:12,100 --> 00:23:13,780
我們不能留下　這誰都知道
We can't stay here. We both know that.

276
00:23:13,780 --> 00:23:17,320
我剛也是這意思　我們該相信你的直覺
I was just telling Shane I think we should trust your gut.

277
00:23:26,370 --> 00:23:28,670
我們去巡邏一下
Let's go do our sweep.

278
00:23:38,430 --> 00:23:40,160
跟你說吧　哥們
Tell you what, man,

279
00:23:40,200 --> 00:23:42,530
這些人他們心裡沒底
These people, man, they're not convinced.

280
00:23:44,170 --> 00:23:46,370
你去疾控中心的主意
You head to the C.D.C.,

281
00:23:46,400 --> 00:23:48,540
可能沒人支持
You might be on your own.

282
00:23:48,570 --> 00:23:51,070
你真想讓洛莉和卡爾
You gotta really consider whether you want to

283
00:23:51,110 --> 00:23:53,210
落到這種危險境地嗎
put Lori and Carl in that kind of spot.

284
00:23:53,650 --> 00:23:55,880
我得為我的家庭著想
I got to do what's best for my family.

285
00:23:55,910 --> 00:23:58,150
為家人著想　這算哪門子著想
Best for your family? What's that?

286
00:23:58,180 --> 00:24:01,420
-讓他們身處各種險境嗎　-什麼險境
- Exposing them to all kinds of risks?　- As opposed to what?

287
00:24:01,450 --> 00:24:04,220
又不是跨越100英里的敵占區
Crossing 100 miles of hostile territory?

288
00:24:04,780 --> 00:24:05,990
如果我們命懸一線
If we're looking for a lifeline,

289
00:24:05,990 --> 00:24:07,890
得就近求援
I say swim toward the closest ship,

290
00:24:07,920 --> 00:24:10,360
遠水救不了近火
Not further out to sea.

291
00:24:10,880 --> 00:24:12,290
你為什麼就不支持我呢
Why can't you back me up?

292
00:24:12,330 --> 00:24:15,030
聽著　我也想　只是…
Look, I want to. It's just...

293
00:24:15,790 --> 00:24:17,900
我不懂
I don't see it.

294
00:24:17,930 --> 00:24:20,300
不是你的家人　你當然不明白
If it was your family, you'd feel differently.

295
00:24:25,310 --> 00:24:27,910
你剛說什麼
What did you say to me?

296
00:24:30,380 --> 00:24:32,380
是我保護他們的安全　夥計
I kept 'em safe, man.

297
00:24:33,020 --> 00:24:35,820
我視如己出般地保護他們
I looked after them like they were my own.

298
00:24:35,850 --> 00:24:37,990
-我是這麼做的　-我不是那個意思
- That's what I did.　- I didn't mean it that way.

299
00:24:38,020 --> 00:24:40,190
那你什麼意思
Well, how'd you mean it?

300
00:24:40,690 --> 00:24:42,260
說啊　你是什麼意思
Go on, man. How'd you mean it?

301
00:24:43,840 --> 00:24:45,460
你誤解了
you're misinterpreting me.

302
00:24:45,500 --> 00:24:47,230
-是嗎　-我誤會了我的意思
- All right.　- You're just hearing it wrong.

303
00:24:47,270 --> 00:24:49,670
-真的嗎　-聽著　你也知道
- Yeah?　- Look, you know--

304
00:24:49,700 --> 00:24:53,540
你的恩惠我無以為報　好嗎
You know I can never repay that debt, okay?

305
00:25:39,780 --> 00:25:41,350
天啊
Jesus.

306
00:25:47,460 --> 00:25:49,690
我知道
I know.

307
00:25:51,560 --> 00:25:54,370
看來要穿反光背心了　免得誤傷自己人
Gonna have to start wearing reflective vests out here.

308
00:25:57,570 --> 00:25:59,570
說真的
Seriously.

309
00:25:59,980 --> 00:26:02,770
來吧　哥們
Come on, man.

310
00:26:06,110 --> 00:26:07,550
走吧　夥計
Come on, man, let's go.

311
00:26:07,580 --> 00:26:09,580
這裡啥都沒有
Nothing out here.

312
00:26:25,530 --> 00:26:30,300
我想了想瑞克的計劃
I've been, uh-- I've been thinking about Rick's plan.

313
00:26:30,340 --> 00:26:32,270
聽著　這個…
Now look, there are no--

314
00:26:32,300 --> 00:26:34,810
不管怎樣都沒有任何保證
There are no guarantees either way.

315
00:26:34,840 --> 00:26:37,640
我率先承認這一點
I'll be the first one to admit that.

316
00:26:37,680 --> 00:26:39,910
我和他認識很久了
I've known this man a long time.

317
00:26:41,380 --> 00:26:42,910
我相信他的直覺
I trust his instincts.

318
00:26:45,680 --> 00:26:49,520
我覺得最重要的是　我們得團結在一起
I say the most important thing here is we need to stay together.

319
00:26:52,800 --> 00:26:56,630
如果大家都同意
So those of you that agree,

320
00:26:56,660 --> 00:26:58,400
我們一大早就動身離開
We leave first thing in the morning.

321
00:27:01,030 --> 00:27:02,270
好嗎
Okay?

322
00:27:08,360 --> 00:27:10,190
我們要轉移了
We're moving out,

323
00:27:10,230 --> 00:27:12,830
離開採石場
Leaving the quarry.

324
00:27:12,870 --> 00:27:15,470
如果你昨天聽到我的話　可能已經過來了
If you heard me yesterday, you may be coming here.

325
00:27:15,500 --> 00:27:19,340
這樣的話　你到時我們已經走了
If you are, we'll be gone by the time you arrive.

326
00:27:20,910 --> 00:27:23,940
我會給你留下字條和地圖
I'm leaving a note and map behind for you

327
00:27:23,980 --> 00:27:25,810
貼在一輛紅車上
taped to a red car

328
00:27:25,840 --> 00:27:28,150
這樣你就能跟上我們了
So you can follow our trail.

329
00:27:29,750 --> 00:27:31,280
我們要去疾控中心
We're heading to the C.D.C.

330
00:27:31,320 --> 00:27:33,420
那裡是我們最後的希望
If there's anything left, it's got to be there,

331
00:27:33,450 --> 00:27:35,220
你不覺得嗎
don't you think?

332
00:27:36,860 --> 00:27:38,660
摩根
Morgan...

333
00:27:40,290 --> 00:27:42,430
我希望你對那的看法是對的
I hope you were right about that place.

334
00:27:44,060 --> 00:27:46,660
拜託千萬別出錯
I need you to be.

335
00:27:58,020 --> 00:27:59,510
大家聽好了
Everybody listen up.

336
00:27:59,550 --> 00:28:02,480
手上有電台接收器的　我們在40頻道
Those of you with C.B.s, we're gonna be on channel 40.

337
00:28:02,510 --> 00:28:04,380
不要弄出很大聲響　好嗎
Let's keep the chatter down, okay?

338
00:28:04,820 --> 00:28:07,520
如果沒有接收器　一旦出了問題
Now you got a problem, don't have a C.B.,

339
00:28:07,550 --> 00:28:08,770
收不到信號　失去聯繫的話
can't get a signal or anything at all,

340
00:28:08,770 --> 00:28:09,920
要立刻吹號
you're gonna hit your horn one time.

341
00:28:10,310 --> 00:28:11,890
隊伍就會停下來
That'll stop the caravan.

342
00:28:12,420 --> 00:28:14,930
-有問題嗎　-我們…
- Any questions? - We're, uh...

343
00:28:14,960 --> 00:28:17,430
我們不去了
We're-- we're not going.

344
00:28:20,100 --> 00:28:22,430
我們在伯明翰還有親戚
We have family in Birmingham.

345
00:28:22,470 --> 00:28:24,600
我們想去投奔他們
We want to be with our people.

346
00:28:24,640 --> 00:28:26,800
你們單獨行動的話　就沒人能照應你們了
You go on your own, you won't have anyone to watch your back.

347
00:28:26,840 --> 00:28:28,870
我們想賭一把
We'll take the chance.

348
00:28:29,400 --> 00:28:31,310
我得為我的家人著想
I got to do what's best for my family.

349
00:28:31,340 --> 00:28:34,580
-確定嗎　-我們討論過了
- You sure? - We talked about it.

350
00:28:34,950 --> 00:28:37,080
我們決定了
We're sure.

351
00:28:37,120 --> 00:28:38,820
好吧
All right.

352
00:28:38,850 --> 00:28:40,750
-肖恩　-好吧
- Shane. - Yeah, all right.

353
00:28:40,790 --> 00:28:42,920
-點357那把嗎　-對
- .357? - Yeah.

354
00:28:48,360 --> 00:28:49,830
裡面還有一半子彈
The box is half full.

355
00:28:53,400 --> 00:28:56,730
謝謝你們　一切的一切
Thank you all... for everything.

356
00:28:56,770 --> 00:28:58,800
來
Come here.

357
00:28:59,580 --> 00:29:00,610
祝你好運　夥計
Good luck, man.

358
00:29:00,640 --> 00:29:02,710
感激不盡
Appreciate it.

359
00:29:03,880 --> 00:29:06,010
再見了
Bye.

360
00:29:06,050 --> 00:29:08,180
謝謝
Thank you.

361
00:29:08,210 --> 00:29:10,380
再見
Bye.

362
00:29:12,120 --> 00:29:14,590
如果改變主意　我們在40頻道
Channel 40 if you change your minds.

363
00:29:15,050 --> 00:29:16,450
-好嗎　-好
- All right? - Yeah.

364
00:29:17,230 --> 00:29:18,620
我知道
I know.

365
00:29:21,690 --> 00:29:24,230
你怎麼知道我們會更走運
What makes you think our odds are any better?

366
00:29:25,430 --> 00:29:27,600
來吧　動身吧
Come on. Let's go.

367
00:29:27,630 --> 00:29:30,500
出發
Let's move out.

368
00:29:38,450 --> 00:29:42,780
摩根　去疾控中心　這裡不安全　瑞克

369
00:31:02,530 --> 00:31:05,110
我早說過　這軟管撐不了多遠
I told you we'd never get far on that hose.

370
00:31:05,570 --> 00:31:07,880
得用那輛小貨車上的才行
I said I needed the one from the cube van.

371
00:31:08,690 --> 00:31:10,050
能想辦法湊合一下嗎
Can you jury-rig it?

372
00:31:10,420 --> 00:31:12,020
我一直在湊合了
That's all it's been so far.

373
00:31:12,050 --> 00:31:14,460
這是管道膠帶　不是軟管
It's more duct tape than hose.

374
00:31:14,980 --> 00:31:16,690
現在連膠帶都沒有了
And I'm out of duct tape.

375
00:31:18,230 --> 00:31:19,890
前面好像有東西
I see something up ahead.

376
00:31:20,640 --> 00:31:22,860
走運的話　會是個加油站
A gas station if we're lucky.

377
00:31:23,550 --> 00:31:25,370
各位　吉姆他
Y'all, Jim--

378
00:31:25,400 --> 00:31:28,170
情況不妙　我覺得他快不行了
It's bad. I don't think he can take anymore.

379
00:31:29,870 --> 00:31:31,810
瑞克　你照看一下這邊吧
Hey, Rick, you want to hold down the fort?

380
00:31:31,840 --> 00:31:33,670
我開到前面去　看能帶回點什麼來
I'll drive ahead, see what I can bring back.

381
00:31:33,710 --> 00:31:36,110
我也一起去　照應你一下
Yeah, I'll come along too and I'll back you up.

382
00:31:36,150 --> 00:31:37,780
你們都警惕一點
Y'all keep your eyes open now.

383
00:31:37,810 --> 00:31:39,380
我們馬上回來
We'll be right back.

384
00:31:47,260 --> 00:31:48,820
我們很開就能繼續前進
We'll be back on the road soon.

385
00:31:48,860 --> 00:31:51,230
不要　上帝啊
Oh no. Christ.

386
00:31:52,620 --> 00:31:53,690
我的骨頭
My bones--

387
00:31:54,160 --> 00:31:55,300
我的骨頭好像一觸即碎
my bones are like glass.

388
00:31:55,330 --> 00:31:56,800
一點顛簸都…
Every little bump--

389
00:31:56,830 --> 00:31:59,830
上帝　這一路快把我折磨死了
God, this ride is killing me.

390
00:32:00,820 --> 00:32:02,370
把我留在這吧
Leave me here.

391
00:32:05,280 --> 00:32:07,110
我完了
I'm done.

392
00:32:09,450 --> 00:32:11,680
別管我了
Just leave me.

393
00:32:12,660 --> 00:32:14,480
我想跟我的家人團聚
I want to be with my family.

394
00:32:19,220 --> 00:32:20,660
他們都去世了
They're all dead.

395
00:32:22,510 --> 00:32:24,890
我看你都不知道自己在說什麼
I don't think you know what you're asking.

396
00:32:24,930 --> 00:32:28,400
是發燒的緣故　你一直都神志不清
The fever-- you've been delirious more often than not.

397
00:32:28,430 --> 00:32:30,330
我知道　你以為我不知道嗎
I know. Don't you think I know?

398
00:32:35,340 --> 00:32:37,840
我現在清醒得很
I'm clear now.

399
00:32:37,870 --> 00:32:40,410
五分鐘後可能就清醒不了了
In five minutes I may not be.

400
00:32:40,440 --> 00:32:43,850
瑞克　我清楚自己在說什麼
Rick, I know what I'm asking.

401
00:32:44,230 --> 00:32:45,610
我希望如此
I want this.

402
00:32:47,350 --> 00:32:49,780
別管我了
Leave me here.

403
00:32:50,130 --> 00:32:51,950
責任我來承擔
Now that's on me.

404
00:32:53,150 --> 00:32:54,060
好嗎
Okay?

405
00:32:54,740 --> 00:32:56,120
是我的決定
My decision.

406
00:32:57,320 --> 00:32:58,860
不是你的失策
Not your failure.

407
00:33:04,530 --> 00:33:06,270
他說他想這樣
It's what he says he wants.

408
00:33:06,760 --> 00:33:09,040
他神志清楚嗎
And he's lucid?

409
00:33:09,070 --> 00:33:10,970
看來是的
He seems to be.

410
00:33:11,010 --> 00:33:13,370
我會答應的
I would say yes.

411
00:33:14,060 --> 00:33:16,880
在營地時　我說達裡爾可能是對的
Back in the camp when I said Daryl might be right

412
00:33:16,910 --> 00:33:18,980
你讓我閉嘴
and you shut me down,

413
00:33:19,640 --> 00:33:21,320
是你誤會我了
you misunderstood.

414
00:33:21,350 --> 00:33:24,590
我絕對不會贊同
I would never go along

415
00:33:24,620 --> 00:33:27,420
無情地結束一個人的生命
with callously killing a man.

416
00:33:27,460 --> 00:33:29,820
我只是想提議
I was just gonna suggest

417
00:33:30,620 --> 00:33:33,830
問問吉姆的想法
that we ask Jim what he wants.

418
00:33:35,930 --> 00:33:38,200
現在我們知道了
And I think we have an answer.

419
00:33:40,170 --> 00:33:41,800
就把他丟在這裡
We just leave him here?

420
00:33:41,840 --> 00:33:43,970
自己走掉嗎
We take off?

421
00:33:44,410 --> 00:33:46,710
那我想我不會原諒自己
Man, I'm not sure I could live with that.

422
00:33:47,070 --> 00:33:48,140
這不是你們的事
It's not your call,

423
00:33:49,340 --> 00:33:50,380
你們兩個說了都不算
either one of you.

424
00:33:54,150 --> 00:33:56,220
好　就這樣
Yeah. That's it.

425
00:34:01,420 --> 00:34:04,630
又是一棵爛樹
Hey, another damn tree.

426
00:34:07,250 --> 00:34:09,300
吉姆
Hey, Jim--

427
00:34:10,010 --> 00:34:11,870
你也知道　不一定非得這樣
I mean, you know it doesn't need to be this.

428
00:34:12,510 --> 00:34:13,870
不
No.

429
00:34:15,040 --> 00:34:16,940
這樣挺好的
It's good.

430
00:34:16,970 --> 00:34:19,140
微風拂面
The breeze feels nice.

431
00:34:20,000 --> 00:34:21,210
好
Okay.

432
00:34:21,610 --> 00:34:22,580
好吧
All right.

433
00:34:30,470 --> 00:34:32,350
閉上眼睛　親愛的
Just close your eyes, sweetie.

434
00:34:32,390 --> 00:34:34,090
不要硬撐了
Don't fight.

435
00:34:47,240 --> 00:34:50,440
吉姆　你要這個嗎
Jim, do you want this?

436
00:34:51,740 --> 00:34:53,140
不了
No.

437
00:34:54,140 --> 00:34:56,340
你自己會用得著
You'll need it.

438
00:34:58,710 --> 00:35:00,680
我沒事的
I'm okay.

439
00:35:03,020 --> 00:35:04,850
我沒事
I'm okay.

440
00:35:13,460 --> 00:35:15,760
謝謝你
Thanks for, uh,

441
00:35:15,800 --> 00:35:17,200
為我們而戰
for fighting for us.

442
00:35:18,140 --> 00:35:19,930
好的
Okay.

443
00:36:31,000 --> 00:36:35,310
野火計劃　最高位3417　已啟動
開始傳輸信息

444
00:36:36,830 --> 00:36:38,730
我是詹納
Jenner here.

445
00:36:39,210 --> 00:36:42,810
今天是野火計劃啟動後的第194天
It's day 194 since Wildfire was declared

446
00:36:42,850 --> 00:36:46,220
也是疾病突然全球爆發後的第63天
and 63 days since the disease abruptly went global.

447
00:36:46,700 --> 00:36:49,050
目前沒有臨床研究進展需要上報
There's no clinical progress to report.

448
00:36:53,890 --> 00:36:55,390
記錄1　我終於把東區的輻射防護器
Item-- I finally got the scrubbers

449
00:36:55,390 --> 00:36:57,290
給關掉了以便節省電力
in the east sector shut down to save power.

450
00:36:57,330 --> 00:36:58,730
真希望一個月前我就能關掉
Wish I could have done it a month ago,

451
00:36:58,760 --> 00:37:00,260
但我花了好久才搞清楚那些機器
but it took me that long to figure it out.

452
00:37:00,300 --> 00:37:01,860
可惜我從沒有學過工程
Too bad I never studied engineering.

453
00:37:01,900 --> 00:37:03,430
不然可以省很多電力
Could have saved a lot of amps.

454
00:37:03,470 --> 00:37:06,600
記錄2　我還是睡不好覺
Item-- I'm still not sleeping well.

455
00:37:07,670 --> 00:37:09,440
作息根本無法規律
Can't seem to keep regular hours.

456
00:37:09,860 --> 00:37:11,770
生活在地下的壞處
Living underground doesn't help,

457
00:37:11,810 --> 00:37:13,980
無法分辨白天黑夜
not knowing if it's day or night.

458
00:37:14,010 --> 00:37:18,580
這些日子我的狀態很不好
I'm just feeling very off-kilter these days.

459
00:37:22,410 --> 00:37:24,250
野火計劃　最高位3417　已啟動
信息已終止傳輸

460
00:38:29,750 --> 00:38:31,550
警備狀態
Alert status.

461
00:38:31,590 --> 00:38:34,390
空氣探測器警告出現腐蝕性煙霧
Air qualifiers indicate corrosive fumes.

462
00:38:34,420 --> 00:38:36,790
所有人員請立即離開
All personnel must clear the room.

463
00:38:36,830 --> 00:38:40,330
吸入該腐蝕性氣體　可致命
Corrosive element is deemed poisonous if inhaled.

464
00:38:56,550 --> 00:38:58,550
所有人員已離開
All personnel clear.

465
00:38:58,580 --> 00:39:00,580
全面消毒已啟動
Full decontamination in effect.

466
00:39:00,620 --> 00:39:02,580
不
No!

467
00:39:12,330 --> 00:39:15,060
全面消毒已完成
Full decontamination complete.

468
00:39:20,970 --> 00:39:23,840
第19號試驗樣本被毀了
The TS19 samples are gone.

469
00:39:23,870 --> 00:39:27,080
這無疑是一大慘痛損失
The tragedy of their loss cannot be overstated.

470
00:39:29,480 --> 00:39:31,980
它們可是迄今為止最新鮮的樣本
They were our freshest samples by far.

471
00:39:33,520 --> 00:39:36,250
我們採集的其它樣本根本無法與之相比
None of the other samples we gathered even came close.

472
00:39:37,650 --> 00:39:39,890
那些樣本都已壞死脫落
Those are necrotic,

473
00:39:39,920 --> 00:39:42,860
都是些無用的壞死組織
useless dead flesh.

474
00:39:47,900 --> 00:39:50,300
我都不知道我幹嘛跟你說話
I don't even know why I'm talking to you.

475
00:39:53,170 --> 00:39:55,370
我敢說外面連一個
I bet there isn't a single son of a bitch

476
00:39:55,400 --> 00:39:57,640
狗雜種的影子都沒　對不對
out there still listening, is there?

477
00:40:01,280 --> 00:40:03,480
對不對
Is there?

478
00:40:06,380 --> 00:40:08,180
算了
Fine.

479
00:40:08,220 --> 00:40:10,820
省得我跟你瞎瞪眼
Saves me the embarrassment.

480
00:40:17,090 --> 00:40:19,590
我看明天我還是一槍斃了自己好了
I think tomorrow I'm gonna blow my brains out.

481
00:40:22,330 --> 00:40:24,200
我還沒決定好
I haven't decided.

482
00:40:27,040 --> 00:40:28,770
但是今晚
But tonight,

483
00:40:29,200 --> 00:40:31,040
我要不醉不休
I'm getting drunk.

484
00:40:39,620 --> 00:40:41,550
說起這個
Speaking of which,

485
00:40:41,930 --> 00:40:44,020
你覺得我能拋多遠呢
how far do you think I can chuck this, huh?

486
00:40:45,520 --> 00:40:47,090
我看鐵定很遠
Pretty far I bet.

487
00:40:53,700 --> 00:40:55,830
都拋出場外了
It is out of the stadium!

488
00:41:29,930 --> 00:41:33,330
好了　大伙　繼續前進　繼續走
All right, everybody. Keep moving. Go on.

489
00:41:33,370 --> 00:41:36,100
保持安靜　繼續走
Stay quiet. Let's go.

490
00:41:54,920 --> 00:41:56,920
好了　繼續前進　都跟緊
Okay, keep moving. Stay together.

491
00:41:56,960 --> 00:41:59,760
-繼續前進　快點　-別吵
- Keep moving. Come on. - Shh.

492
00:42:03,170 --> 00:42:04,770
-卡蘿爾　-別吵
- Carol. - Shh.

493
00:42:04,800 --> 00:42:06,500
天吶
Oh, god.

494
00:42:29,270 --> 00:42:31,360
不是吧
No.

495
00:42:32,060 --> 00:42:33,630
大伙跟緊對方　快點
Keep it together. Come on.

496
00:42:33,660 --> 00:42:35,800
我們快到了　寶貝
We're almost there, baby.

497
00:42:35,830 --> 00:42:37,270
快到了
Almost there.

498
00:42:41,530 --> 00:42:42,370
啥都沒有嗎
Nothing?

499
00:42:47,910 --> 00:42:49,980
裡面沒人
There's nobody here.

500
00:42:50,010 --> 00:42:52,250
那為啥這些捲簾門都落下了
Then why are these shutters down?

501
00:42:52,280 --> 00:42:53,820
-有行屍　-寶貝　快點　　
- Walkers! - Baby, come on.

502
00:42:58,350 --> 00:43:00,360
你把我們送上了死路
You led us into a graveyard!

503
00:43:00,390 --> 00:43:02,620
-他做的決定　-這決定他媽的錯了
- He made a call. - It was the wrong damn call!

504
00:43:02,660 --> 00:43:05,230
閉嘴　你給我閉嘴　給我安靜點
Just shut up. You hear shut up. Shut up!

505
00:43:05,260 --> 00:43:06,570
瑞克　這是個死胡同 
Rick, this is a dead end.

506
00:43:06,570 --> 00:43:07,330
我們該去哪裡
Where are we gonna go?

507
00:43:07,360 --> 00:43:09,430
你聽到了嗎　別指責了
Do you hear me? No blame.

508
00:43:09,470 --> 00:43:10,300
她說得對　我們不能待在這裡 
She's right. We can't be here,

509
00:43:10,300 --> 00:43:11,500
天就要黑了　這裡離城區太近了
this close to the city after dark.

510
00:43:13,970 --> 00:43:15,840
瑞克　我們可以選擇前往本寧堡
Fort Benning, Rick-- still an option.

511
00:43:15,870 --> 00:43:17,740
怎麼去　沒有食物　沒有燃料
On what? No food, no fuel.

512
00:43:17,740 --> 00:43:18,740
而且還100英里遠
That's 100 miles.

513
00:43:18,770 --> 00:43:20,480
是125英里　我查過地圖
125. I checked the map.

514
00:43:20,510 --> 00:43:22,710
去他媽本寧堡　我們今晚該怎麼辦　
Forget Fort Benning. We need answers tonight, now.

515
00:43:22,750 --> 00:43:24,850
-讓我想想辦法　-快點　我們走
- Well, think of something. - Come on, let's go.

516
00:43:24,880 --> 00:43:28,080
-快點離開這　-我們走　快
- Let's get out of here. - Let's go. Please.

517
00:43:28,120 --> 00:43:30,720
好了　大伙都上車
All right, everybody back to the cars.

518
00:43:30,750 --> 00:43:33,090
-我們走　快點　-攝像頭動了
- Let's go. Move. - The camera-- it moved.

519
00:43:34,040 --> 00:43:36,760
-別做夢了　-真的動了
- You imagined it. - It moved.

520
00:43:36,790 --> 00:43:39,560
-它真的動了　-瑞克　這已經報廢了
- It moved. - Rick, it is dead, man.

521
00:43:39,600 --> 00:43:42,860
這是個自動裝置　是裝置而已　好嗎　
It's an automated device. It's gears, okay?

522
00:43:42,900 --> 00:43:44,470
不過是機器轉了回去　快點走吧
They're just winding down. Now come on.

523
00:43:44,500 --> 00:43:46,970
-不　走開　-哥們　聽我一句
- No, just go away. - Man, just listen to me.

524
00:43:47,000 --> 00:43:49,070
看看四周　這裡全報廢了　明白嗎
Look around this place. It's dead, okay?

525
00:43:49,100 --> 00:43:51,640
別再揪著這裡不放了　瑞克　
It's dead. You need to let it go, Rick.

526
00:43:51,670 --> 00:43:53,510
瑞克　這裡面沒人
Rick, there's nobody here!

527
00:43:53,540 --> 00:43:56,540
我知道你在裡面　我知道你能聽到我說話
I know you're in there. I know you can hear me.

528
00:43:56,580 --> 00:43:58,110
大伙馬上都給我回車上去
Everybody get back to the cars now!

529
00:43:58,110 --> 00:43:59,510
求求你　我們已經走投無路了
Please, we're desperate.

530
00:43:59,550 --> 00:44:01,850
請幫幫我們　我們這裡有婦女跟孩子
Please help us. We have women, children,

531
00:44:01,880 --> 00:44:03,990
-沒有食物　汽油也快沒了　-瑞克
- No food, hardly any gas left. - Rick.

532
00:44:04,020 --> 00:44:05,650
-裡面沒有人　-我們無處可去了
- There's nobody here. - We have nowhere else to go.

533
00:44:05,690 --> 00:44:07,820
警惕四周
Keep your eyes open.

534
00:44:07,860 --> 00:44:10,690
你不讓我們進去就等於在害死我們
If you don't let us in, you're killing us!

535
00:44:10,730 --> 00:44:13,630
-求求你了　-快點　哥們　咱們走
- Please! - Come on, buddy, let's go.

536
00:44:13,660 --> 00:44:15,160
-我們走　-請幫幫我們
- Let's go. - Please help us.

537
00:44:17,200 --> 00:44:20,440
你這是要害死我們　你不能見死不救
You're killing us! You're killing us!

538
00:44:20,470 --> 00:44:22,600
你是要害死我們
You're killing us!

