1
00:00:27,020 --> 00:00:28,650
運氣如何
Any luck?

2
00:00:30,490 --> 00:00:33,250
我們怎麼知道這菇有沒有毒
How do we tell if they're poison?

3
00:00:33,290 --> 00:00:36,760
我只知道一種保險的方法
Uh, there's only one sure way I know of.

4
00:00:38,990 --> 00:00:40,830
等肖恩回來了問他嗎
Ask Shane when he gets back?

5
00:00:40,860 --> 00:00:42,500
沒錯　回答正確
Yeah, you've got it.

6
00:00:42,530 --> 00:00:43,860
謝了
Thank you.

7
00:00:46,470 --> 00:00:49,040
戴爾　我出去一次
Dale, I'm heading out.

8
00:00:49,070 --> 00:00:51,910
寶貝　別走出戴爾的視線　好嗎
Sweetheart, I want you to stay where Dale can see you, okay?

9
00:00:51,940 --> 00:00:53,670
好的　媽媽
Yes, mom.

10
00:00:53,710 --> 00:00:55,910
你也是　別走太遠了
You too. Don't wander too far.

11
00:00:55,940 --> 00:00:57,510
走得太遠就聽不到喊聲了
Stay within shouting distance.

12
00:00:57,550 --> 00:01:00,350
你要是看到了什麼就大吼　我們很快就到
And if you see anything, holler. I'll come running.

13
00:01:00,380 --> 00:01:02,220
明白　老媽子
Yes, mom.

14
00:02:41,750 --> 00:02:43,720
你嚇死我了
You scared the hell out of me.

15
00:02:43,750 --> 00:02:45,990
我等了這麼久　得有點補償吧
I bet. That's what you get for keeping me waiting.

16
00:02:46,020 --> 00:02:47,520
我會儘量小聲點
I was trying to be quiet.

17
00:02:47,560 --> 00:02:49,720
-你去哪兒了　-艾米去採蘑菇了
- Where you been? - Amy the mushroom queen--

18
00:02:49,760 --> 00:02:51,890
我得等她回來才能過來
I had to wait for her to get back.

19
00:02:58,000 --> 00:03:00,230
-我們有多少時間　-夠多了
- How much time do we have? - Enough.

20
00:03:54,020 --> 00:03:55,890
-過來　-好
- Come here. - Okay.

21
00:04:03,790 --> 00:04:05,450
YYeTs人人影視誠意奉獻

22
00:04:07,620 --> 00:04:09,260
翻譯 anmoer 原子蛋

23
00:04:10,900 --> 00:04:12,690
翻譯 憶 zhanginfo

24
00:04:12,730 --> 00:04:14,560
翻譯 點點點 NaryKing

25
00:04:17,900 --> 00:04:19,100
時間軸 之間

26
00:04:19,100 --> 00:04:20,220
校對 海因裡希

27
00:04:20,220 --> 00:04:21,350
後期/特效 WiLL

28
00:04:21,350 --> 00:04:22,520
監製 海因裡希

29
00:04:22,530 --> 00:04:25,530
CHD版個人美化微修：字幕雷哥

30
00:04:34,100 --> 00:04:38,970
走

31
00:04:34,850 --> 00:04:38,970
肉

32
00:04:35,220 --> 00:04:38,970
行屍

33
00:04:35,220 --> 00:04:38,970
『第一季 第二集』

34
00:04:59,840 --> 00:05:01,380
喂　你還活著嗎
Hey, are you alive in there?

35
00:05:04,520 --> 00:05:06,880
-喂喂　-終於出聲了
- Hello? Hello? - There you are.

36
00:05:06,910 --> 00:05:08,650
讓我一陣好等
You had me wondering.

37
00:05:08,680 --> 00:05:10,220
你在哪裡　坦克外面嗎
Where are you? Outside?

38
00:05:10,250 --> 00:05:11,850
你現在能看到我嗎
Can you see me right now?

39
00:05:12,230 --> 00:05:14,050
對　我可以
Yeah, I can see you.

40
00:05:14,090 --> 00:05:16,860
壞消息是　你被行屍包圍了
You're surrounded by walkers. That's the bad news.

41
00:05:16,890 --> 00:05:18,760
那好消息呢
There's good news?

42
00:05:19,080 --> 00:05:21,600
-沒有好消息　-聽著　不管你是誰
- No. - Listen, whoever you are,

43
00:05:21,630 --> 00:05:24,230
我要告訴你　我在這裡真的很不爽
I don't mind telling you I'm a little concerned in here.

44
00:05:25,120 --> 00:05:27,870
夥計　你真該從我這看看
Oh man. You should see it from over here.

45
00:05:27,900 --> 00:05:30,400
你準會嚇癱掉
You'd be having a major freak-out.

46
00:05:31,340 --> 00:05:32,910
有什麼好建議給我嗎
Got any advice for me?

47
00:05:33,690 --> 00:05:36,280
有啊　你得逃出去
Yeah, I'd say make a run for it.

48
00:05:39,230 --> 00:05:40,410
「逃出去」　就這些嗎
That's it? "Make a run for it"?

49
00:05:41,150 --> 00:05:42,850
別一副不敢相信的樣子
My way's not as dumb as it sounds.

50
00:05:42,880 --> 00:05:44,450
要是你從我的角度看過去
You've got eyes on the outside here.

51
00:05:44,450 --> 00:05:45,850
就會看到只有一隻行屍還在上面
There's one geek still up

52
00:05:45,850 --> 00:05:47,490
其他都爬到坦克下面
on the tank but the others have climbed down

53
00:05:47,520 --> 00:05:49,240
啃那頓馬肉大餐去了
and joined the feeding frenzy where the horse went down.

54
00:05:49,240 --> 00:05:50,850
-聽明白嗎　-明白
- With me so far? - So far.

55
00:05:50,850 --> 00:05:53,580
坦克另一邊的街上沒那麼多行屍
Okay, the street on the other side of the tank is less crowded.

56
00:05:53,620 --> 00:05:56,180
趁他們不注意趕緊跑　你還有戲
If you move now while they're distracted, you stand a chance.

57
00:05:56,220 --> 00:05:58,950
-有彈藥嗎　-都丟在那個口袋裡了
- Got ammo? - In that duffel bag I dropped out there,

58
00:05:58,990 --> 00:06:00,450
還有槍　我能拿回來嗎
And guns. Can I get to it?

59
00:06:00,490 --> 00:06:02,990
別管那袋子了　想也別想
Forget the bag, okay? It's not an option.

60
00:06:03,020 --> 00:06:05,360
-你身上有什麼武器　-等下
- What do you have on you? - Hang on.

61
00:06:23,140 --> 00:06:26,410
好吧
Yeah. Yeah.

62
00:06:26,910 --> 00:06:29,540
我找到把貝雷塔手槍　一個彈匣
I've got a beretta with one clip,

63
00:06:29,580 --> 00:06:31,990
-15發子彈　-省著點用
- 15 rounds. - Make 'em count.

64
00:06:31,990 --> 00:06:33,500
跳到坦克的右側
Jump off the right side of the tank,

65
00:06:33,500 --> 00:06:34,740
一直沿著那個方向跑
keep going in that direction.

66
00:06:34,770 --> 00:06:37,270
跑個大概50碼會看到有條小路
There's an alley up the street, maybe 50 yards.

67
00:06:37,310 --> 00:06:39,210
那裡會合
Be there.

68
00:06:39,890 --> 00:06:42,030
你叫什麼
Hey, what's your name?

69
00:06:42,060 --> 00:06:44,860
你有沒有在聽　時間緊迫
Have you been listening? You're running out of time.

70
00:06:44,900 --> 00:06:46,130
好吧
Right.

71
00:07:16,900 --> 00:07:18,160
喂　我是活人
Whoa! Not dead!

72
00:07:18,160 --> 00:07:19,140
快點　快跑
Come on! Come on!

73
00:07:20,420 --> 00:07:22,190
這裡
Back here!

74
00:07:23,230 --> 00:07:25,860
快來
Come on! Come on!

75
00:07:30,170 --> 00:07:32,750
你幹毛呢　快上來
What are you doing?! Come on!

76
00:07:44,060 --> 00:07:45,900
快來　爬上去
Come on, get up.

77
00:07:57,390 --> 00:07:59,180
伊斯特伍德：美國硬派影星

78
00:07:57,390 --> 00:07:59,180
真犀利啊　伊斯特伍德
Nice moves there, Clint Eastwood.

79
00:07:59,210 --> 00:08:02,480
你個新治安官騎著馬過來清理治安嗎
You the new sheriff come riding in to clean up the town?

80
00:08:02,510 --> 00:08:05,680
-那可不是我的目的　-好吧　隨你了
- It wasn't my intention. - Yeah, whatever. Yeehaw.

81
00:08:05,720 --> 00:08:08,490
你還真是個傻瓜
You're still a dumbass.

82
00:08:08,520 --> 00:08:11,220
我叫瑞克　謝謝你
Rick. Thanks.

83
00:08:12,290 --> 00:08:14,590
我叫格倫　不用謝
Glenn. You're welcome.

84
00:08:16,470 --> 00:08:17,740
不是吧
Oh no.

85
00:08:25,170 --> 00:08:26,870
好消息是
The bright side:

86
00:08:27,120 --> 00:08:29,230
要是死了　好歹是摔死的
It'll be the fall that kills us.

87
00:08:29,260 --> 00:08:31,830
我這人比較樂天
I'm a glass-half-full kind of guy.

88
00:08:37,930 --> 00:08:39,930
是你在巷子裡設了路障嗎
Are you the one that barricaded the alley?

89
00:08:39,970 --> 00:08:42,600
別人設的　應該是在行屍佔領這裡之前
Somebody did-- I guess when the city got overrun.

90
00:08:42,600 --> 00:08:45,470
設路障的人肯定沒想到會有這麼多行屍
Whoever did it was thinking not many geeks would get through.

91
00:08:45,500 --> 00:08:47,640
我在坦克裡時　你為什麼要冒險幫我
Back at the tank, why'd you stick your neck out for me?

92
00:08:48,200 --> 00:08:50,010
抱著一種天真愚蠢的希望吧
Call it foolish, naive hope

93
00:08:50,040 --> 00:08:52,310
換作是我在裡面
that if I'm ever that far up shit creek,

94
00:08:52,340 --> 00:08:53,840
也希望有人來救我
somebody might do the same for me.

95
00:08:53,880 --> 00:08:56,480
說不定我會比你更白癡
Guess I'm an even bigger dumbass than you.

96
00:09:13,850 --> 00:09:17,110
我回來了　帶回一個人外加四個行屍
I'm back. Got a guest plus four geeks in the alley.

97
00:09:32,580 --> 00:09:34,520
快進去
Let's go!

98
00:09:36,420 --> 00:09:37,890
莫拉萊斯　撤
Morales, let's go!

99
00:09:41,190 --> 00:09:42,960
你他媽的　老子真想斃了你
You son of a bitch. We ought to kill you.

100
00:09:43,540 --> 00:09:45,100
淡定　安德莉亞　 放下槍　
Just chill out, Andrea. Back off.

101
00:09:45,100 --> 00:09:46,100
拜託　別激動
Come on, ease up.

102
00:09:46,130 --> 00:09:47,600
別激動　你搞毛
Ease up? You're kidding me, right?

103
00:09:47,630 --> 00:09:49,930
這傻逼害死我們了
We're dead because of this stupid asshole.

104
00:09:49,970 --> 00:09:53,600
安德莉亞　我說快他媽把槍放下
Andrea, I said back the hell off.

105
00:09:59,880 --> 00:10:01,140
行　你就開槍吧
Well, pull the trigger.

106
00:10:05,050 --> 00:10:07,420
我們死定了
We're dead-- all of us--

107
00:10:08,490 --> 00:10:10,320
拜你所賜
Because of you.

108
00:10:12,190 --> 00:10:14,470
我不明白
I don't understand.

109
00:10:14,480 --> 00:10:17,800
我們來這裡找點必需品
Look, we came into the city to scavenge supplies.

110
00:10:17,830 --> 00:10:20,070
你知道怎麼才能找嗎　得活著
You know what the key to scavenging is? Surviving!

111
00:10:20,100 --> 00:10:23,040
知道怎麼才能活著嗎　得低調行事 
You know the key to surviving? Sneaking in and out, tiptoeing.

112
00:10:23,070 --> 00:10:25,170
這麼大張旗鼓地開槍　你以為是決戰猶馬鎮嗎
Not shooting up the streets like it's the O.K.Corral.

113
00:10:25,210 --> 00:10:27,870
辟里啪啦的那些行屍大老遠都聽到了
Every geek for miles around heard you popping off rounds.

114
00:10:27,910 --> 00:10:30,110
你簡直就是給他們敲鐘開餐
You just rang the dinner bell.

115
00:10:30,140 --> 00:10:32,110
現在明白了嗎
Get the picture now?

116
00:10:39,050 --> 00:10:41,020
天吶
Oh god.

117
00:10:46,330 --> 00:10:48,660
話說　你到底在外面幹什麼
What the hell were you doing out there anyway?

118
00:10:48,700 --> 00:10:50,160
我想引起直升機的注意
Trying to flag the helicopter.

119
00:10:50,200 --> 00:10:52,100
直升機　靠　太扯淡了
Helicopter? Man, that's crap.

120
00:10:52,130 --> 00:10:54,230
-媽的哪來的直升機　-你丫的是
- Ain't no damn helicopter. - You were chasing a hallucination,

121
00:10:54,270 --> 00:10:56,740
-產生幻覺了吧　-我的確看見了
- imagining things. It happens. - I saw it.

122
00:10:57,620 --> 00:11:00,810
T仔　呼叫看看　看能聯繫上其他人嗎
Hey, T-dog, try that C.B. Can you contact the others?

123
00:11:00,840 --> 00:11:03,080
其他人　避難所的人嗎
Others? The refugee center?

124
00:11:03,110 --> 00:11:04,090
是啊　還避難所呢
Yeah, the refugee center.

125
00:11:04,090 --> 00:11:05,980
你是不是還指望有美味佳餚等著我們
They've got biscuits waiting at the oven for us.

126
00:11:06,010 --> 00:11:09,250
沒有信號　上樓頂試試
Got no signal. Maybe the roof.

127
00:11:11,240 --> 00:11:12,750
靠　是迪克森幹的嗎
Oh no. Is that Dixon?

128
00:11:12,790 --> 00:11:15,220
-這瘋子在幹什麼　-快快　快走
- What is that maniac doing? - Come on, let's go.

129
00:11:32,310 --> 00:11:35,340
喂　迪克森　你瘋了嗎
Hey, dixon, are you crazy?!

130
00:11:36,510 --> 00:11:38,680
我的天哪
Oh Jeez.

131
00:11:38,710 --> 00:11:42,580
我說　跟操著傢伙的人說話是不是該客氣點
Hey! Y'all be more polite to a man with a gun!

132
00:11:45,120 --> 00:11:46,630
這都不懂
Only common sense.

133
00:11:46,630 --> 00:11:49,080
靠　子彈都快沒了　你還浪費
Man, you wasting bullets we ain't even got!

134
00:11:49,080 --> 00:11:50,760
是不是想多招點行屍才好啊
And you're bringing even more of them down on our ass!

135
00:11:50,760 --> 00:11:51,830
你給我悠著點
Man, just chill.

136
00:11:51,840 --> 00:11:54,760
整天被墨西哥衰人嚷嚷也好不到哪去
Bad enough I've got this taco-bender on my ass all day.

137
00:11:54,800 --> 00:11:56,730
我要聽你嚷嚷嗎
Now I'm gonna take orders from you?

138
00:11:56,760 --> 00:11:59,690
沒門　夥計　怎麼可能
I don't think so, bro. That'll be the day.

139
00:11:59,690 --> 00:12:02,920
「怎麼可能」　對我有意見你就說啊
"That'll be the day"? You got something you want to tell me?

140
00:12:02,930 --> 00:12:04,340
-嘿　T仔　算了　-不行
- Hey, T-dog man, just leave it. - No.

141
00:12:04,370 --> 00:12:05,870
-算了　沒必要
- All right? It ain't worth it.

142
00:12:05,910 --> 00:12:09,040
莫爾　你消停了好吧
Now Merle, just relax, okay?

143
00:12:09,080 --> 00:12:11,040
我們麻煩夠多了
We've got enough trouble.

144
00:12:11,080 --> 00:12:13,550
-你想知道我有什麼意見　-對
- You want to know the day? - Yeah.

145
00:12:13,580 --> 00:12:16,250
那我就直說了　吆喝先生
I'll tell you the day, Mr."Yo."

146
00:12:16,280 --> 00:12:17,970
哥不想聽黑鬼吆喝
It's the day I take orders from a nigger.

147
00:12:17,970 --> 00:12:20,370
-狗日的　-莫爾　算了
- Motherfucker! - Hey, come on, Merle. That's enough.

148
00:12:20,410 --> 00:12:22,110
算了
Come on.

149
00:12:22,140 --> 00:12:24,310
迪克森
Dixon!

150
00:12:24,350 --> 00:12:25,810
我靠　別打了
Whoa, cut it out, man!

151
00:12:25,850 --> 00:12:29,120
住手　迪克森　住手
Stop it! Dixon, get off him!

152
00:12:29,150 --> 00:12:30,450
迪克森　你會打傷他的
Dixon, you're gonna hurt him.

153
00:12:33,750 --> 00:12:36,290
莫爾　別鬧了
Merle, cut it out!

154
00:12:44,040 --> 00:12:46,140
不要啊　求你了
No no no, please. Please.

155
00:13:05,080 --> 00:13:07,660
行啊　好說
Yeah! All right!

156
00:13:07,670 --> 00:13:11,000
咱們就來開個小會
We're gonna have ourselves a little powwow, huh?

157
00:13:11,250 --> 00:13:14,850
來決定誰當老大
Talk about who's in charge.

158
00:13:15,220 --> 00:13:18,120
我投我自己　你們呢
I vote me. Anybody else?

159
00:13:18,160 --> 00:13:20,770
丫們也來搞點民主
Huh? Democracy time, y'all.

160
00:13:20,770 --> 00:13:22,860
投票的舉手啊
Show of hands, huh?

161
00:13:22,860 --> 00:13:26,110
大家都同意嗎
All in favor? Huh?

162
00:13:26,610 --> 00:13:28,640
快點啊　投票
Come on. Let's see 'em.

163
00:13:28,680 --> 00:13:29,850
快點
Oh, come on.

164
00:13:29,880 --> 00:13:31,750
都同意嗎
All in favor?

165
00:13:31,780 --> 00:13:35,250
可以　很好
Yeah. That's good.

166
00:13:35,290 --> 00:13:38,690
現在我說了算　沒錯吧
Now that means I'm the boss, right?

167
00:13:38,720 --> 00:13:42,060
還有誰有異議
Yeah. Anybody else?

168
00:13:42,090 --> 00:13:44,890
-誰有異議　-我
- Hmm? Anybody?　- Yeah.

169
00:13:55,610 --> 00:13:58,310
-你他媽的是誰啊　-友好的警官
- Who the hell are you, man?!　- Officer friendly.

170
00:14:00,710 --> 00:14:03,780
聽著　莫爾　情況變了
Look here, Merle. Things are different now.

171
00:14:03,810 --> 00:14:06,700
不搞種族歧視
There are no niggers anymore.

172
00:14:06,700 --> 00:14:09,990
也不搞白人優越主義
No dumb-as-shit, inbred white-trash fools either.

173
00:14:10,020 --> 00:14:12,590
我們不過是待宰割的人肉
Only dark meat and white meat.

174
00:14:12,620 --> 00:14:14,420
現在只有活人和行屍之分
There's us and the dead.

175
00:14:14,460 --> 00:14:16,390
只有齊心協力才能活下去
We survive this by pulling together,

176
00:14:16,430 --> 00:14:19,130
-別搞分裂　-你去死吧
- Not apart.　- Screw you, man.

177
00:14:20,660 --> 00:14:23,170
看來你聽話不愛聽重點
I can see you make a habit of missing the point.

178
00:14:23,200 --> 00:14:25,670
是嗎　那你就再死一次吧
Yeah? Well, screw you twice.

179
00:14:25,700 --> 00:14:27,870
對帶著槍的人說話別太囂張
Ought to be polite to a man with a gun.

180
00:14:27,910 --> 00:14:29,610
給點常識好不
Only common sense.

181
00:14:31,640 --> 00:14:34,980
你不會開槍的　你是個警察
You wouldn't. You're a cop.

182
00:14:36,610 --> 00:14:38,110
現在的我
All I am anymore

183
00:14:38,150 --> 00:14:40,650
只想找回自己的妻兒
is a man looking for his wife and son.

184
00:14:40,680 --> 00:14:43,750
擋我者死
Anybody that gets in the way of that is gonna lose.

185
00:14:45,620 --> 00:14:48,190
給些時間你好好想想
I'll give you a moment to think about that.

186
00:14:58,640 --> 00:15:00,770
還想嘗嘗嗎
Got some on your nose there.

187
00:15:00,800 --> 00:15:03,070
你要拿我怎麼樣
What are you gonna do?

188
00:15:03,110 --> 00:15:04,710
逮捕我嗎
Arrest me?

189
00:15:04,740 --> 00:15:07,710
你搞什麼　那是我的私人財產
Hey! What are you doing? Man, that was my stuff!

190
00:15:09,980 --> 00:15:12,050
一旦我鬆綁　你就死定了
If I get loose, you'd better pray--

191
00:15:12,080 --> 00:15:14,920
聽到嗎　你這頭豬
Yeah, you hear me, you pig?!

192
00:15:14,950 --> 00:15:16,920
-聽到沒有　-聽得到你在瞎喊
- You hear me?!　- Yeah, your voice carries.

193
00:15:16,950 --> 00:15:19,060
聽到沒有　你這噁心的豬
Do you hear me, you filthy pig?!

194
00:15:22,280 --> 00:15:23,730
你不是亞特蘭大的警官
You're not Atlanta P.D.

195
00:15:24,670 --> 00:15:28,910
-你哪兒來的　-大路的另一頭
- Where you from?　- Up the road a ways.

196
00:15:29,800 --> 00:15:33,870
來自大路另一頭的友好警官
Well, officer friendly from up the road a ways,

197
00:15:33,910 --> 00:15:35,670
歡迎你來到大城市
welcome to the big city.

198
00:15:46,980 --> 00:15:49,030
天啊　下面就像時代廣場一樣
My god, it's like Times Square down there.

199
00:15:49,030 --> 00:15:52,420
-信號怎麼樣　-就像迪克森的腦袋
- How's that signal?　- Like Dixon's brain--

200
00:15:52,450 --> 00:15:55,520
殘得可以
Weak.

201
00:15:55,550 --> 00:15:57,970
-繼續試　-何必呢　他們什麼也做不了
- Keep trying.　- Why? There's nothing they can do.

202
00:15:57,970 --> 00:16:00,060
屁用也沒有
Not a damn thing.

203
00:16:00,090 --> 00:16:02,340
首要任務是離開這個城市
Got some people outside the city is all.

204
00:16:02,340 --> 00:16:04,680
根本就沒有什麼避難所　別作夢了
There's no refugee center. That's a pipe dream.

205
00:16:04,710 --> 00:16:06,680
她說的對　我們得靠自己
Then she's right. We're on our own.

206
00:16:06,710 --> 00:16:08,010
我們要自己找出路
It's up to us to find a way out.

207
00:16:08,050 --> 00:16:09,550
祝你好運
Good luck with that.

208
00:16:09,580 --> 00:16:12,450
據我所知　市裡這塊不太安全
These streets ain't safe in this part of town from what I hear.

209
00:16:13,440 --> 00:16:15,690
對吧　甜心
Ain't that right, sugar tizz?

210
00:16:15,720 --> 00:16:17,960
寶貝兒
Hey, honeybunch,

211
00:16:17,990 --> 00:16:19,760
幫我解開手銬行不
What say you get me out of these cuffs,

212
00:16:19,790 --> 00:16:23,030
我們找個地方然後大幹一場
We go off somewhere and bump some uglies?

213
00:16:23,990 --> 00:16:26,530
-反正都要死了　-還不如讓我死
- Gonna die anyway.　- I'd rather.

214
00:16:28,040 --> 00:16:31,340
好吧　我懂了　原來你是硬骨頭啊
Rod Muncher. I figured as much.

215
00:16:31,370 --> 00:16:33,400
走大街出去不安全
The streets ain't safe.

216
00:16:33,440 --> 00:16:35,170
這我們都同意
Now there's an understatement.

217
00:16:35,210 --> 00:16:37,980
大街底下呢　走下水道
What about under the streets? The sewers?

218
00:16:38,010 --> 00:16:40,080
等等
Oh man.

219
00:16:40,110 --> 00:16:42,180
格倫　看看那小巷
Hey, Glenn, check the alley.

220
00:16:42,210 --> 00:16:43,850
看看有沒有井蓋
You see any manhole covers?

221
00:16:52,590 --> 00:16:55,830
沒有　一定在滿是行屍的大街上
No, must be all out on the street where the geeks are.

222
00:16:55,860 --> 00:16:59,060
不一定　像這樣的二十世紀的老建築
Maybe not. Old building like this built in the '20s--

223
00:16:59,100 --> 00:17:00,790
大型建築物在負二層都有
Big structures often had drainage tunnels

224
00:17:00,790 --> 00:17:04,440
防洪用的通往下水道的排水管道
into the sewers in case of flooding down in the subbasements.

225
00:17:04,470 --> 00:17:07,210
-你怎麼知道　-這是我的工作　曾經是
- How do you know that?　- It's my job-- was.

226
00:17:07,240 --> 00:17:08,940
我在城市規劃辦公室工作
I worked in the city zoning office.

227
00:17:21,190 --> 00:17:23,390
是這裡嗎　你確定嗎
This is it? Are you sure?

228
00:17:24,100 --> 00:17:26,320
我以前把這裡上下搜了個遍
I really scoped this place out the other times I was here.

229
00:17:26,360 --> 00:17:28,430
這是這棟樓裡唯一通往底下的路
It's the only thing in the building that goes down.

230
00:17:29,530 --> 00:17:31,060
但我從沒下去過
But I've never gone down it.

231
00:17:32,250 --> 00:17:33,530
誰會想下去啊
Who'd want to, right?

232
00:17:38,200 --> 00:17:40,870
好吧
Oh. Great.

233
00:17:42,470 --> 00:17:43,060
我們跟在你後面
We'll be right behind you.

234
00:17:43,060 --> 00:17:44,910
不行　至少你不行
No, you won't. Not you.

235
00:17:44,940 --> 00:17:47,180
為什麼　覺得我不敢嗎
Why not me? Think I can't?

236
00:17:47,830 --> 00:17:49,180
不是
I wasn't--

237
00:17:49,210 --> 00:17:50,820
想說什麼就說吧
Speak your mind.

238
00:17:52,720 --> 00:17:56,990
到目前為止　我總是獨自一人
Look, until now I always came here by myself--

239
00:17:57,020 --> 00:17:59,620
進進出出　拿些東西　都不是問題
In and out, grab a few things-- no problem.

240
00:17:59,660 --> 00:18:02,290
我第一次帶上一隊人馬　就整個亂套了
The first time I bring a group-- everything goes to hell.

241
00:18:02,330 --> 00:18:04,100
毫無冒犯之意
No offense.

242
00:18:06,130 --> 00:18:08,770
如果你們要我從這洞裡下去　沒問題
If you want me to go down this gnarly hole, fine--

243
00:18:09,870 --> 00:18:12,200
但得由我說了算
But only if we do it my way.

244
00:18:12,240 --> 00:18:12,900
下面很狹窄
It's tight down there.

245
00:18:13,320 --> 00:18:15,110
如果我遇到了什麼　能儘快逃出來
If I run into something and have to get out quick,

246
00:18:15,140 --> 00:18:17,340
我可不想你們跟在後面堵路　害我被殺
I don't want you all jammed up behind me getting me killed.

247
00:18:18,540 --> 00:18:21,950
我只帶一個人　你也不行
I'll take one person-- not you either.

248
00:18:21,980 --> 00:18:24,350
你有莫爾的槍　我也見識過你的槍法
You've got Merle's gun and I've seen you shoot.

249
00:18:24,380 --> 00:18:26,250
你得在裡面把守店門　保護大家
I'd feel better if you were out in that store

250
00:18:26,290 --> 00:18:28,490
這樣我會更放心　
watching those doors, covering our ass.

251
00:18:28,520 --> 00:18:30,820
就你還有把槍　所以你該和他一起
And you've got the only other gun, so you should go with him.

252
00:18:30,860 --> 00:18:33,930
你做我策應　傑奎就待這裡
You be my wingman. Jacqui stays here.

253
00:18:33,960 --> 00:18:35,960
一有情況就衝下面喊
Something happens, yell down to us,

254
00:18:35,990 --> 00:18:37,560
-馬上把我們弄上來　-好
- get us back up here in a hurry. - Okay.

255
00:18:37,600 --> 00:18:40,700
那好　大家各司其職
Okay, everybody knows their jobs.

256
00:19:21,670 --> 00:19:23,040
靠
Dah!

257
00:19:47,570 --> 00:19:49,570
抱歉　我拿槍指著你
Sorry for the gun in your face.

258
00:19:50,800 --> 00:19:53,070
人害怕時難免會衝動
People do things when they're afraid.

259
00:19:53,110 --> 00:19:55,410
不　那太不應該了
Not that was entirely unjustified.

260
00:19:56,010 --> 00:19:58,310
可你的確陷我們於絕境
You did get us into this.

261
00:19:58,340 --> 00:20:00,480
要是我幫大家逃出去可以彌補嗎
If I get us out, would that make up for it?

262
00:20:00,510 --> 00:20:03,880
彌補不了　不過算是個好開始
No, but it'd be a start.

263
00:20:16,190 --> 00:20:18,830
以後得先打開保險
Next time though, take the safety off.

264
00:20:18,860 --> 00:20:20,360
否則開不了槍
It won't shoot otherwise.

265
00:20:22,430 --> 00:20:24,740
自己的槍嗎
Is that your gun?

266
00:20:24,770 --> 00:20:26,740
是個禮物　怎麼了
It was a gift. Why?

267
00:20:31,040 --> 00:20:33,240
小紅點說明保險打開了
Little red dot means it's ready to fire.

268
00:20:33,870 --> 00:20:35,610
也許你要用到它
You may have occasion to use it.

269
00:20:38,420 --> 00:20:40,380
謝謝提醒
Good to know.

270
00:20:44,000 --> 00:20:45,560
有人在嗎
Anybody out there?

271
00:20:48,890 --> 00:20:51,630
喂　有人收到嗎
Hello? Anybody read?

272
00:20:51,660 --> 00:20:53,130
真希望聽到別人的聲音
I'm hoping to hear somebody's voice

273
00:20:53,170 --> 00:20:55,030
因為只有自己的聲音太鬱悶了
'cause I'm getting sick and tired of hearing mine.

274
00:20:55,070 --> 00:20:57,470
對　不過是我們倆
Yeah, well, that makes two of us.

275
00:20:57,500 --> 00:20:59,500
幹嘛不扔了那破無線電
Why don't you knock that crap off?

276
00:20:59,540 --> 00:21:01,110
這讓我頭疼　小子
You're giving me a headache, boy.

277
00:21:02,370 --> 00:21:03,910
你幹嘛不把腦袋坐到屁股底下
Why don't you pull your head out of your ass?

278
00:21:03,940 --> 00:21:05,740
那你的頭就不疼了
Maybe your headache will go away.

279
00:21:05,780 --> 00:21:09,650
媽的　還是想點好事吧
Try some positivity for a change. Damn.

280
00:21:09,680 --> 00:21:11,480
我跟你說
I'll tell you what,

281
00:21:11,520 --> 00:21:12,980
你幫我把手銬解開
you get me out of these cuffs

282
00:21:13,020 --> 00:21:15,720
我一定給你好好當靠山
and I'll be all "Sammy sunshine" positive for you.

283
00:21:17,020 --> 00:21:21,390
看到那邊工具箱裡的鋼鋸了嗎
Hey, see that hacksaw over there in that toolbag?

284
00:21:22,960 --> 00:21:26,860
幫我拿過來怎麼樣　肯定有你好處
Get it for me, hmm? Make it worth your while.

285
00:21:26,900 --> 00:21:28,630
怎麼樣夥計　快點吧
What do you say, man? Come on.

286
00:21:29,130 --> 00:21:30,530
幫我弄掉這銬子
Get me out of these things.

287
00:21:30,570 --> 00:21:32,640
然後接著揍我嗎
So you can beat my ass again?

288
00:21:34,630 --> 00:21:36,240
要不就是多叫我幾聲「黑鬼」
Or call me nigger some more?

289
00:21:36,970 --> 00:21:38,440
說什麼啊　又不是針對你
Come on now. It wasn't personal.

290
00:21:38,440 --> 00:21:41,710
也就是咱倆意見有點不合罷了
It's just that your kind and my kind ain't meant to mix.

291
00:21:42,340 --> 00:21:43,950
有什麼大不了
That's all.

292
00:21:43,980 --> 00:21:46,720
又不是說咱倆就不能合作了
It don't mean we can't... work together,

293
00:21:46,750 --> 00:21:49,850
好好談談　只要我們大家能雙贏
parley, as long as there's some kind of mutual gain involved.

294
00:21:53,090 --> 00:21:56,530
那麼　鋼鋸的事
So... about that hacksaw--

295
00:21:56,560 --> 00:21:58,630
恐怕你還想讓我幫你拿那支步槍吧
I guess you want me to get that rifle over there too

296
00:21:58,660 --> 00:22:01,030
然後等那警察上來時一槍斃了他
so you can shoot that cop when he comes back up, huh?

297
00:22:16,420 --> 00:22:19,750
看來我們是到污水管道了
Yeah, we've got ourselves a sewer tunnel.

298
00:22:19,790 --> 00:22:21,450
傑奎說的對
Jacqui was right.

299
00:22:22,620 --> 00:22:24,360
這能切開嗎
Can we cut through it?

300
00:22:24,390 --> 00:22:27,220
能啊　只要給我個噴燈再來半天時間
If we had a blowtorch and half a day, sure.

301
00:22:28,030 --> 00:22:30,160
戴爾的鋼鋸肯定沒戲
Dale's hacksaw sure as hell won't do it.

302
00:22:51,620 --> 00:22:53,320
看上什麼了
See something you like?

303
00:22:53,350 --> 00:22:56,750
不是我　不過有個人肯定喜歡
Not me, but I know someone who would.

304
00:22:58,290 --> 00:23:00,390
我妹妹
My sister.

305
00:23:00,430 --> 00:23:02,890
在有些方面她還像個孩子
She's still such a kid in some ways.

306
00:23:02,930 --> 00:23:04,830
獨角獸啊　龍啊
Unicorns, dragons.

307
00:23:05,340 --> 00:23:06,660
她就癡迷那類東西
She's into all that stuff.

308
00:23:06,700 --> 00:23:09,000
說到美人魚　她最喜歡了
But mermaids, they rule.

309
00:23:09,030 --> 00:23:11,770
她喜歡美人魚
She loves mermaids.

310
00:23:11,800 --> 00:23:13,370
拿走不就得了
Why not take it?

311
00:23:14,610 --> 00:23:16,710
可有個警察正盯著我呢
There's a cop staring at me.

312
00:23:21,700 --> 00:23:23,280
這算行竊嗎
Would it be considered looting?

313
00:23:25,720 --> 00:23:28,750
我認為那些規矩都作廢了　你看呢
I don't think those rules apply anymore. Do you?

314
00:23:46,960 --> 00:23:48,910
-你們在下面發現什麼了　-出不去
- What did you find down there? - Not a way out.

315
00:23:50,540 --> 00:23:52,110
我們得找條路
We need to find a way...

316
00:23:52,730 --> 00:23:53,740
馬上
and soon.

317
00:24:01,720 --> 00:24:02,760
瞧工地那邊
That construction site,

318
00:24:02,760 --> 00:24:04,790
卡車司機總是把鑰匙放在一起
those trucks, they always keep keys on hand.

319
00:24:07,470 --> 00:24:09,360
根本沒辦法穿過那片行屍
You'll never make it past the walkers.

320
00:24:09,390 --> 00:24:10,760
可你幫我從坦克裡逃了出去
You got me out of that tank.

321
00:24:10,790 --> 00:24:13,300
是　可他們當時在吃東西　都魂不守舍
Yeah, but they were feeding. They were distracted.

322
00:24:13,330 --> 00:24:14,830
我們能再讓它們分神嗎
Can we distract them again?

323
00:24:14,860 --> 00:24:17,200
就是　聽他的　他什麼不知道啊
Right. Listen to him. He's onto something.

324
00:24:17,230 --> 00:24:19,700
還「聲東擊西」呢　從電影裡學的吧
A diversion, like on "Hogan's heroes."

325
00:24:19,740 --> 00:24:22,770
-拜託　你能消停一下嗎　-他們是聽聲辨物嗎
- God. Give it a rest. - They're drawn by sound, right?

326
00:24:23,250 --> 00:24:25,970
對　就像狗　聽到動靜就跑來了
Right, like dogs. They hear a sound, they come.

327
00:24:26,010 --> 00:24:27,880
-還有呢　-除了能聽到你嗎
- What else? - Aside from they hear you?

328
00:24:27,910 --> 00:24:30,610
他們用嗅覺辨認　一旦抓到就立刻吃掉
They see you, smell you and if they catch you, they eat you.

329
00:24:31,330 --> 00:24:33,650
-他們會分辨我們的氣味　-你聞不出來嗎
- They can tell us by smell? - Can't you?

330
00:24:33,680 --> 00:24:36,320
他們身上有腐屍味　我們沒有　多明顯的區別
They smell dead, we don't. It's pretty distinct.

331
00:24:41,940 --> 00:24:43,410
如果壞主意也有奧運會的話
If bad ideas were an Olympic event,

332
00:24:43,410 --> 00:24:45,250
-這個絕對是金牌得主　-他說的沒錯
- This would take the gold. - He's right.

333
00:24:45,280 --> 00:24:47,480
快停手　慢慢來考慮清楚　好嗎
Just stop, okay? Take some time to think this through.

334
00:24:47,520 --> 00:24:49,980
要多慢　他們已經穿過第一道門了　
How much time? They already got through one set of doors,

335
00:24:50,020 --> 00:24:51,890
這玻璃也撐不了多久
That glass won't hold forever.

336
00:25:48,780 --> 00:25:50,340
韋恩·鄧拉普
Wayne Dunlap.

337
00:25:50,380 --> 00:25:52,550
佐治亞州人
Georgia license.

338
00:25:52,580 --> 00:25:56,580
1979年出生
Born in 1979.

339
00:26:01,090 --> 00:26:04,530
去世時身上有28美元
He had $28 in his pocket when he died...

340
00:26:06,330 --> 00:26:08,330
和一個女生的照片　她很漂亮
and a picture of a pretty girl.

341
00:26:11,730 --> 00:26:15,040
「愛你的蕾切爾贈」
"With love, from Rachel."

342
00:26:16,100 --> 00:26:17,540
他曾像我們一樣
He used to be like us--

343
00:26:18,240 --> 00:26:19,790
為賬單和房租發愁
worrying about bills

344
00:26:19,820 --> 00:26:23,260
或者超級杯橄欖球聯賽
or the rent or the Super Bowl.

345
00:26:26,000 --> 00:26:29,430
如果我能與家人團聚　一定向他們說起韋恩
If I ever find my family, I'm gonna tell them about Wayne.

346
00:26:37,710 --> 00:26:39,810
還有一件事
One more thing--

347
00:26:41,210 --> 00:26:43,380
他曾是名器官捐贈者
he was an organ donor.

348
00:26:48,120 --> 00:26:50,620
聖母瑪利亞
Madre de dios!

349
00:26:51,720 --> 00:26:54,430
上帝
Oh! God!

350
00:26:54,460 --> 00:26:55,960
太噁心了
Gack!

351
00:26:55,990 --> 00:26:57,260
上帝啊　
Oh God.

352
00:26:59,000 --> 00:27:02,000
神啊
Dios!

353
00:27:02,030 --> 00:27:03,670
天吶
Oh god.

354
00:27:17,120 --> 00:27:19,280
繼續砍
Keep chopping.

355
00:27:22,450 --> 00:27:25,160
-快吐了我　-等會再吐
- I am so gonna hurl. - Later.

356
00:27:39,470 --> 00:27:41,340
大家手套都戴好了嗎
Everybody got gloves?

357
00:27:42,930 --> 00:27:45,740
千萬別弄到皮膚上或眼睛裡
Don't get any on your skin or in your eyes.

358
00:28:14,070 --> 00:28:16,040
上帝
Oh god!

359
00:28:16,070 --> 00:28:19,110
天吶　太糟了
Oh jeez. Oh, this is bad.

360
00:28:19,140 --> 00:28:20,710
糟的不能再糟了
This is really bad.

361
00:28:20,750 --> 00:28:22,210
想想別的事
Think about something else--

362
00:28:22,250 --> 00:28:23,810
小狗小貓的
puppies and kittens.

363
00:28:23,850 --> 00:28:25,880
死狗死貓還差不多
Dead puppies and kittens.

364
00:28:29,390 --> 00:28:31,800
太不厚道了　你怎麼回事
That is just evil. What is wrong with you?

365
00:28:31,800 --> 00:28:34,360
下一次讓那瘋子好好修理修理他
Next time let the cracker beat his ass.

366
00:28:34,990 --> 00:28:37,930
-對不起了　-你個混蛋
- I'm sorry, yo. - You suck.

367
00:28:41,470 --> 00:28:44,640
-跟他們味道一樣了嗎　-能不一樣嗎
- Do we smell like them? - Oh yeah.

368
00:28:45,800 --> 00:28:47,640
格倫
Glenn.

369
00:28:49,670 --> 00:28:51,480
以防萬一吧
Just in case.

370
00:28:58,920 --> 00:29:00,630
如果我們回得來　你們要準備好
If we make it back, be ready.

371
00:29:00,630 --> 00:29:02,750
那莫爾·迪克森怎麼辦
What about Merle Dixon?

372
00:29:15,730 --> 00:29:17,400
把斧子給我
Give me the axe.

373
00:29:19,100 --> 00:29:22,510
-得多弄點內臟　-天啊
- We need-- we need more guts. - Oh god!

374
00:31:13,860 --> 00:31:15,330
怎麼回事　夥計
Hey, what's happening, man?

375
00:31:15,360 --> 00:31:17,630
T仔　試試那個民用電台
Hey, T-dog, try that C.B.

376
00:31:17,660 --> 00:31:19,430
拜託　你們倒是跟我說句話啊
Hey, come on. Talk to me, y'all.

377
00:31:19,460 --> 00:31:22,500
呼叫大本營　我是T仔　有人收到嗎
Base camp, this is T-dog. Anybody hear me?

378
00:31:22,530 --> 00:31:24,600
有人能收到我的信息嗎
Can anybody out there hear me?

379
00:31:26,510 --> 00:31:27,060
那裡
There.

380
00:31:29,640 --> 00:31:32,340
那混蛋帶著手銬鑰匙走了嗎
That asshole is out on the street with the handcuff keys?

381
00:31:44,530 --> 00:31:47,260
夥計　軟管不夠長啊
Boy, that hose isn't long for this world, is it?

382
00:31:48,330 --> 00:31:49,830
是不夠　先生
No sir.

383
00:31:49,860 --> 00:31:52,760
到底哪裡能他媽的給換一個
Where the hell are we gonna find a replacement?

384
00:31:54,030 --> 00:31:56,170
天色很晚了　他們應該回來了才對
It's late. They should've been back by now.

385
00:31:56,200 --> 00:31:58,370
擔心也沒用
Worrying won't make it better.

386
00:32:04,980 --> 00:32:06,510
幹得好　就這樣
Attaboy. Yeah.

387
00:32:06,550 --> 00:32:08,550
三二一　拉出來
And three, two, one-- pull it.

388
00:32:12,020 --> 00:32:13,980
再來一次
Start it over.

389
00:32:15,490 --> 00:32:17,790
這樣做「P」字　繞著手指來
Make your "P" the other way-- around your finger.

390
00:32:19,410 --> 00:32:21,090
很好　像纏在手指上一樣綁起來
Good, just tie it like around your finger.

391
00:32:22,330 --> 00:32:23,930
好樣的
Attaboy.

392
00:32:23,960 --> 00:32:26,000
呼叫大本營
Hello, base camp!

393
00:32:27,500 --> 00:32:29,830
有人能收到信息嗎
Can anybody out there hear me?

394
00:32:33,640 --> 00:32:36,640
大本營　我是T仔　有人收到嗎
Base camp, this is T-dog. Anybody hear me?

395
00:32:37,420 --> 00:32:38,540
喂　你好
Hello? Hello?

396
00:32:38,580 --> 00:32:40,310
這邊信號不太好
Reception's bad on this end.

397
00:32:40,350 --> 00:32:43,510
-請重複　請重複　-肖恩　是你嗎
- Repeat. Repeat. - Shane, is that you?

398
00:32:43,550 --> 00:32:45,050
是他們嗎
Is that them?

399
00:32:45,710 --> 00:32:46,800
我們有麻煩了
We're in some deep shit.

400
00:32:46,800 --> 00:32:48,650
我們被困在百貨公司裡了
We're trapped in the department store.

401
00:32:50,710 --> 00:32:52,960
-他說他們被困住了　-這到處都是怪物
- He say they're trapped? - There are geeks all over the place.

402
00:32:52,990 --> 00:32:55,660
有成百上千個　我們被包圍了
Hundreds of 'em. We're surrounded.

403
00:32:55,690 --> 00:32:57,860
T仔　請重複最後一句　重複下
T-dog, repeat that last. Repeat.

404
00:33:05,750 --> 00:33:07,050
他剛說的是百貨商店
He said the department store.

405
00:33:07,050 --> 00:33:10,210
我也聽見了
I heard it too.

406
00:33:10,720 --> 00:33:12,280
-肖恩　-不行
- Shane? - No way.

407
00:33:12,310 --> 00:33:14,040
我們不能去找他們
We do not go after them.

408
00:33:14,080 --> 00:33:15,910
不能讓剩下的成員冒險
We do not risk the rest of the group.

409
00:33:15,950 --> 00:33:18,620
-你們也知道　-就這麼撒手不管了嗎
- Y'all know that. - So we're just gonna leave her there?

410
00:33:19,050 --> 00:33:21,920
艾米　我知道這很難接受…
Look, Amy, I know that this is not easy--

411
00:33:21,920 --> 00:33:24,090
為了我們大家
She volunteered to go

412
00:33:24,120 --> 00:33:25,790
她自告奮勇前往城裡
to help the rest of us.

413
00:33:25,820 --> 00:33:28,430
沒錯　但她知道其中的風險吧
I know, and she knew the risks, right?

414
00:33:29,030 --> 00:33:32,200
要是她被困住　那麼就死定了
See, if she's trapped, she's gone.

415
00:33:32,610 --> 00:33:34,440
我們得接受事實
So we just have to deal with that.

416
00:33:35,540 --> 00:33:36,940
我們無能為力
There's nothing we can do.

417
00:33:38,660 --> 00:33:41,390
她是我親姐姐　你個狗娘養的
She's my sister, you son of a bitch.

418
00:33:55,050 --> 00:33:57,080
艾米
Amy...

419
00:33:58,670 --> 00:34:00,240
沒事　別擔心　小鬼
Come on. It's all right, buddy.

420
00:34:53,630 --> 00:34:56,910
居然行得通　真不敢相信
It's gonna work. I can't believe it.

421
00:34:57,590 --> 00:35:00,150
別說話　繼續裝
Don't draw attention.

422
00:35:32,870 --> 00:35:34,740
天哪
Oh man.

423
00:35:50,930 --> 00:35:52,260
只是場暴雨而已
It's just a cloudburst.

424
00:35:52,260 --> 00:35:54,970
這裡常會下暴雨　很快就會停
We get them all the time. It'll pass real quick.

425
00:36:25,220 --> 00:36:27,890
行屍味是不是被雨水沖掉了　
The smell's washing off, isn't it?

426
00:36:27,920 --> 00:36:29,690
-是不是被沖掉了　-沒有
- Is it washing off? - No, it's not.

427
00:36:33,580 --> 00:36:36,130
也許吧
Well, maybe.

428
00:36:38,340 --> 00:36:39,700
快跑
Run!

429
00:36:53,660 --> 00:36:54,880
快快快 
Come on, come on, come on.

430
00:37:25,550 --> 00:37:26,580
瑞克
Rick!

431
00:37:43,430 --> 00:37:44,450
快　快開車
Go go go go!

432
00:38:05,930 --> 00:38:08,330
-他們要丟下我們　-什麼　　
- They're leaving us. - What? What?

433
00:38:08,360 --> 00:38:10,700
-他們要去哪　-不不　給我回來
- Where they going? Where they going? - No no, come back.

434
00:38:15,640 --> 00:38:17,640
天哪天哪　他們全聚集在那兒
Oh my god. Oh my god. They're all over that place.

435
00:38:17,640 --> 00:38:18,970
你得設法把他們引開
You need to draw them away.

436
00:38:19,010 --> 00:38:20,910
那個商店的前捲簾門那裡
Those roll-up doors at the front of the store--

437
00:38:20,940 --> 00:38:22,580
你得幫我把他們從那裡引開
That area? --That's what I need cleared.

438
00:38:22,610 --> 00:38:25,580
通知他們　讓他們到捲簾門口等著
Raise your friends. Tell them to get down there and be ready.

439
00:38:25,610 --> 00:38:28,350
我要怎麼引開這些怪物　我剛沒注意聽
And I'm drawing the geeks away how? I-- I missed that part.

440
00:38:28,380 --> 00:38:30,020
製造噪音
Noise.

441
00:39:02,830 --> 00:39:04,090
到商店的前捲簾門那裡去
Those roll-up doors at the front of the store

442
00:39:04,090 --> 00:39:06,250
就街對面的捲簾門　在那兒會合　
facing the street-- meet us there and be ready.

443
00:39:21,470 --> 00:39:22,870
快　咱們走　快點
Come on! Let's go, let's go!

444
00:39:22,870 --> 00:39:23,930
等等　你們不能丟下我
Hey, you can't leave me here!

445
00:39:23,930 --> 00:39:26,070
我又不蠢　兄弟　莫拉萊斯　
I'm not fooling, man! Morales!

446
00:39:26,110 --> 00:39:28,710
-哥們　別丟下我　-快點
- Hey, man! Don't do this! - Come on.

447
00:39:28,740 --> 00:39:30,610
那是我的槍　你不能丟下我
Hey, that's my gun. You can't leave me.

448
00:39:30,650 --> 00:39:31,550
你們不要丟下我 
Don't leave me here, you guys.

449
00:39:31,550 --> 00:39:32,850
莫拉萊斯　快點
Morales, come on.

450
00:39:32,880 --> 00:39:34,780
來了　我們真得走了
I'm coming! We've gotta go!

451
00:39:34,820 --> 00:39:37,380
莫拉萊斯　你把手銬給我解開　哥們
Morales! You can't leave me like this, man!

452
00:39:37,420 --> 00:39:39,290
T仔　哥們　你不能丟下我不管
Hey, T-dog. No, man. You can't leave me, man.

453
00:39:39,320 --> 00:39:40,950
你不能丟下我　至少把手銬解開
You can't leave me here-- not like this.

454
00:39:40,990 --> 00:39:42,760
你會遭天譴的　你還有沒有人性
You can't, man. It's not human.

455
00:39:42,790 --> 00:39:45,290
求你了　不要丟下我
Come on, don't do this.

456
00:39:45,330 --> 00:39:47,330
求你了　T仔　行行好　
Come on, T. Come on!

457
00:39:47,360 --> 00:39:49,530
快過來　就是這樣　
Come on, yeah! Yeah!

458
00:39:49,560 --> 00:39:52,170
過來　對　快點過來　好哥們
Come on! Co-- that's it! Yes! Come on, baby!

459
00:39:52,200 --> 00:39:54,800
快來
Come on.

460
00:40:05,410 --> 00:40:06,480
快走
Go.

461
00:40:09,680 --> 00:40:12,120
你個狗雜種　你他媽故意的
Son of a bitch! You did that on purpose!

462
00:40:12,120 --> 00:40:12,840
我不是故意的 
I didn't mean to!

463
00:40:12,840 --> 00:40:14,350
騙死人呢你　你他媽就是故意的
You lie! You did it on purpose!

464
00:40:14,350 --> 00:40:17,620
-真的是意外　-別丟下我　
- It was an accident! - Don't leave me, man!

465
00:40:17,660 --> 00:40:20,860
別丟下我　不要丟下我
Don't leave me! Don't leave me!

466
00:40:21,140 --> 00:40:21,760
對不起
I'm sorry.

467
00:40:21,760 --> 00:40:23,670
-你個騙子　-對不起了　兄弟　
- You liar! - I'm sorry. Man, I'm sorry.

468
00:40:24,060 --> 00:40:27,080
-對不起　-別丟下我　別這么做
- I'm sorry.　- Don't leave me! don't do it, man!

469
00:40:27,510 --> 00:40:28,700
操你們全家
Damn you all!

470
00:40:28,740 --> 00:40:30,670
兄弟　別丟下我　
Don't leave me, man!

471
00:40:30,710 --> 00:40:33,910
別丟…　別丟下我
Don't leave-- don't leave me!

472
00:40:35,340 --> 00:40:37,410
別鎖門　你還是不是人　　　
Hey! What are you doing, man?

473
00:40:37,450 --> 00:40:39,410
你會遭報應的
You're gonna rot in hell!

474
00:40:39,450 --> 00:40:41,050
下地獄吧你
You're gonna rot in hell!

475
00:40:41,080 --> 00:40:43,680
-給我回來　-等我一下
- Come back, man! - Wait a minute!

476
00:40:43,720 --> 00:40:45,920
我來了　別丟下我
Here I come! Don't leave me!

477
00:40:46,320 --> 00:40:47,470
等我啊
Don't leave!

478
00:40:57,910 --> 00:40:59,370
噓
Shh.

479
00:40:59,400 --> 00:41:01,640
怎麼了
What is that?

480
00:41:13,550 --> 00:41:15,580
過來吧　來吧
Come on. Come on.

481
00:41:17,890 --> 00:41:20,520
靠近點　靠近點　來吧來吧　
Get closer. Get closer. Come on. Come on.

482
00:41:57,460 --> 00:41:59,660
等等我
Hey, wait for me!

483
00:42:10,570 --> 00:42:13,210
他們進來了　快走　他們來了
They're here! Let's go! They're in here!

484
00:42:14,340 --> 00:42:15,940
-快走　-快開門
- Let's go! - Open the door!

485
00:42:18,510 --> 00:42:20,780
-趕緊走　-快
- We've gotta go! - Go!

486
00:42:30,090 --> 00:42:30,890
我進來了
I'm in!

487
00:42:44,810 --> 00:42:47,460
不要丟下我
Don't leave me!

488
00:42:47,460 --> 00:42:50,810
你會下地獄的　去死吧　他媽的　
You'll die! Go to hell! Damn you!

489
00:42:54,720 --> 00:42:56,620
你會下第十八層地獄
You're gonna rot in hell!

490
00:43:20,500 --> 00:43:23,040
我居然把鑰匙掉了
I dropped the damn key.

491
00:43:32,190 --> 00:43:33,850
格倫人呢
Where's Glenn?

