1
00:00:05,030 --> 00:00:07,800
沒錯　你也聽到了　賤貨
That's right. You heard me, bitch.

2
00:00:08,320 --> 00:00:09,430
有問題嗎
You got a problem?

3
00:00:09,460 --> 00:00:11,700
夠爺們的話就放馬過來
Bring it on if you're man enough,

4
00:00:11,730 --> 00:00:14,770
不然的話就乖乖認命
or take it up the chain if you're a pussy.

5
00:00:15,630 --> 00:00:16,770
你也聽到了
You heard me,

6
00:00:16,810 --> 00:00:19,740
你個娘炮婊子士官
You pussy-ass noncom bitch.

7
00:00:19,780 --> 00:00:21,510
你又不聾
You ain't deaf.

8
00:00:21,540 --> 00:00:23,580
去你媽的服從命令聽指揮
Take it up the damn chain of command

9
00:00:23,610 --> 00:00:28,320
你他媽給老子見鬼去吧
or you can kiss my lily-white ass.

10
00:00:29,710 --> 00:00:30,450
沒錯
That's right.

11
00:00:30,490 --> 00:00:32,890
我就這麼說了　你聽得一清二楚
That's what I said. You heard me.

12
00:00:32,920 --> 00:00:35,460
之後這個白癡　他揮了一拳 
And then this idiot, he takes a swing,

13
00:00:35,490 --> 00:00:37,590
告訴你…
You know, and well...

14
00:00:40,860 --> 00:00:43,830
你真該欣賞下他的表情
Oh, you should've seen the look on his face

15
00:00:44,350 --> 00:00:47,170
我把他門牙都打掉了
When I punched out his front teeth.

16
00:00:48,800 --> 00:00:50,940
五顆門牙
Yeah, five of 'em.

17
00:00:50,970 --> 00:00:53,910
乒乒乓乓　就像這樣
Pow! Pow! Just like that.

18
00:00:56,570 --> 00:00:58,050
我的天
Oh my god.

19
00:00:58,080 --> 00:01:01,450
這麼一來害得我
16 months in the stockade--

20
00:01:01,480 --> 00:01:04,650
蹲了16個月監獄
Oh, that's what them teeth cost me.

21
00:01:06,690 --> 00:01:08,490
那時真是
That was--

22
00:01:09,180 --> 00:01:11,060
真是難熬啊
That was hard time,

23
00:01:12,390 --> 00:01:15,300
但說實話　光是看著
But by god, it was worth every minute of it

24
00:01:16,400 --> 00:01:18,530
那混球把自己的牙
Just to see that prick

25
00:01:18,570 --> 00:01:20,600
吐在地上　真他媽的絕對值了
Spit his teeth out on the ground.

26
00:01:23,880 --> 00:01:25,370
是的　長官
Yes sir,

27
00:01:25,410 --> 00:01:26,970
絕對值
Worth every minute.

28
00:01:49,900 --> 00:01:51,470
不
Oh no.

29
00:01:51,500 --> 00:01:54,440
不不不
No no! No no! No no!

30
00:01:54,470 --> 00:01:56,170
老天爺
God! Godod

31
00:01:56,200 --> 00:01:58,670
不要
No no!

32
00:01:58,710 --> 00:02:00,880
耶穌基督
God! Jesus!

33
00:02:00,910 --> 00:02:02,440
不不　仁慈的上帝
No no, merciful christ!

34
00:02:02,480 --> 00:02:04,150
不要
No no. No no.

35
00:02:04,180 --> 00:02:07,550
上帝啊　救救我
God, help me! God! God!

36
00:02:07,580 --> 00:02:10,580
老天爺啊　行行好
Jesus, please! Jesus, please.

37
00:02:10,620 --> 00:02:13,290
救我　快救救我
Help me! Come on now!

38
00:02:13,320 --> 00:02:15,020
救命
Help me.

39
00:02:23,270 --> 00:02:24,770
不要
No no. Oh, no no.

40
00:02:24,800 --> 00:02:26,230
老天爺
Oh my god.

41
00:02:28,740 --> 00:02:32,140
天啊　上帝啊
No, jesus. Jesus.

42
00:02:36,750 --> 00:02:38,810
不要
No no no no no no.

43
00:02:38,850 --> 00:02:40,610
求你了
Please.

44
00:02:40,650 --> 00:02:43,020
我這人太壞　我知道
I didn't behave, I know.

45
00:02:43,050 --> 00:02:45,150
我是罪有應得
I know I'm being punished.

46
00:02:45,190 --> 00:02:47,360
我知道
I know. I--

47
00:02:47,390 --> 00:02:49,860
我活該　我活該
Oh, I deserve it. I deserve it.

48
00:02:49,890 --> 00:02:51,290
我一直很壞
I've been bad.

49
00:02:54,360 --> 00:02:56,160
求你現在幫幫我　給我一條出路
Help me now. Show me the way.

50
00:02:56,200 --> 00:02:58,670
求你了　救救我
Go on, tell me what to do.

51
00:02:58,700 --> 00:03:00,200
快告訴我怎麼辦
Tell me. Tell me.

52
00:03:02,770 --> 00:03:04,310
老天爺
God!

53
00:03:15,980 --> 00:03:17,890
好吧
That's okay.

54
00:03:18,920 --> 00:03:21,760
不用在意了　你個白癡耶穌
Never you mind, silly christ boy.

55
00:03:21,790 --> 00:03:23,860
我之前沒求過你
I ain't begged you before.

56
00:03:23,890 --> 00:03:26,360
現在也別指望我求你
I ain't gonna start begging now.

57
00:03:26,400 --> 00:03:28,930
我死也不要求你
I ain't gonna beg you now!

58
00:03:29,470 --> 00:03:32,000
你不用操心了
Don't you worry about me

59
00:03:32,030 --> 00:03:35,140
我再也不會求你了
Begging you ever! I'll never beg you!

60
00:03:35,170 --> 00:03:37,510
我死也不會求你
I ain't gonna beg you!

61
00:03:37,540 --> 00:03:39,840
我之前從沒求過你
I never begged you before.

62
00:03:49,280 --> 00:03:50,850
不
No!

63
00:03:50,580 --> 00:03:52,240
YYeTs人人影視誠意奉獻

64
00:03:54,380 --> 00:03:56,050
翻譯 海因裡希 NaryKing

65
00:03:57,660 --> 00:03:59,480
翻譯 zhanginfo 憶

66
00:03:59,490 --> 00:04:01,350
翻譯 原子蛋 點點點

67
00:04:04,710 --> 00:04:05,910
時間軸 之間

68
00:04:05,910 --> 00:04:07,010
校對 海因裡希

69
00:04:07,010 --> 00:04:08,140
後期/特效 WiLL

70
00:04:08,140 --> 00:04:09,310
監製 海因裡希

71
00:04:09,320 --> 00:04:12,320
CHD版個人美化微修：字幕雷哥

72
00:04:20,910 --> 00:04:25,760
走

73
00:04:21,660 --> 00:04:25,760
肉

74
00:04:22,010 --> 00:04:25,760
行屍

75
00:04:22,010 --> 00:04:25,760
『第一季 第三集』

76
00:04:29,130 --> 00:04:30,860
你別放在心上了
Best not to dwell on it.

77
00:04:30,890 --> 00:04:33,060
莫爾被一個人扔在那兒
Merle got left behind.

78
00:04:35,700 --> 00:04:37,700
他回不來沒人會難過
Nobody's gonna be sad he didn't come back...

79
00:04:39,770 --> 00:04:41,840
好吧　也許除了達裡爾
Except maybe Daryl.

80
00:04:41,870 --> 00:04:44,670
-達裡爾是誰　-他弟弟
- Daryl? - His brother.

81
00:04:57,280 --> 00:04:58,920
至少有人今天過得很開心
At least somebody's having a good day.

82
00:05:02,020 --> 00:05:05,360
-還給我　-住手
- Give it back. - Stop it.

83
00:05:05,390 --> 00:05:09,500
-不要　-是我找到的
- No! - I found it.

84
00:05:09,530 --> 00:05:11,570
-不要　-給我
- No! - Give it.

85
00:05:11,600 --> 00:05:13,370
米約　別和你姐姐吵了
Mijo, leave your sister alone.

86
00:05:13,400 --> 00:05:14,870
-為什麼　-聽話
- Why? - Come on.

87
00:05:14,900 --> 00:05:17,000
親愛的　你越煩躁就得越久
Baby, the more you fidget, the longer it takes.

88
00:05:17,040 --> 00:05:19,740
-別動了　好嗎　-我盡力了
- So don't, okay? - I'm trying.

89
00:05:19,770 --> 00:05:21,010
那就再盡力點
Well, try harder.

90
00:05:21,040 --> 00:05:22,410
你這樣就受不了的話
If you think this is bad,

91
00:05:22,440 --> 00:05:25,050
等到刮鬍子時有你好受
wait till you start shaving.

92
00:05:25,080 --> 00:05:26,450
那可痛呢
That stings.

93
00:05:26,480 --> 00:05:28,180
等到那時
That day comes, you'll be

94
00:05:28,220 --> 00:05:30,320
你會無比懷念媽媽給你理髮
wishing for one of your mama's haircuts.

95
00:05:30,350 --> 00:05:32,920
真這麼誇張　我才不信
I'll believe that when I see it.

96
00:05:32,950 --> 00:05:35,260
這樣吧　如果你像個男子漢那樣
I'll tell you what-- you just get through this

97
00:05:35,290 --> 00:05:36,820
好好理髮
with some manly dignity and

98
00:05:36,820 --> 00:05:39,190
明天我教你點特別的玩意
tomorrow I'll teach you something special.

99
00:05:40,250 --> 00:05:43,030
我教你怎麼抓青蛙
I will teach you to catch frogs.

100
00:05:43,060 --> 00:05:46,270
-我以前抓過青蛙　-我是說一群青蛙
- I've caught a frog before. - I said frogs-- plural.

101
00:05:46,300 --> 00:05:49,470
小傢伙　那是門藝術　抓起來可不容易
And it is an art, my friend. It is not to be taken lightly.

102
00:05:49,500 --> 00:05:52,210
其中的方法和工具
There are ways and means.

103
00:05:52,240 --> 00:05:53,870
知道的人寥寥無幾
Few people know about it.

104
00:05:53,910 --> 00:05:56,210
而我願意告訴你這秘訣
I'm willing to share my secrets.

105
00:05:58,080 --> 00:06:00,780
我是女生　你和他說
Oh, I'm a girl. You talk to him.

106
00:06:00,820 --> 00:06:04,190
僅此一次　不得反悔哦
It's a one-time offer, bud-- not to be repeated.

107
00:06:04,220 --> 00:06:07,590
我們幹嘛要這麼多青蛙
Why do we need frogs, plural?

108
00:06:07,620 --> 00:06:10,390
-你沒吃過青蛙腿嗎　-好惡
- You ever eat frog legs? - Eww!

109
00:06:10,430 --> 00:06:13,330
-不　很美味　-他說得對　很惡
- No, yum! - No, he's right. Eww.

110
00:06:13,360 --> 00:06:15,930
當你吃夠了那些罐頭豆子
When you get down to that last can of beans,

111
00:06:15,960 --> 00:06:17,900
肯定會愛死青蛙腿的　女士
You're gonna be loving those frog legs, lady.

112
00:06:17,930 --> 00:06:19,060
我現在就能猜到你說　肖恩
I can see it now-- "Shane,

113
00:06:19,060 --> 00:06:21,270
你看能再多給我一份嗎
Do you think I could have a second helping, please?

114
00:06:21,300 --> 00:06:24,210
-拜託　就一份　-是嗎　走著瞧
- Please? Just one? - Yeah, I doubt that.

115
00:06:25,110 --> 00:06:26,410
別聽她的　小伙子
Don't listen to her, man.

116
00:06:26,440 --> 00:06:28,880
咱倆是英雄　我們會給那幫人
You and me, we'll be heroes. We'll feed these folks

117
00:06:28,910 --> 00:06:30,910
搞到法式田雞腿大餐
Cajun-style kermit legs.

118
00:06:30,950 --> 00:06:32,980
我寧願吃豬肉
I would rather eat miss piggy.

119
00:06:33,010 --> 00:06:36,020
不過也好吃不到哪去
Yes, that came out wrong.

120
00:06:36,050 --> 00:06:38,720
孩子　數英雄人物
Heroes, son, spoken of in song and legend.

121
00:06:38,750 --> 00:06:40,590
還看你我　肖恩和卡爾
You and me, Shane and Carl.

122
00:06:42,620 --> 00:06:45,390
戴爾　你那裡什麼情況
Hey, Dale, can you see what that is?

123
00:06:45,430 --> 00:06:47,190
怎麼了　戴爾
Talk to me, Dale!

124
00:06:47,960 --> 00:06:50,230
還不好說
I can't tell yet.

125
00:06:54,500 --> 00:06:56,600
是他們嗎　他們回來了嗎
Is it them? Are they back?

126
00:07:00,180 --> 00:07:01,810
我勒個去
I'll be damned.

127
00:07:01,840 --> 00:07:05,180
-什麼東西　-我猜是被盜車輛
- What is it? - A stolen car is my guess.

128
00:07:17,390 --> 00:07:20,890
-靠　把那破報警器關了　-我關不了
- Holy crap. Turn that damn thing off! - I don't know how!

129
00:07:20,930 --> 00:07:22,010
把車前蓋打開　聽到沒有啊
Pop the hood, please. Pop the damn hood,

130
00:07:22,010 --> 00:07:22,730
我姐安德莉亞…
My sister Andrea--

131
00:07:22,760 --> 00:07:25,030
-打開前蓋　-什麼　行行　好了好了
- Pop the damn hood! - What? Okay okay. Yeah yeah yeah

132
00:07:25,070 --> 00:07:28,000
-可以了　-她好嗎　她沒事吧
- Yeah yeah! - Is she okay? Is she all right?

133
00:07:28,040 --> 00:07:30,340
-沒事　她沒事　-她回來了嗎
- She's okay! She's okay! - Is she coming back?

134
00:07:30,370 --> 00:07:32,310
-是的　-那她怎麼沒和你在一起
- Yes! - Why isn't she with you?

135
00:07:32,340 --> 00:07:35,210
-她在哪兒　真沒事嗎　-真沒事
- Where is she? She's okay? - Yes!

136
00:07:35,240 --> 00:07:37,180
都沒事　大家都沒事
Yeah, fine. Everybody is.

137
00:07:38,710 --> 00:07:40,350
除了倒霉的莫爾
Well, Merle not so much.

138
00:07:40,380 --> 00:07:42,450
你瘋啦　開輛鬼哭狼嚎的破車回來
Are you crazy, driving this wailing bastard up here?

139
00:07:42,480 --> 00:07:44,320
非要把那堆臭殭屍都引過來嗎
Are you trying to draw every walker for miles?

140
00:07:44,350 --> 00:07:47,350
-放心沒事　-這他媽還叫沒事啊
- I think we're okay. - You call being stupid okay?

141
00:07:47,390 --> 00:07:49,060
警報器的聲音會在山谷裡迴響
Well, the alarm was echoing all over these hills.

142
00:07:49,090 --> 00:07:51,430
根本辨別不出位置
Hard to pinpoint the source.

143
00:07:51,460 --> 00:07:53,760
我不是抬槓　也就說說
I'm not arguing. I'm just saying.

144
00:07:53,800 --> 00:07:55,600
下次你不能長點腦子嗎
It wouldn't hurt you to think things through

145
00:07:55,630 --> 00:07:57,560
又不會缺胳膊短腿　行嗎
a little more carefully next time, would it?

146
00:07:58,600 --> 00:07:59,870
對不起
Sorry.

147
00:08:00,900 --> 00:08:02,600
好歹算弄了台靚車
Got a cool car.

148
00:08:15,620 --> 00:08:17,250
下來見見大家
Come meet everybody.

149
00:08:25,190 --> 00:08:28,200
-艾米　-安德莉亞
- Amy. - Andrea!

150
00:08:30,900 --> 00:08:32,860
謝天謝地
Oh my god!

151
00:08:34,640 --> 00:08:37,770
你嚇死我了
You scared the shit out of me.

152
00:08:37,810 --> 00:08:41,280
-爸爸　-老爸　-嗨
- Papi! - Daddy! - Hey.

153
00:08:41,310 --> 00:08:43,240
寶貝　來這邊
Come here, sweetie.

154
00:08:43,280 --> 00:08:44,810
嗨
Hey.

155
00:08:45,620 --> 00:08:47,580
都說了我會回來　沒錯吧
I told you I'd be back, didn't I?

156
00:08:56,690 --> 00:08:58,960
還能見到你可真好
You are a welcome sight.

157
00:08:59,620 --> 00:09:03,100
我還以為肯定見不到你們了
I thought we had lost you folks for sure.

158
00:09:03,130 --> 00:09:05,030
你們怎麼逃出來的
How'd y'all get out of there anyway?

159
00:09:05,070 --> 00:09:08,370
-有個新來的幫了我們　-新來的
- New guy-- he got us out. - New guy?

160
00:09:08,400 --> 00:09:10,470
對　那瘋子跑進了城裡
Yeah, crazy vato just got into town.

161
00:09:10,510 --> 00:09:13,970
直升機大哥　來跟大家打個招呼
Hey, helicopter boy! Come say hello.

162
00:09:16,210 --> 00:09:18,410
和你一樣　那老兄也是警察
The guy's a cop like you.

163
00:09:36,800 --> 00:09:38,470
老天保佑
Oh my god.

164
00:09:41,440 --> 00:09:43,500
爸爸　爸爸
Dad! Dad!

165
00:09:46,210 --> 00:09:47,810
卡爾
Carl.

166
00:10:28,020 --> 00:10:30,050
無所適從
Disoriented.

167
00:10:30,080 --> 00:10:32,190
這最能形容我的感覺
I guess that comes closest.

168
00:10:33,220 --> 00:10:34,660
完全不知所措
Disoriented.

169
00:10:36,390 --> 00:10:39,390
夾雜著恐懼　茫然和迷惑
Fear, confusion-- all those things but...

170
00:10:40,790 --> 00:10:43,290
但主要還是無所適從
disoriented comes closest.

171
00:10:43,570 --> 00:10:45,600
語言無法形容
Words can be meager things.

172
00:10:46,580 --> 00:10:48,470
有時候語言是如此蒼白
Sometimes they fall short.

173
00:10:48,900 --> 00:10:50,970
我感覺像是被從這個世界
I felt like I'd been ripped out of my life

174
00:10:51,320 --> 00:10:53,000
隔離了出去
and put somewhere else.

175
00:10:54,940 --> 00:10:57,540
我一度以為自己陷進了
For a while I thought I was trapped

176
00:10:57,570 --> 00:10:59,910
昏迷中的噩夢裡
in some coma dream,

177
00:10:59,940 --> 00:11:02,750
再也醒不過來了
something I might not wake up from ever.

178
00:11:04,750 --> 00:11:06,480
媽媽說你死了
Mom said you died.

179
00:11:10,680 --> 00:11:13,550
她這麼想合情合理
She had every reason to believe that.

180
00:11:13,590 --> 00:11:15,620
不要怪她
Don't you ever doubt it.

181
00:11:18,090 --> 00:11:20,360
情況變糟糕的時候
When things started to get really bad,

182
00:11:20,400 --> 00:11:22,730
院方的人和我說
they told me at the hospital that

183
00:11:22,760 --> 00:11:25,930
要把你們這批患者轉移到亞特蘭大
they were gonna medevac you and the other patients to Atlanta,

184
00:11:27,100 --> 00:11:29,370
結果卻沒了下文
and it never happened.

185
00:11:29,400 --> 00:11:32,010
看到亞特蘭大這德行我也不奇怪了
Well, I'm not surprised after Atlanta fell.

186
00:11:32,590 --> 00:11:36,540
看來就連醫院也被行屍佔領了
Yeah. And from the look of that hospital, it got overrun.

187
00:11:36,580 --> 00:11:40,510
一點沒錯　我好不容易才把大家救出來
Yeah, looks don't deceive. I barely got them out,

188
00:11:41,510 --> 00:11:42,450
知道嗎
you know?

189
00:11:42,480 --> 00:11:45,550
我不知道該怎麼感激你才好
I can't tell you how grateful I am to you, Shane.

190
00:11:46,660 --> 00:11:48,420
我不知還能說什麼
I can't begin to express it.

191
00:11:50,560 --> 00:11:53,290
語言又顯得蒼白無力了
There go those words falling short again.

192
00:11:53,730 --> 00:11:55,400
得了　區區小事
Paltry things.

193
00:12:04,840 --> 00:12:08,280
愛德　能別隨便添柴火嗎
Hey, Ed, you want to rethink that log?

194
00:12:08,310 --> 00:12:10,210
太冷了　夥計
It's cold, man.

195
00:12:13,850 --> 00:12:16,150
再冷規矩總不能壞　你說呢
The cold don't change the rules, does it?

196
00:12:17,190 --> 00:12:19,090
火得小些　有點就行了
Keep our fires low, just embers.

197
00:12:19,120 --> 00:12:22,660
-以免被發現　-我說了　天氣太冷
- So we can't be seen from a distance, right? - I said it's cold.

198
00:12:22,690 --> 00:12:24,730
你就不能別多管閒事嗎
You should mind your own business for once.

199
00:12:32,900 --> 00:12:34,570
愛德
Hey, Ed...

200
00:12:36,640 --> 00:12:38,670
你非要和我叫板嗎
are you sure you want to have this conversation, man?

201
00:12:42,110 --> 00:12:44,810
好吧　把火熄了
Go on. Pull the damn thing out.

202
00:12:45,210 --> 00:12:46,410
快點
Go on!

203
00:12:50,360 --> 00:12:51,250
老天
Christ.

204
00:13:06,200 --> 00:13:09,200
卡蘿爾　索菲亞　晚上還好嗎
Hey, Carol, Sophia, how are y'all this evening?

205
00:13:09,240 --> 00:13:12,070
-沒事　我們能行　-好
- Fine. We're just fine. - Okay.

206
00:13:13,440 --> 00:13:14,940
-火堆的事抱歉　-別這麼說
- I'm sorry about the fire. - No no no.

207
00:13:14,980 --> 00:13:16,580
不用道歉
No apology needed.

208
00:13:18,530 --> 00:13:19,750
晚上好好休息
Y'all have a good night, okay?

209
00:13:20,820 --> 00:13:22,580
謝謝
Thank you.

210
00:13:22,620 --> 00:13:24,750
謝謝合作
I appreciate the cooperation.

211
00:13:34,530 --> 00:13:37,160
你想過怎麼和達裡爾·迪克森說了嗎
Have you given any thought to Daryl Dixon?

212
00:13:37,200 --> 00:13:40,030
他要是知道自己哥哥被拋棄肯定不高興
He won't be happy to hear his brother was left behind.

213
00:13:40,630 --> 00:13:43,240
我來和他說　是我弄掉的鑰匙　我自己擔著
I'll tell him. I dropped the key. It's on me.

214
00:13:43,270 --> 00:13:45,170
是我銬的他　所以是我的事　
I cuffed him. That makes it mine.

215
00:13:45,210 --> 00:13:46,840
夥計們　這沒什麼好爭的
Guys, it's not a competition.

216
00:13:46,880 --> 00:13:48,680
我不想扯到種族問題
I don't mean to bring race into this,

217
00:13:48,710 --> 00:13:50,910
不過說成白人做的應該好點
but it might sound better coming from a white guy.

218
00:13:53,520 --> 00:13:55,250
一人做事一人當
I did what I did.

219
00:13:56,000 --> 00:13:57,590
我他媽就該離他遠點
Hell if I'm gonna hide from him.

220
00:13:57,620 --> 00:14:00,720
-咱可以騙他　-還是實話實說的好
- We could lie. - Or tell the truth.

221
00:14:01,250 --> 00:14:03,160
莫爾那時都失控了
Merle was out of control.

222
00:14:03,190 --> 00:14:06,090
必須有所行動　不然他會害死我們
Something had to be done or he'd have gotten us killed.

223
00:14:07,230 --> 00:14:09,200
你丈夫必須這麼做
Your husband did what was necessary.

224
00:14:09,230 --> 00:14:10,800
莫爾被落下了
And if Merle got left behind,

225
00:14:10,830 --> 00:14:12,970
是他咎由自取
it is nobody's fault but Merle's.

226
00:14:13,000 --> 00:14:15,240
就跟達裡爾這麼說嗎
And that's what we tell Daryl?

227
00:14:17,650 --> 00:14:21,740
我覺得他可不會和你講道理　你說呢
I don't see a rational discussion to be had from that, do you?

228
00:14:25,100 --> 00:14:26,080
不用我多說吧
Word to the wise--

229
00:14:27,250 --> 00:14:28,980
等他弟弟打獵回來
we're gonna have our hands full

230
00:14:29,020 --> 00:14:30,680
我們就有的忙活了
when he gets back from his hunt.

231
00:14:32,520 --> 00:14:35,920
我嚇壞了　所以先逃了
I was scared and I ran.

232
00:14:35,960 --> 00:14:38,330
-這點我承認　-我們都嚇壞了
- I'm not ashamed of it. - We were all scared.

233
00:14:38,360 --> 00:14:40,930
我們都逃了　你要說什麼
We all ran. What's your point?

234
00:14:40,960 --> 00:14:43,060
我把門用鏈子鎖上了
I stopped long enough to chain that door.

235
00:14:45,170 --> 00:14:46,770
樓梯很窄
Staircase is narrow.

236
00:14:46,800 --> 00:14:49,400
也許一次可以
Maybe half a dozen geeks can squeeze against it

237
00:14:49,440 --> 00:14:51,340
擠下六七隻怪物
at any one time.

238
00:14:51,370 --> 00:14:53,740
但這還不足以闖進去
It's not enough to break through that--

239
00:14:53,780 --> 00:14:55,880
門上有鏈子和掛鎖
not that chain, not that padlock.

240
00:14:58,010 --> 00:15:01,780
我要說的是　迪克森還活著
My point-- Dixon's alive

241
00:15:01,820 --> 00:15:04,750
還在那上面　被手銬銬著
and he's still up there, handcuffed on that roof.

242
00:15:06,520 --> 00:15:07,690
是我們的責任
That's on us.

243
00:15:21,270 --> 00:15:24,310
終於找到你了吧
I found you, didn't I?

244
00:15:26,880 --> 00:15:28,080
我愛你　爸爸
I love you, dad.

245
00:15:30,710 --> 00:15:32,710
我也愛你　卡爾
I love you, Carl.

246
00:16:12,370 --> 00:16:14,090
終於找到你們倆了
I found you both.

247
00:16:15,260 --> 00:16:16,860
是啊
Yeah.

248
00:16:20,460 --> 00:16:22,130
我就知道能找到你們
I knew I would.

249
00:16:23,730 --> 00:16:26,530
你有點得瑟了
You're getting cocky now, a little bit.

250
00:16:26,570 --> 00:16:28,870
沒有　我真的知道
No. No, I knew.

251
00:16:30,570 --> 00:16:33,710
我回過家裡一趟　發現空無一人
Walking into our home, finding an empty house,

252
00:16:33,740 --> 00:16:35,710
-你們都走了　-對不起
- both of you gone. - I'm so sorry.

253
00:16:35,740 --> 00:16:38,850
我知道你們還活著
I knew you were alive.

254
00:16:40,780 --> 00:16:42,280
怎麼知道
How?

255
00:16:44,930 --> 00:16:46,950
相片不見了
The photos were gone,

256
00:16:47,340 --> 00:16:49,090
我們的相冊都不見了
all our family albums.

257
00:17:13,070 --> 00:17:14,450
我說過我知道
I told you so.

258
00:17:15,140 --> 00:17:17,080
現在算是得瑟了吧
Now you're getting cocky, huh?

259
00:17:17,440 --> 00:17:18,620
相當得瑟
A lot.

260
00:17:32,620 --> 00:17:34,300
這張是在這裡的
It belongs in here.

261
00:17:40,820 --> 00:17:43,540
親愛的　我真的以為再也見不到你了
Baby, I really thought I would never see you again.

262
00:17:48,160 --> 00:17:49,880
對不起
I'm so sorry...

263
00:17:51,320 --> 00:17:52,990
真的對不起
for everything.

264
00:17:56,120 --> 00:17:57,930
我感覺…
I feel like--

265
00:17:57,960 --> 00:18:00,190
你在醫院的時候　我
when you were in the hospital, I just--

266
00:18:00,230 --> 00:18:02,100
我真的很回到過去
I wanted to take it all back--

267
00:18:02,130 --> 00:18:04,700
就算是我們以前爭吵的日子
the anger and the bad times.

268
00:18:04,730 --> 00:18:07,230
只要能彌補那些過錯
But the mistakes--

269
00:18:10,640 --> 00:18:12,940
我們還有機會
Maybe we got a second chance.

270
00:18:13,440 --> 00:18:15,140
不是每個人都有這種機會
Not many people get that.

271
00:18:32,230 --> 00:18:34,230
我到處找都沒找到
I wondered where that went.

272
00:18:36,030 --> 00:18:38,470
想要回去嗎
Do you want it back?

273
00:18:40,540 --> 00:18:42,400
當然
Of course.

274
00:19:28,180 --> 00:19:30,180
他不會醒的
He won't wake up.

275
00:20:34,730 --> 00:20:36,260
-早　-早
- Morning. - Morning.

276
00:20:38,130 --> 00:20:39,460
-早　-早
- Hey. - Hi.

277
00:20:41,850 --> 00:20:43,940
-早　-早
- Morning. - Morning.

278
00:20:43,970 --> 00:20:45,370
衣服還沒乾
They're still a little damp.

279
00:20:45,400 --> 00:20:46,840
有太陽的話馬上就乾了
The sun'll have'em dry in no time.

280
00:20:46,870 --> 00:20:48,610
你把我的衣服也洗了嗎　
You washed my clothes?

281
00:20:48,610 --> 00:20:49,940
嗯　我們盡力而為
Well, best we could.

282
00:20:49,980 --> 00:20:51,340
在洗衣板上洗
Scrubbing on a washboard

283
00:20:51,380 --> 00:20:53,580
不如家裡的舊洗衣機洗得乾淨
ain't half as good as my old Maytag back home.

284
00:20:53,610 --> 00:20:55,550
你真好　謝謝
That's very kind. Thank you.

285
00:21:00,180 --> 00:21:01,520
你看他們
Look at'em.

286
00:21:01,890 --> 00:21:03,760
噁心的禿鷲
Vultures.

287
00:21:03,790 --> 00:21:05,240
繼續啊　拆乾淨吧
Yeah, go on, strip it clean.

288
00:21:05,240 --> 00:21:07,140
發電機需要燃料
Generators need every drop of fuel they can get.

289
00:21:07,170 --> 00:21:10,510
不然就發動不了車了　對不住了　格倫
Got no power without it. Sorry, Glenn.

290
00:21:10,960 --> 00:21:13,410
還以為能再飆上幾天呢
Thought I'd get to drive it at least a few more days.

291
00:21:14,180 --> 00:21:16,710
也許哪天還能再偷一輛來
Maybe we'll get to steal another one someday.

292
00:21:21,890 --> 00:21:23,750
警長早啊
Morning, officer.

293
00:21:30,420 --> 00:21:31,360
睡得香嗎
You sleep okay?

294
00:21:32,870 --> 00:21:35,410
很久沒睡這麼香了
Better than in a long time.

295
00:21:37,140 --> 00:21:39,640
我不想吵醒你
Well, I didn't want to wake you.

296
00:21:39,680 --> 00:21:41,380
我想讓你多睡會兒
I figured you could use it.

297
00:21:43,650 --> 00:21:46,450
-怎麼了　-我在想
- God. What? - I've been thinking

298
00:21:46,490 --> 00:21:48,750
被落下的那個人
about the man we left behind.

299
00:21:51,920 --> 00:21:53,360
你不是認真的吧
You're not serious.

300
00:22:02,470 --> 00:22:03,970
水來了
Water's here, y'all.

301
00:22:04,000 --> 00:22:06,570
提醒你們　燒開了再用
Just a reminder to boil before use.

302
00:22:13,110 --> 00:22:15,680
你是在問我意見還是通知我
Are you asking me or telling me?

303
00:22:16,850 --> 00:22:18,820
-問你意見　-我覺得你瘋了
- Asking. - Well, I think it's crazy.

304
00:22:18,850 --> 00:22:22,620
我覺得這樣實在是太蠢了
I think it is just the stupidest way to break your--

305
00:22:22,650 --> 00:22:24,090
-媽媽　-卡爾
- Mom! - Carl?

306
00:22:24,120 --> 00:22:25,420
在那邊
It's over there!

307
00:22:25,460 --> 00:22:26,790
-爸爸　-寶貝
- Dad! - Baby!

308
00:22:26,830 --> 00:22:29,260
-媽媽　媽咪　-瑞克　給
- Mama! Mommy! - Rick!

309
00:22:29,290 --> 00:22:31,330
-卡爾　-過來孩子們　快過來
- Carl! - Over here, boy! Come on, come on!

310
00:22:31,360 --> 00:22:33,860
卡爾　寶貝
Carl! Baby!

311
00:22:33,900 --> 00:22:36,000
-媽媽　-你沒事吧　過來　過來
- Mom! - You're okay! I've got him. I've got him.

312
00:22:36,030 --> 00:22:39,300
-有沒有被咬被抓傷　-沒有　我沒事
- Nothing bit you? Nothing scratched you? - No, I'm okay.

313
00:23:36,700 --> 00:23:38,900
頭一回在這裡碰上
It's the first one we've had up here.

314
00:23:38,930 --> 00:23:41,200
他們從沒跑這麼遠到山上來
They never come this far up the mountain.

315
00:23:41,230 --> 00:23:43,830
城裡沒吃的了　所以跑上山了
Well, they're running out of food in the city, that's what.

316
00:24:06,190 --> 00:24:10,060
-我靠　-狗娘養的
- Oh, Jesus. - Son of a bitch.

317
00:24:11,560 --> 00:24:13,560
那是我打到的鹿
That's my deer!

318
00:24:15,030 --> 00:24:17,060
瞧瞧　都讓這個
Look at it. All gnawed on by this...

319
00:24:17,100 --> 00:24:19,130
髒兮兮的　染了病的
filthy, disease-bearing,

320
00:24:19,170 --> 00:24:22,030
沒娘養的雜種糟蹋了
motherless poxy bastard!

321
00:24:22,070 --> 00:24:23,640
算了　孩子　這沒用
Calm down, son. That's not helping.

322
00:24:23,670 --> 00:24:25,300
你知道個屁　老不死的
What do you know about it, old man?

323
00:24:25,340 --> 00:24:28,110
戴著你這傻逼帽子回你的「金池塘」去吧
You take this stupid hat and go back to "On Golden Pond"?

324
00:24:29,170 --> 00:24:31,940
老子大老遠追著這隻鹿
I've been tracking this deer for miles.

325
00:24:31,980 --> 00:24:33,980
想把它帶回營地
Gonna drag it back to camp,

326
00:24:34,010 --> 00:24:36,080
給大伙上點鹿肉吃
cook us up some venison.

327
00:24:36,120 --> 00:24:38,080
你們覺得怎樣　把咬掉的這部分
What do you think? Do you think we can cut around

328
00:24:38,120 --> 00:24:39,650
割掉怎麼樣
this chewed up part right here?

329
00:24:39,690 --> 00:24:41,250
我才不冒那個險
I would not risk that.

330
00:24:41,290 --> 00:24:43,920
真他媽糟蹋了
That's a damn shame.

331
00:24:44,370 --> 00:24:46,590
我獵了些松鼠　十來只
I got some squirrel-- about a dozen or so.

332
00:24:47,320 --> 00:24:49,330
這能吃吧
That'll have to do.

333
00:24:53,800 --> 00:24:55,370
天啊
Oh god.

334
00:24:57,100 --> 00:24:59,100
你們這幫人　有沒有搞錯
Come on, people. What the hell?

335
00:25:06,750 --> 00:25:08,650
要命中腦袋才行
It's gotta be the brain.

336
00:25:09,410 --> 00:25:10,780
你們連這都不懂嗎
Don't y'all know nothing?

337
00:25:18,980 --> 00:25:20,730
莫爾
Merle!

338
00:25:22,560 --> 00:25:25,960
莫爾　你他媽的給我滾出來
Merle! Get your ugly ass out here!

339
00:25:27,130 --> 00:25:28,700
我獵了些松鼠
I got us some squirrel!

340
00:25:29,390 --> 00:25:30,500
過來一起煮
Let's stew 'em up.

341
00:25:31,900 --> 00:25:35,610
達裡爾　等一下　我有話跟你說
Daryl, just slow up a bit. I need to talk to you.

342
00:25:38,210 --> 00:25:40,040
說什麼
About what?

343
00:25:41,070 --> 00:25:42,350
莫爾
About Merle.

344
00:25:42,380 --> 00:25:46,020
在亞特蘭大出了些問題
There was a-- there was a problem in Atlanta.

345
00:25:53,960 --> 00:25:55,860
他死了嗎
He dead?

346
00:25:58,020 --> 00:25:59,430
還不確定
We're not sure.

347
00:25:59,940 --> 00:26:01,530
他是死是活你怎會不知道
He either is or he ain't!

348
00:26:01,570 --> 00:26:04,100
我只是不能確定
No easy way to say this, so I'll just say it.

349
00:26:05,170 --> 00:26:07,570
-你是誰　-瑞克·格蘭姆斯
- Who are you?　- Rick Grimes.

350
00:26:07,610 --> 00:26:11,140
瑞克·格蘭姆斯　你有什麼話要說
Rick Grimes, you got something you want to tell me?

351
00:26:11,180 --> 00:26:13,210
你哥哥對我們造成了威脅
Your brother was a danger to us all,

352
00:26:13,250 --> 00:26:16,350
所以我把他銬在屋頂的一條金屬管上
so I handcuffed him on a roof, hooked him to a piece of metal.

353
00:26:16,380 --> 00:26:18,620
他還在那兒
He's still there.

354
00:26:19,060 --> 00:26:22,390
慢著　讓我好好消化一下
Hold on. Let me process this.

355
00:26:22,620 --> 00:26:25,420
你是說你把我哥銬在屋頂上
You're saying you handcuffed my brother to a roof

356
00:26:25,460 --> 00:26:27,130
還把他丟在那裡
And you left him there?!

357
00:26:27,630 --> 00:26:29,060
是的
Yeah.

358
00:26:36,340 --> 00:26:37,870
小心刀子
Watch the knife!

359
00:26:42,240 --> 00:26:44,180
好了
Okay. Okay.

360
00:26:44,210 --> 00:26:47,510
-快放開我　-我看還是不要了
- You'd best let me go!　- Nah, I think it's better if I don't.

361
00:26:48,250 --> 00:26:49,650
鎖喉不合法
Chokehold's illegal.

362
00:26:49,680 --> 00:26:51,480
你去投訴吧
You can file a complaint.

363
00:26:51,520 --> 00:26:53,350
得了　夥計　我們能耗上一整天
Come on, man. We'll keep this up all day.

364
00:26:54,480 --> 00:26:57,200
我想和你冷靜下來談談這事
I'd like to have a calm discussion on this topic.

365
00:26:57,200 --> 00:26:59,620
你能做到嗎
Do you think we can manage that?

366
00:26:59,660 --> 00:27:02,830
你能做到嗎 
Do you think we can manage that?

367
00:27:08,400 --> 00:27:10,940
我那麼做並不是一時興起
What I did was not on a whim.

368
00:27:11,340 --> 00:27:15,040
你哥哥和其他人相處不太好
Your brother does not work and play well with others.

369
00:27:15,070 --> 00:27:19,010
那不是瑞克的錯　我拿著鑰匙
It's not Rick's fault. I had the key.

370
00:27:19,040 --> 00:27:21,710
-結果掉了　-你不能撿起來嗎
- I dropped it.　- You couldn't pick it up?

371
00:27:21,750 --> 00:27:24,180
我把它掉進下水道了
Well, I dropped it in a drain.

372
00:27:32,020 --> 00:27:34,330
別以為這能讓我好受點
If it's supposed to make me feel better, it don't.

373
00:27:34,360 --> 00:27:35,890
那不如聽聽這個
Well, maybe this will.

374
00:27:35,930 --> 00:27:37,860
我把屋頂的門用鎖鏈鎖上了
Look, I chained the door to the roof--

375
00:27:37,900 --> 00:27:39,600
所以那些行屍抓不到他
so the geeks couldn't get at him--

376
00:27:39,630 --> 00:27:43,400
-門上有掛鎖　-這該有點用吧
- With a padlock.　- It's gotta count for something.

377
00:27:49,040 --> 00:27:50,910
你們都給我去死
Hell with all y'all!

378
00:27:51,380 --> 00:27:53,240
告訴我他在哪裡
Just tell me where he is

379
00:27:53,280 --> 00:27:55,280
我去救他出來
so's I can go get him.

380
00:27:55,310 --> 00:27:57,920
他會帶你去
He'll show you.

381
00:27:57,950 --> 00:27:59,780
不是嗎
Isn't that right?

382
00:28:06,130 --> 00:28:08,130
我要回去
I'm going back.

383
00:28:26,270 --> 00:28:27,810
就這樣嗎
So that's it, huh?

384
00:28:27,810 --> 00:28:29,390
你準備這麼走掉
You're just gonna walk off?

385
00:28:29,400 --> 00:28:31,230
丟下所有人不管嗎
Just to hell with everybody else?

386
00:28:31,270 --> 00:28:33,170
我不會丟下所有人不管
I'm not saying to hell with anybody--

387
00:28:33,200 --> 00:28:35,500
至少不會丟下你和洛莉
Not you Shane; Lori least of all.

388
00:28:36,410 --> 00:28:37,700
跟她說吧
Tell her that.

389
00:28:39,740 --> 00:28:41,070
她懂的
She knows.

390
00:28:42,460 --> 00:28:43,780
聽著　我
Well, look, I--

391
00:28:43,810 --> 00:28:45,910
我不懂　瑞克　你可以
I don't, okay, Rick? So could you just--

392
00:28:45,950 --> 00:28:48,010
你可以告訴我嗎
Could you throw me a bone here, man?

393
00:28:48,050 --> 00:28:49,720
告訴我為什麼這麼做
Could you just tell me why?

394
00:28:49,750 --> 00:28:52,050
為什麼你要為莫爾·迪克森這種人渣冒這險
Why would you risk your life for a douche bag like Merle Dixon?

395
00:28:52,090 --> 00:28:54,590
-說話小心點　-我很小心了
- Hey, choose your words more carefully.　- No, I did.

396
00:28:54,620 --> 00:28:57,990
人渣算客氣的了　莫爾·迪克森
Douche bag's what I meant. Merle Dixon--

397
00:28:58,030 --> 00:29:00,730
即使你渴死他也不會給你水喝
The guy wouldn't give you a glass of water if you were dying of thirst.

398
00:29:00,730 --> 00:29:02,600
他這人怎麼樣與我無關
What he would or wouldn't do doesn't interest me.

399
00:29:02,630 --> 00:29:05,160
我可不會讓一個人渴死
I can't let a man die of thirst-- me.

400
00:29:05,200 --> 00:29:07,470
就這麼被活活曬死
Thirst and exposure.

401
00:29:07,900 --> 00:29:10,070
我們把他扔在那　就像掉進陷阱的動物
We left him like an animal caught in a trap.

402
00:29:10,100 --> 00:29:12,410
誰都不能這樣死　更別說一個活生生的人了
That's no way for anything to die, let alone a human being.

403
00:29:14,610 --> 00:29:17,480
就你和達裡爾倆　這就是你們的計劃嗎
So you and Daryl, that's your big plan?

404
00:29:21,280 --> 00:29:23,050
不是吧
Oh, come on.

405
00:29:23,080 --> 00:29:25,350
你認得路　你之前去過那兒
You know the way. You've been there before--

406
00:29:25,390 --> 00:29:27,690
進進出出都不是問題　你自己說的
In and out, no problem. You said so yourself.

407
00:29:29,190 --> 00:29:31,020
我知道這很不公平
It's not fair of me to ask-- I know that--

408
00:29:31,060 --> 00:29:32,630
但和你在一起我更有安全感
But I'd feel a lot better with you along.

409
00:29:32,660 --> 00:29:34,590
我想她也會這麼想
I know she would too.

410
00:29:35,610 --> 00:29:37,930
很好　你三個人一起去冒險
That's just great. Now you're gonna risk three men, huh?

411
00:29:37,970 --> 00:29:39,060
四個
Four.

412
00:29:40,470 --> 00:29:42,600
這麼多人　我真是受寵若驚
My day just gets better and better, don't it?

413
00:29:42,640 --> 00:29:44,670
你看還有別人主動站出來
You see anybody else here stepping up

414
00:29:44,710 --> 00:29:46,610
救你那混賬老哥麼
to save your brother's cracker ass?

415
00:29:47,000 --> 00:29:49,440
-那你幹嘛去　-你不會懂的
- Why you?　- You wouldn't even begin to understand.

416
00:29:50,050 --> 00:29:52,310
-我們不是一類人　-那就四個人吧
- You don't speak my language. - That's four.

417
00:29:52,350 --> 00:29:53,460
不只是四個人
It's not just four.

418
00:29:53,680 --> 00:29:55,780
你讓我們所有人都處於危險之中
You're putting every single one of us at risk.

419
00:29:55,820 --> 00:29:58,380
你也知道　瑞克　你看到那行屍
Just know that, Rick. Come on, you saw that walker.

420
00:29:58,420 --> 00:30:00,050
就在這兒　就出現在營地裡
It was here. It was in camp.

421
00:30:00,090 --> 00:30:01,550
他們開始在城市外行動了
They're moving out of the cities.

422
00:30:01,590 --> 00:30:03,490
他們要來了　我們需要所有有生力量
They come back, we need every able body we've got.

423
00:30:03,520 --> 00:30:05,290
我們要留在這裡保護營地
We need 'em here. We need 'em to protect camp.

424
00:30:05,330 --> 00:30:07,330
在我看來　這裡更需要的
It seems to me what you really need most here

425
00:30:08,430 --> 00:30:12,700
-是更多的槍　-沒錯　槍
- are more guns.　- Right, the guns.

426
00:30:12,730 --> 00:30:14,630
-等等　什麼槍　-六支獵槍
- Wait. What guns? - Six shotguns,

427
00:30:14,670 --> 00:30:17,670
兩支強火力步槍　還有十來支手槍
two high-powered rifles, over a dozen handguns.

428
00:30:17,700 --> 00:30:20,240
走之前　我把警局裡的倉庫搜了個遍
I cleaned out the cage back at the station before I left.

429
00:30:20,270 --> 00:30:22,980
在亞特蘭大被困住時　我把那袋子掉了
I dropped the bag in Atlanta when I got swarmed.

430
00:30:23,010 --> 00:30:25,750
就在大街上　我們得拿回來
It's just sitting there on the street, waiting to be picked up.

431
00:30:25,780 --> 00:30:30,350
-多少彈藥　-各式各樣一共七百發
- Ammo?　- 700 rounds, assorted.

432
00:30:31,160 --> 00:30:33,320
你歷經艱辛找到我們
You went through hell to find us.

433
00:30:33,350 --> 00:30:36,360
現在又要轉身離開嗎
You just got here and you're gonna turn around and leave?

434
00:30:37,900 --> 00:30:39,730
爸爸　我不想你去
Dad, I don't want you to go.

435
00:30:42,130 --> 00:30:44,800
別管那些槍了　肖恩是對的
To hell with the guns. Shane is right.

436
00:30:44,830 --> 00:30:46,970
莫爾·迪克森
Merle Dixon?

437
00:30:47,380 --> 00:30:50,340
就算加上那些槍　也不值得我們去冒險
He's not worth one of your lives, even with guns thrown in.

438
00:30:52,040 --> 00:30:54,040
告訴我為什麼
Tell me. Make me understand.

439
00:30:54,070 --> 00:30:58,640
我遇到一個男人和他的孩子　我欠他們人情
I owe a debt to a man I met and his little boy.

440
00:30:59,160 --> 00:31:01,180
洛莉　要不是他們收留了我
Lori, if they hadn't taken me in,

441
00:31:01,220 --> 00:31:03,180
我早就死了
I'd have died.

442
00:31:03,520 --> 00:31:05,950
如果沒有他們　我們不可能重逢
It's because of them that I made it back to you at all.

443
00:31:06,360 --> 00:31:08,390
他們說會跟著我到亞特蘭大
They said they'd follow me to Atlanta.

444
00:31:08,420 --> 00:31:10,890
如果我不提醒他　他們會重蹈我的覆轍
They'll walk into the same trap I did if I don't warn him.

445
00:31:12,060 --> 00:31:13,340
為什麼你聯繫不上他們
What's stopping you?

446
00:31:14,530 --> 00:31:17,400
對講機落在那個袋子裡了
The walkie-talkie, the one in the bag I dropped.

447
00:31:17,430 --> 00:31:18,600
他手裡也有一個
He's got the other one.

448
00:31:18,610 --> 00:31:20,900
我們本來說好他們快到時再聯繫
Our plan was to connect when they got closer.

449
00:31:20,930 --> 00:31:23,900
-是我們的對講機嗎　-對
- These are our walkies? - Yeah.

450
00:31:23,940 --> 00:31:25,910
那就用這個民用電台不行嗎
So use the C.B.. What's wrong with that?

451
00:31:25,940 --> 00:31:27,840
民用電台是可以
The C.B.'s fine.

452
00:31:27,870 --> 00:31:29,780
但那些垃圾對講機
It's the walkies that suck to crap--

453
00:31:29,810 --> 00:31:32,510
都是七十年代的了　不適用於其它頻寬
date back to the '70s, don't match any other bandwidth--

454
00:31:32,550 --> 00:31:34,280
連我們車裡的天線都不行
not even the scanners in our cars.

455
00:31:37,140 --> 00:31:38,880
我需要那個袋子
I need that bag.

456
00:31:51,790 --> 00:31:53,130
好嗎
Okay?

457
00:31:58,160 --> 00:31:59,870
好吧
All right.

458
00:32:04,010 --> 00:32:06,010
聽說你有斷線鉗
Rumor is you have bolt cutters.

459
00:32:08,050 --> 00:32:11,520
-可能吧　-到了屋頂上
- Maybe. - Yeah, we get to that roof, though,

460
00:32:11,550 --> 00:32:14,320
我們得弄斷鎖鏈和手銬
we'll need to cut that chain and the handcuffs.

461
00:32:15,820 --> 00:32:17,790
我向來不喜歡外借工具
I never like lending tools.

462
00:32:18,340 --> 00:32:19,530
上次有人借
The last time I did--

463
00:32:19,560 --> 00:32:21,730
對　說的就是你
and yes, I am talking about you--

464
00:32:21,760 --> 00:32:24,100
這麼說吧　被丟在那裡的
let's just say your bag of guns

465
00:32:24,130 --> 00:32:25,930
不只是你那袋槍而已
wasn't the only bag that was dropped.

466
00:32:25,970 --> 00:32:28,530
我的工具也被丟下了　在莫爾那
My tools got left behind with Merle.

467
00:32:29,080 --> 00:32:30,600
我們會把你的工具也帶回來
We'll bring your tools back too.

468
00:32:30,640 --> 00:32:33,910
就當斷線鉗是投資好了
Think of the bolt cutters as an investment.

469
00:32:35,510 --> 00:32:37,580
更像賭博才是
Sounds like more of a gamble.

470
00:32:44,690 --> 00:32:47,350
-那我有什麼好處　-想要什麼好處
- What do I get in return? - What do you want?

471
00:32:47,390 --> 00:32:49,160
要你們帶回來的一桿槍怎麼樣
How about one of those guns you bring back?

472
00:32:49,190 --> 00:32:51,560
-由我挑　-成交
- My pick. - Done.

473
00:32:52,490 --> 00:32:54,560
戴爾　不如…
Dale, let's...

474
00:32:55,450 --> 00:32:56,660
讓這交易多點甜頭
sweeten the deal a bit.

475
00:32:57,900 --> 00:32:59,540
你的那輛小貨車
Now that cube van of yours--

476
00:33:00,330 --> 00:33:01,710
車怎麼了
What about it?

477
00:33:01,740 --> 00:33:03,980
房車的水箱軟管被擊中了
The R.V.'s radiator hose is shot.

478
00:33:04,390 --> 00:33:05,180
如果我們要轉移或者跑遠路
That's a problem if we

479
00:33:05,180 --> 00:33:07,580
就會出問題
need to get somewhere and wanna get very far.

480
00:33:07,610 --> 00:33:11,320
用你小貨車上的軟管正好合適
And the hose on that van is just about a perfect match--

481
00:33:11,350 --> 00:33:13,320
總之　我可以讓它完全合適
Well, enough that I can make it fit.

482
00:33:14,010 --> 00:33:15,420
這麼說吧　等我們回來
I'll tell you what-- we get back,

483
00:33:15,450 --> 00:33:19,020
你要把那車拆成廢鐵我都沒意見
you can strip that van down to the bare metal.

484
00:33:21,590 --> 00:33:24,330
-快點　出發吧　-謝謝你
- Come on, let's go! - Thank you.

485
00:33:29,820 --> 00:33:33,040
瑞克　蟒蛇轉輪裡還有子彈嗎
Hey, Rick, got any rounds in the Python?

486
00:33:34,830 --> 00:33:35,770
沒有
No.

487
00:33:35,810 --> 00:33:37,380
上次咱倆射擊比賽的時候
Last time we were on the gun range,

488
00:33:37,770 --> 00:33:40,680
我最後肯定拿了一些你的松頭子彈
I'm sure I wound up with a few loose rounds of yours.

489
00:33:42,250 --> 00:33:45,380
你和那個袋子　就像個百寶箱
You and that bag-- like the bottom of an old lady's purse.

490
00:33:45,420 --> 00:33:47,020
你這麼做　我很不爽　夥計
I hate that you're doing this, man.

491
00:33:47,050 --> 00:33:49,590
愚蠢而魯莽
I think that it's foolish and reckless.

492
00:33:49,620 --> 00:33:52,120
但如果你執意要去　好歹帶上子彈
But if you're gonna go, you're taking bullets.

493
00:33:52,840 --> 00:33:55,560
我不太想在城裡開槍
I'm not sure I'd want to fire a shot in the city,

494
00:33:55,590 --> 00:33:58,160
-前車之鑒　-隨你的便
- Not after what happened last time. - That's up to you.

495
00:33:59,500 --> 00:34:01,170
好吧
Well...

496
00:34:04,540 --> 00:34:06,100
四個人　四發子彈
Four men, four rounds.

497
00:34:07,310 --> 00:34:08,910
太巧了　不是嗎
What are the odds, huh?

498
00:34:10,200 --> 00:34:11,810
我們只能希望…
Well, let's just hope that--

499
00:34:11,840 --> 00:34:14,510
四是你的幸運數字吧
let's just hope four is your lucky number, okay?

500
00:34:15,750 --> 00:34:18,420
-謝謝　-不客氣
- Thank you. - All right.

501
00:34:51,920 --> 00:34:53,750
我覺得他們會沒事
You know, I bet they'll be just fine.

502
00:34:54,920 --> 00:34:56,950
我不擔心
I'm not worried.

503
00:35:00,220 --> 00:35:01,390
你擔心嗎
Are you?

504
00:35:04,290 --> 00:35:05,960
嗯　有一點
Yeah, a little.

505
00:35:07,130 --> 00:35:08,570
不用擔心
Don't be.

506
00:35:10,040 --> 00:35:12,300
-為什麼　-你想啊　媽媽
- Why? - Think about it, mom.

507
00:35:12,340 --> 00:35:14,970
他經歷了這麼多事
Everything that's happened to him so far--

508
00:35:16,010 --> 00:35:17,910
卻還是安然無恙
nothing's killed him yet.

509
00:35:35,830 --> 00:35:37,030
他最好沒事
He'd better be okay.

510
00:35:37,450 --> 00:35:39,160
我就這一句話
It's my only word on the matter.

511
00:35:39,200 --> 00:35:41,100
告訴過你了　行屍們無法接近他
I told you the geeks can't get at him.

512
00:35:41,800 --> 00:35:45,040
只有我們能打開那扇門
The only thing that's gonna get through that door is us.

513
00:35:48,840 --> 00:35:49,770
從這開始步行吧
We walk from here.

514
00:36:09,530 --> 00:36:10,390
戴爾
Dale.

515
00:36:11,700 --> 00:36:14,900
-看到卡爾了嗎　-肖恩帶他去採石場了
- Have you seen Carl? - Shane took him down to the quarry.

516
00:36:14,930 --> 00:36:18,140
還大言不慚地說要抓一堆青蛙呢
There was some mighty bold talk about catching frogs.

517
00:36:27,980 --> 00:36:30,250
我什麼都捉不到
I'm not getting anything.

518
00:36:30,520 --> 00:36:32,220
對啊
Yeah.

519
00:36:32,250 --> 00:36:34,490
牠們都狡猾地躲在水下了
Being all wily, staying submerged.

520
00:36:34,520 --> 00:36:36,420
那幫小廢物肯定發現情況不妙了
Little suckers, they know something's up.

521
00:36:36,460 --> 00:36:37,920
肯定是這樣
That's what's going on.

522
00:36:37,960 --> 00:36:40,830
只好用老辦法解決了
Just going to have to do this the old-fashioned way.

523
00:36:41,660 --> 00:36:43,300
聽著　小伙子
All right, little man, look.

524
00:36:43,330 --> 00:36:45,830
你才是關鍵
You are the-- you are the key in all this, okay?

525
00:36:45,870 --> 00:36:47,930
我只是負責去追牠們中的一隻
All I'm gonna do is I'm gonna go after one of them,

526
00:36:47,970 --> 00:36:49,530
把其它的都嚇跑
All right, scare the rest of them off.

527
00:36:49,570 --> 00:36:51,600
牠們會四處逃竄　我把牠們都往你那邊趕
They're all gonna scatter. I'm gonna drive 'em your way.

528
00:36:51,640 --> 00:36:53,610
-好吧　-你就負責捉住每個
- All right. - What you need to do is you need to round up

529
00:36:53,640 --> 00:36:55,770
打你眼皮底下溜過的小壞蛋　懂了嗎
every bad boy you see, all right? Are you with me?

530
00:36:55,810 --> 00:36:57,640
-懂了　-懂了就好　凶一點我看看
- Yeah. Yeah. - Hells yeah. Give me your mean face.

531
00:36:57,680 --> 00:36:59,510
好了長官　準備好了嗎
Yes sir. Are you ready?

532
00:36:59,550 --> 00:37:01,010
-準備好了　-準備好了嗎　開始吧
- Yeah! - Are you ready? Here we go, boy.

533
00:37:12,560 --> 00:37:14,460
好了　小伙子　牠們朝你的方向去了
All right, little man, they're coming your way.

534
00:37:14,490 --> 00:37:16,090
朝你那去了　快　抓住牠們
They're coming your wa go on, get 'em, get 'em.

535
00:37:16,130 --> 00:37:17,460
朝你那去了　快點
They're coming your way, come on.

536
00:37:17,500 --> 00:37:20,330
捉住這些小青蛙　捉住這些小青蛙
Catch them frogs. Catch them frogs.

537
00:37:20,370 --> 00:37:21,490
來了來了　小伙子
They're coming, little man!

538
00:37:21,490 --> 00:37:23,270
快抓　把網放那邊抓住牠們
Get 'em! Get that net in there and get 'em!

539
00:37:23,300 --> 00:37:27,210
我開始置疑這裡的勞動分工問題了
I'm beginning to question the division of labor here.

540
00:37:27,240 --> 00:37:28,220
牠們來了　小伙子
They're coming, little man!

541
00:37:28,220 --> 00:37:29,780
快用網網住牠們　快　抓住牠們
Get 'em! Get that net in there and get 'em!

542
00:37:29,810 --> 00:37:32,840
壞小子　有啥收穫　都抓到啥啦
What have you got, bad boy? What do you got? What do you got?

543
00:37:33,600 --> 00:37:34,420
屁也沒 
Dirt.

544
00:37:34,420 --> 00:37:37,220
可憐的娃　算了　咱繼續努力
Oh boy. All right, we've got to start over.

545
00:37:37,250 --> 00:37:40,950
加油吧　先找水桶
Come on, let's find this bucket.

546
00:37:40,990 --> 00:37:42,310
有人能解釋一下為什麼女人
Can someone explain to me how the

547
00:37:42,310 --> 00:37:44,320
就得跟菲傭似的盡伺候男人
women wound up doing all the Hattie Mcdaniel work?

548
00:37:42,310 --> 00:37:44,320
海蒂·麥克丹尼爾　黑人女演員　在眾多影片中飾演女傭

549
00:37:44,360 --> 00:37:46,830
世界末日到了　你不知道嗎　
The world ended. Didn't you get the memo?

550
00:37:50,230 --> 00:37:51,600
世道就是如此　認了吧
It's just the way it is.

551
00:38:02,970 --> 00:38:04,910
-先救莫爾還是先取槍　-先救莫爾
- Merle first or guns? - Merle!

552
00:38:04,940 --> 00:38:07,580
-沒的商量　-我們得計劃一下
- We ain't even having this conversation. - We are.

553
00:38:07,610 --> 00:38:09,180
這裡你比較熟悉　由你決定
You know the geography. It's your call.

554
00:38:09,220 --> 00:38:10,250
莫爾離這最近 
Merle's closest.

555
00:38:10,250 --> 00:38:12,320
取槍的話　我們得原路折回
The guns would mean doubling back.

556
00:38:12,350 --> 00:38:13,990
先救莫爾
Merle first.

557
00:38:18,750 --> 00:38:20,530
我真想念我的洗衣機
I do miss my Maytag.

558
00:38:18,750 --> 00:38:20,530
美泰克公司生產洗衣機等產品

559
00:38:23,070 --> 00:38:26,130
我想念我的奔馳和衛星導航系統　
I miss my Benz, my sat nav.

560
00:38:26,170 --> 00:38:27,830
我想念我那台
I miss my coffeemaker

561
00:38:27,870 --> 00:38:29,770
帶有雙向滴漏過濾器
with that dual-drip filter

562
00:38:29,800 --> 00:38:32,140
以及內置研磨器的咖啡機
and built-in grinder, honey.

563
00:38:32,170 --> 00:38:33,810
我想我的電腦…
My computer...

564
00:38:33,840 --> 00:38:35,510
還有發短信
And texting.

565
00:38:36,680 --> 00:38:38,010
我想念我的按摩棒
I miss my vibrator.

566
00:38:40,550 --> 00:38:43,220
天吶
Oh my god!

567
00:38:46,470 --> 00:38:48,550
我也想
Me too.

568
00:38:54,520 --> 00:38:56,090
你們笑什麼呢
What's so funny?

569
00:38:56,130 --> 00:38:58,200
分享個人英勇事跡而已　愛德
Just swapping war stories, Ed.

570
00:38:59,270 --> 00:39:00,830
對吧
Yeah.

571
00:39:12,450 --> 00:39:14,250
有事嗎　愛德
Problem, Ed?

572
00:39:15,250 --> 00:39:17,020
與你無關
Nothin' that concerns you.

573
00:39:18,180 --> 00:39:20,950
專心洗你的衣服　廢話少說
And you ought to focus on your work.

574
00:39:20,990 --> 00:39:23,520
這可不是什麼喜劇俱樂部
This ain't no comedy club.

575
00:39:26,490 --> 00:39:28,390
卡爾
Hey, Carl.

576
00:39:28,430 --> 00:39:30,730
我不是跟你說過別離開戴爾的視線嗎
What did I tell you about not leaving Dale's sight?

577
00:39:30,760 --> 00:39:33,330
可肖恩說我們要一起抓青蛙　還記得嗎
But Shane said we could catch frogs, remember?

578
00:39:33,370 --> 00:39:35,370
肖恩說什麼不打緊　聽我的就是了
It doesn't matter what Shane says. It matters what I say.

579
00:39:35,400 --> 00:39:38,040
走吧　回營地去
Go on back to camp.

580
00:39:38,070 --> 00:39:40,070
我就跟在你後面
I'll be right behind you.

581
00:39:43,780 --> 00:39:45,610
恕我直言
I've got to tell you,

582
00:39:45,650 --> 00:39:47,680
我認為你不該拿他出氣
I do not think you should be taking this out on him.

583
00:39:47,710 --> 00:39:48,860
不用你來告訴我怎麼做 
You don't tell me what to do.

584
00:39:48,860 --> 00:39:49,980
你已經沒這個權利了
You lost that privilege.

585
00:39:50,020 --> 00:39:52,180
洛莉　等一下好嗎
Lori, could you just wait up a second?

586
00:39:52,220 --> 00:39:53,250
我們該談談　我們都沒有機會…
I think we should talk. We haven't had a chance--

587
00:39:53,250 --> 00:39:54,290
不了　不用談了
No. No no.

588
00:39:54,320 --> 00:39:56,290
我們已經結束了　要談跟青蛙談去
That's over too. You can tell that to the frogs.

589
00:39:56,320 --> 00:39:57,170
該死　洛莉　
Damn it, Lori.

590
00:39:57,170 --> 00:39:58,220
我不知道你是如何看待這事　
Look, I don't know how it appears to you

591
00:39:58,260 --> 00:39:59,250
或者你是怎麼想的… 
or what you think--

592
00:39:59,250 --> 00:40:00,190
我是如何看的　抱歉
How it appears to me? I'm sorry.

593
00:40:00,230 --> 00:40:02,890
難道我說的還不夠清楚嗎　我再說一遍
Is there a gray area here? Let me dispel it.

594
00:40:02,930 --> 00:40:05,030
你離我遠點　離我兒子遠點
You stay away from me. You stay away from my son.

595
00:40:05,060 --> 00:40:07,070
別看著他　別跟他說話
You don't look at him. You don't talk to him.

596
00:40:07,100 --> 00:40:09,670
從現在開始　禁止與我們一家人接觸
From now on, my family is off-limits to you.

597
00:40:12,000 --> 00:40:14,010
洛莉　這不公平
Lori, I don't think that's fair.

598
00:40:14,040 --> 00:40:17,110
-肖恩　閉嘴　給我閉嘴　-我認為…
- Shane, shut up. Don't! - I don't think that--

599
00:40:17,140 --> 00:40:20,650
我老公回來了　他還活著
My husband is back. He is alive.

600
00:40:21,240 --> 00:40:23,450
他是我最好的兄弟
He's my best friend.

601
00:40:23,480 --> 00:40:26,350
你覺得我反而不高興嗎
Do you think I'm not happy about that?

602
00:40:26,390 --> 00:40:28,520
你怎麼敢這樣　你為什麼做這種事
How dare you? Why would you be?

603
00:40:28,550 --> 00:40:31,890
是你告訴我他已經死了
You are the one that told me that he died.

604
00:40:33,760 --> 00:40:35,830
你個狗雜種
You son of a bitch.

605
00:41:03,020 --> 00:41:06,790
操　你個噁心巴拉的小丑
Damn. You are one ugly skank.

606
00:41:32,390 --> 00:41:33,790
愛德　這麼說吧
Ed, tell you what--

607
00:41:34,230 --> 00:41:35,720
既然你不樂意我們洗你的衣服
You don't like how your laundry is done,

608
00:41:35,760 --> 00:41:39,090
我們倒是很樂意你自個兒洗　接著
you are welcome to pitch in and do it yourself. Here.

609
00:41:40,230 --> 00:41:41,890
美女　這不是我該幹的活　
Ain't my job, missy.

610
00:41:41,930 --> 00:41:42,970
安德莉亞　別這樣　
Andrea, don't.

611
00:41:42,970 --> 00:41:44,100
那你幹什麼活　愛德
What is your job, Ed?

612
00:41:44,130 --> 00:41:45,960
死坐著抽菸嗎
Sitting on your ass smoking cigarettes?

613
00:41:46,000 --> 00:41:47,200
總比聽一個自作聰明的婊子
Well, it sure as hell ain't listening

614
00:41:47,230 --> 00:41:48,670
說教來的強
to some uppity smart-mouthed bitch.

615
00:41:48,700 --> 00:41:52,040
明白嗎　我們走
Tell you what-- come on. Let's go.

616
00:41:52,070 --> 00:41:54,240
我認為她沒必要跟著你走　愛德
I don't think she needs to go anywhere with you, Ed.

617
00:41:54,240 --> 00:41:56,410
干你屁事　快點
And I say it's none of your business. Come on now.

618
00:41:56,440 --> 00:41:58,440
-你聽到了　-卡蘿爾
- You heard me. - Carol.

619
00:41:58,480 --> 00:42:00,610
安德莉亞　放心　沒事的
Andrea, please. It doesn't matter.

620
00:42:00,650 --> 00:42:03,250
別以為自己讀過大學
Hey, don't think I won't knock you on your ass

621
00:42:03,280 --> 00:42:05,080
我就不會揍你　你就一逼貨
just 'cause you're some college-educated cooze,

622
00:42:05,120 --> 00:42:06,750
聽明白了嗎
All right?

623
00:42:06,790 --> 00:42:09,420
你要麼現在跟我走　要不有你後悔的
Now you come on now or you gonna regret it later.

624
00:42:09,460 --> 00:42:11,760
不然她會帶著新傷出現嗎　愛德
So she can show up with fresh bruises later, Ed?

625
00:42:11,790 --> 00:42:13,760
是呀　我們親眼見過
Yeah, we've seen them.

626
00:42:13,790 --> 00:42:15,990
別多管閒事　快點
Stay out of this. Now come on!

627
00:42:16,030 --> 00:42:18,460
你知道嗎　這跟你們屁點關係也沒
You know what? This ain't none of y'all's business.

628
00:42:18,500 --> 00:42:21,070
你們也不想惹怒一頭公牛吧
You don't want to keep prodding the bull here, okay?

629
00:42:21,100 --> 00:42:23,640
話我已經說夠了　趕緊走
Now I am done talking. Come on.

630
00:42:23,670 --> 00:42:25,900
不　別走　卡蘿爾　你不必…　
No no. Carol, you don't have-- -

631
00:42:25,940 --> 00:42:28,410
你再多舌試試用　告訴你
You don't tell me what! I tell you what!

632
00:42:30,610 --> 00:42:32,680
-你別以為你能怎麼著　-放開她
- You think you can-- - Get off her!

633
00:42:32,710 --> 00:42:34,510
-過來　過來　-放開她
- Come here! Come here! - Get off her!

634
00:42:34,550 --> 00:42:37,250
-放開她　放開她　-放開我
- Get off her! Get off her! - Get off me!

635
00:42:37,280 --> 00:42:39,520
愛德
Ed?

636
00:42:39,550 --> 00:42:41,650
-沒事的　沒事　-不要
- It's okay. It's okay. - No!

637
00:42:42,860 --> 00:42:44,290
-沒事的　-不要
- It's okay. - No!

638
00:42:55,800 --> 00:42:57,940
肖恩　別打了
Shane, stop!

639
00:42:57,970 --> 00:42:59,400
快住手
Just stop!

640
00:43:00,570 --> 00:43:03,070
別打了
Stop it!

641
00:43:03,110 --> 00:43:05,080
-別打了　-你要是再敢對你的妻子
- Stop! - You put your hands on your wife,

642
00:43:05,110 --> 00:43:07,050
女兒或者這裡的任何一個人動手
your little girl or anybody else in this camp

643
00:43:07,080 --> 00:43:09,410
下次我不會就這麼放過你　聽到了沒
one more time, I will not stop next time. Do you hear me?

644
00:43:09,450 --> 00:43:11,320
-你聽到了沒　-聽到了
- Do you hear me?! - Yes.

645
00:43:11,350 --> 00:43:13,250
-我會打死你　愛德　-愛德
- I'll beat you to death, Ed. - Ed!

646
00:43:13,290 --> 00:43:15,990
老天爺
Oh god!

647
00:43:16,020 --> 00:43:17,560
不要
No.

648
00:43:17,590 --> 00:43:20,060
天哪
God!

649
00:43:21,260 --> 00:43:24,160
愛德　對不起
Ed, I'm sorry.

650
00:43:24,200 --> 00:43:27,870
天哪　愛德　都是我的錯
Oh my god. Ed, I'm sorry.

651
00:43:29,000 --> 00:43:32,040
對不起　愛德
I'm so sorry, Ed.

652
00:43:32,070 --> 00:43:34,610
愛德　對不起
Ed, I'm sorry.

653
00:43:34,640 --> 00:43:36,780
對不起　愛德
I'm sorry, Ed.

654
00:43:52,320 --> 00:43:55,460
莫爾　莫爾
Merle! Merle!

655
00:44:01,800 --> 00:44:04,770
不　不
No! No!

656
00:44:09,910 --> 00:44:11,540
不
No!

657
00:44:23,260 --> 00:44:26,360
天吶　不
No! No!

