1
00:00:11,000 --> 00:00:12,380
女士　女士　求你
Ma'am. Ma'am, please.

2
00:00:12,410 --> 00:00:14,280
-幫我一把　-不行不行
- Please, can you help me? - No no!

3
00:00:16,010 --> 00:00:18,810
解決他們　解決他們
Check them all. Check them all.

4
00:00:47,660 --> 00:00:49,240
好吧
Okay.

5
00:00:49,710 --> 00:00:51,340
兄弟我帶你出去
I'm gonna get you out of here, bud.

6
00:00:54,680 --> 00:00:57,240
好吧
Okay. Okay.

7
00:01:06,400 --> 00:01:07,930
我該怎麼辦
What do I do?

8
00:01:13,240 --> 00:01:15,000
快點　下士　快走
Come on, corporal. Move out!

9
00:01:27,740 --> 00:01:30,290
聽著　如果你要醒過來　求你馬上醒過來
Listen to me. If you're gonna wake up, I need you to do it now.

10
00:01:30,290 --> 00:01:31,610
可以嗎　快醒醒
Okay? Now.

11
00:01:31,880 --> 00:01:34,550
求你了兄弟　給我點提示　隨便什麼都行
Please, man, just show me a sign. Anything.

12
00:01:34,590 --> 00:01:37,720
求你了　瑞克
Please, Rick.

13
00:01:41,340 --> 00:01:43,030
這地方要陷落了
The place is coming down!

14
00:01:43,060 --> 00:01:45,500
撤退　所有人員都撤退
Fall back! All units fall back.

15
00:01:59,350 --> 00:02:00,950
我
I'm...

16
00:02:05,300 --> 00:02:06,550
沒事
I'm okay.

17
00:02:48,740 --> 00:02:50,400
YYeTs人人影視誠意奉獻

18
00:02:52,540 --> 00:02:54,210
翻譯 海因裡希

19
00:02:55,820 --> 00:02:57,640
翻譯 原子蛋

20
00:02:57,650 --> 00:02:59,510
翻譯 點點點 憶

21
00:03:02,870 --> 00:03:04,070
時間軸 之間

22
00:03:04,070 --> 00:03:05,170
校對 海因裡希

23
00:03:05,170 --> 00:03:06,300
後期/特效 WiLL

24
00:03:06,300 --> 00:03:07,470
監製 海因裡希

25
00:03:07,480 --> 00:03:10,480
CHD版個人美化微修：字幕雷哥

26
00:03:19,070 --> 00:03:23,920
走

27
00:03:19,820 --> 00:03:23,920
肉

28
00:03:20,170 --> 00:03:23,920
行屍

29
00:03:20,170 --> 00:03:23,920
『第一季 第六集 本季完』

30
00:03:30,420 --> 00:03:32,330
達裡爾　你掩護後面
Daryl, you cover the back.

31
00:03:34,570 --> 00:03:36,230
有人嗎
Hello?

32
00:03:38,010 --> 00:03:40,100
-有人嗎　-注意門口
- Hello? - Watch those doors.

33
00:03:40,140 --> 00:03:41,300
小心行屍
Watch for walkers.

34
00:03:48,550 --> 00:03:50,120
有人嗎
Hello?

35
00:03:52,890 --> 00:03:54,760
有沒有誰被感染
Anybody infected?

36
00:03:54,790 --> 00:03:56,790
有個人被感染了
One of our group was.

37
00:03:57,630 --> 00:04:00,520
他沒撐到這
He didn't make it.

38
00:04:01,110 --> 00:04:03,250
為什麼來這　你們要幹什麼
Why are you here? What do you want?

39
00:04:03,640 --> 00:04:05,960
一個機會
A chance.

40
00:04:05,990 --> 00:04:08,630
這年頭這也算是奢望了
That's asking an awful lot these days.

41
00:04:10,160 --> 00:04:12,010
我知道
I know.

42
00:04:23,170 --> 00:04:25,040
你們都得做個血液檢測
You all submit to a blood test.

43
00:04:25,080 --> 00:04:26,580
檢測完才能進來
That's the price of admission.

44
00:04:26,610 --> 00:04:28,520
可以
We can do that.

45
00:04:30,420 --> 00:04:31,700
把行李都弄進來　馬上
You got stuff to bring in, you do it now.

46
00:04:31,700 --> 00:04:34,390
這門要是關了　就開不了
Once this door closes, it stays closed.

47
00:04:40,640 --> 00:04:42,500
維　密封大門
Vi, seal the main entrance.

48
00:04:42,530 --> 00:04:44,470
關閉這裡的電源
Kill the power up here.

49
00:04:50,030 --> 00:04:51,940
我是瑞克·格蘭姆斯
Rick Grimes.

50
00:04:52,920 --> 00:04:54,740
我是埃德溫·詹納博士
Dr. Edwin Jenner.

51
00:04:57,780 --> 00:05:00,920
博士們四處走動時都拿著槍嗎
Doctors always go around packing heat like that?

52
00:05:00,950 --> 00:05:04,220
外面躺著很多行屍呢　我很清楚
There were plenty left lying around. I familiarized myself.

53
00:05:05,650 --> 00:05:08,660
不過你們看上去沒什麼威脅
But you look harmless enough.

54
00:05:08,700 --> 00:05:10,080
除了你
Except you.

55
00:05:10,930 --> 00:05:12,690
我會盯著你
I'll have to keep my eye on you.

56
00:05:20,600 --> 00:05:22,340
我們在地下嗎
Are we underground?

57
00:05:22,780 --> 00:05:24,070
你有幽閉恐怖症嗎
Are you claustrophobic?

58
00:05:24,110 --> 00:05:26,870
-有點　-別去想就不怕
- A little. - Try not to think about it.

59
00:05:31,570 --> 00:05:34,790
維　把大廳的燈點亮
Vi, bring up the lights in the big room.

60
00:05:41,100 --> 00:05:42,700
歡迎來到第五區
Welcome to zone 5.

61
00:05:43,720 --> 00:05:45,430
其他人在哪兒
Where is everybody?

62
00:05:45,470 --> 00:05:47,430
其他博士和員工呢
The other doctors, the staff?

63
00:05:50,230 --> 00:05:52,230
就是我
I'm it.

64
00:05:52,260 --> 00:05:54,140
這兒只有我
It's just me here.

65
00:05:55,510 --> 00:05:57,540
那你剛跟誰說話
What about the person you were speaking with?

66
00:05:58,460 --> 00:06:00,180
維
Vi?

67
00:06:00,220 --> 00:06:03,610
維　跟大家打個招呼
Vi, say hello to our guests.

68
00:06:03,640 --> 00:06:06,980
歡迎下大家
Tell them... welcome.

69
00:06:07,020 --> 00:06:09,720
大家好　歡迎你們
Hello, guests. Welcome.

70
00:06:10,710 --> 00:06:12,850
這裡就剩下我
I'm all that's left.

71
00:06:16,260 --> 00:06:18,170
讓大家失望了
I'm sorry.

72
00:06:21,770 --> 00:06:23,970
這有什麼意義　如果我們被感染了
What's the point? If we were infected,

73
00:06:23,970 --> 00:06:25,770
肯定會發燒
we'd all be running a fever.

74
00:06:26,850 --> 00:06:29,400
我把你們放進來　已經違反了所有規定
I've already broken every rule in the book letting you in here.

75
00:06:29,430 --> 00:06:31,910
至少讓我守一點點規矩
Let me just at least be thorough.

76
00:06:33,940 --> 00:06:34,980
可以了
All done.

77
00:06:37,410 --> 00:06:39,540
你沒事吧
Are you okay?

78
00:06:39,570 --> 00:06:41,840
她幾天沒吃東西了
She hasn't eaten in days.

79
00:06:42,490 --> 00:06:43,990
我們也一樣
None of us have.

80
00:06:48,310 --> 00:06:49,120
好吧
Fine.

81
00:06:49,150 --> 00:06:50,630
知道嗎　在意大利
You know, in Italy,

82
00:06:51,290 --> 00:06:54,290
吃飯時　孩子們也可以喝點小酒
children have a little bit of wine with dinner.

83
00:06:54,320 --> 00:06:55,890
在法國也是
And in France.

84
00:06:55,920 --> 00:06:58,690
要是卡爾在意大利或法國
Well, when Carl is in Italy or France,

85
00:06:58,720 --> 00:07:01,360
-那他也可以喝點　-這有什麼大不了　拜託
- he can have some then. - What's it gonna hurt? Come on.

86
00:07:01,880 --> 00:07:03,200
通融一下
Come on.

87
00:07:03,240 --> 00:07:05,440
怎麼
What?

88
00:07:08,100 --> 00:07:10,100
給　小伙子
There you are, young lad.

89
00:07:16,420 --> 00:07:18,350
這才是我兒子
That's my boy. That's my boy.

90
00:07:20,080 --> 00:07:21,950
-乖孩子　-好難喝
- Good boy. - Yuck.

91
00:07:21,980 --> 00:07:24,180
真難喝
That tastes nasty.

92
00:07:24,230 --> 00:07:26,620
你還是喝點果汁吧　夥計
Well, just stick to sour pop there, bud.

93
00:07:26,660 --> 00:07:28,620
-沒說你　格倫　-什麼
- Not you, Glenn. - What?

94
00:07:28,660 --> 00:07:29,770
你繼續喝　小伙子
Keep drinking, little man.

95
00:07:29,770 --> 00:07:31,490
我想瞧瞧你能臉紅到什麼地步
I want to see how red your face can get.

96
00:07:39,310 --> 00:07:42,210
好像還沒正式感謝招待我們的主人
It seems to me we haven't thanked our host properly.

97
00:07:42,240 --> 00:07:44,300
他為我們所做的遠不止這些
He is more than just our host.

98
00:07:44,330 --> 00:07:47,500
-乾　乾　-敬你一杯　博士　乾
- Hear hear! - Here's to you, doc. Booyah!

99
00:07:47,530 --> 00:07:49,160
-乾　-謝謝你
- Booyah! - Thank you!

100
00:07:49,210 --> 00:07:51,640
乾
Booyah!

101
00:07:51,680 --> 00:07:54,600
你啥時準備告訴我們這裡的事　博士
So when are you gonna tell us what the hell happened here, doc?

102
00:07:56,680 --> 00:07:59,790
其他的那些博士
All the-- the other doctors

103
00:08:00,500 --> 00:08:02,810
本該在這裡研究對策
that were supposed to be figuring out what happened.

104
00:08:02,840 --> 00:08:05,450
-他們到哪去了　-咱們在慶祝　肖恩
- Where are they? - We're celebrating, Shane.

105
00:08:06,020 --> 00:08:07,990
現在別說這些
Don't need to do this now.

106
00:08:08,030 --> 00:08:11,230
慢著　這正是我們此行的目的吧
Whoa, wait a second. This is why we're here, right?

107
00:08:12,360 --> 00:08:13,270
你的目的
This was your move--

108
00:08:13,270 --> 00:08:15,900
就是要尋找答案吧
supposed to find all the answers.

109
00:08:15,930 --> 00:08:17,770
結果呢
Instead we--

110
00:08:17,800 --> 00:08:20,140
我們找到他
we found him.

111
00:08:20,170 --> 00:08:23,000
只找到一個人　為什麼
Found one man. Why?

112
00:08:24,300 --> 00:08:25,820
災難降臨後
Well, when things got bad,

113
00:08:25,820 --> 00:08:28,840
很多人都走了
a lot of people just left.

114
00:08:29,610 --> 00:08:32,310
找他們的家人去了
Went off to be with their families.

115
00:08:32,790 --> 00:08:34,240
後來形勢惡化
And when things got worse,

116
00:08:34,240 --> 00:08:37,380
軍事防禦被擊潰
when the military cordon got overrun,

117
00:08:37,420 --> 00:08:39,140
其他人都逃跑了
the rest bolted.

118
00:08:39,640 --> 00:08:41,660
所有的人嗎
Every last one?

119
00:08:41,690 --> 00:08:45,820
不　很多人無法面對外面的世界
No, many couldn't face walking out the door.

120
00:08:47,720 --> 00:08:51,030
他們別無選擇
They... opted out.

121
00:08:51,490 --> 00:08:54,110
許多人都自殺了
There was a rash of suicides.

122
00:08:56,710 --> 00:08:58,990
真是不堪回首
That was a bad time.

123
00:08:58,990 --> 00:09:00,840
你沒走
You didn't leave.

124
00:09:01,650 --> 00:09:02,710
為什麼
Why?

125
00:09:02,750 --> 00:09:04,710
我一直在工作
I just kept working.

126
00:09:04,750 --> 00:09:08,100
想做點有用的事
Hoping to do some good.

127
00:09:12,010 --> 00:09:15,080
你真掃大家的興　夥計
Dude, you are such a buzzkill, man.

128
00:09:18,280 --> 00:09:20,550
中心大多地方都斷電了
Most of the facility is powered down

129
00:09:20,590 --> 00:09:23,130
包括宿舍　所以你們只能在這湊合
Including housing, so you'll have to make do here.

130
00:09:23,760 --> 00:09:25,190
沙發挺舒服
The couches are comfortable,

131
00:09:25,230 --> 00:09:27,560
喜歡的話倉庫裡還有吊床
But there are cots in storage if you like.

132
00:09:28,880 --> 00:09:31,870
大廳那邊有個娛樂室　孩子們可能會喜歡
There's a rec room down the hall that you kids might enjoy.

133
00:09:31,900 --> 00:09:34,870
只是不要玩電子遊戲　好嗎
Just don't plug in the video games, okay?

134
00:09:34,910 --> 00:09:37,740
任何要用電的都不行　同樣的
or anything that draws power. The same applies--

135
00:09:37,770 --> 00:09:39,770
如果你們要洗澡　用熱水好了
If you shower, go easy on the hot water.

136
00:09:42,500 --> 00:09:44,280
熱水
Hot water?

137
00:09:44,310 --> 00:09:47,050
千真萬確
That's what the man said.

138
00:10:56,910 --> 00:10:58,750
安德莉亞
Andrea?

139
00:11:06,160 --> 00:11:07,430
來
That's it.

140
00:11:07,790 --> 00:11:09,920
慢慢來　吐出來
That's it. Get it out.

141
00:11:11,590 --> 00:11:13,520
沒事了
There you go.

142
00:11:14,960 --> 00:11:17,700
老天
Oh... god.

143
00:11:28,340 --> 00:11:30,580
一切都沒了
Everything's gone.

144
00:11:30,580 --> 00:11:33,070
喝下去總比吐出來好吧
It's always better going down than coming up, huh?

145
00:11:33,110 --> 00:11:35,310
我不是說酒　戴爾
I don't mean the wine, Dale.

146
00:11:35,880 --> 00:11:39,620
結束了　一切都沒了
You know, it's over. There's nothing left.

147
00:11:40,760 --> 00:11:42,290
你不覺得嗎
Don't you see that?

148
00:11:42,320 --> 00:11:45,120
我覺得
Oh, I-- I see a--

149
00:11:45,150 --> 00:11:48,130
這倒是個重新開始的機會
A chance to make a new start.

150
00:11:49,630 --> 00:11:51,630
老天啊　戴爾
Oh my god, Dale.

151
00:11:52,000 --> 00:11:55,170
戴爾　你沒看到詹納的表情嗎
Dale, didn't you see the look on Jenner's face?

152
00:11:55,910 --> 00:11:58,400
相信我吧
Hear what I'm saying.

153
00:11:58,430 --> 00:12:01,200
一切都沒了
There's nothing left.

154
00:12:08,300 --> 00:12:10,080
血液檢驗怎麼樣了
How's the blood?

155
00:12:10,340 --> 00:12:12,290
一切正常
No surprises.

156
00:12:20,200 --> 00:12:22,190
我是來謝謝你的
I came to thank you.

157
00:12:25,010 --> 00:12:26,470
你謝過了
You did.

158
00:12:28,900 --> 00:12:31,040
你沒事吧
You all-- you all right?

159
00:12:31,660 --> 00:12:33,670
你不知道是什麼樣
You don't know what it's like.

160
00:12:35,510 --> 00:12:37,750
你不知道外面世界是什麼樣
You don't know what it's like out there.

161
00:12:38,210 --> 00:12:40,640
你以為你知道　其實不然
You may think you do, but you don't.

162
00:12:43,210 --> 00:12:45,280
我們在外面會死
We'd have died out there.

163
00:12:47,310 --> 00:12:49,820
這只是時間問題
It was only a matter of time.

164
00:12:49,850 --> 00:12:51,790
行屍太多了
There's too many of those things.

165
00:12:54,530 --> 00:12:56,930
我的兒子
My-- my boy...

166
00:12:59,460 --> 00:13:02,250
我的妻子　我從沒…
My-- my wife, I never--

167
00:13:04,730 --> 00:13:07,070
我從沒告訴過他們我真實的想法
I never told 'em what I really thought.

168
00:13:11,310 --> 00:13:13,310
甚至連一點暗示都沒　只是…
I never even hinted, just--

169
00:13:17,770 --> 00:13:19,680
只是悶在心裡
Just kept it in.

170
00:13:20,970 --> 00:13:24,320
悶在心裡　讓大家心懷希望
Kept it in and kept us moving, you know.

171
00:13:24,350 --> 00:13:26,650
悶在心裡　讓大家心懷…
Just kept it in. Kept us...

172
00:13:27,380 --> 00:13:29,290
不會有事
It'll all be okay.

173
00:13:32,360 --> 00:13:34,860
都會好的
It'll be okay.

174
00:13:47,640 --> 00:13:49,770
有什麼好書嗎
Any good books?

175
00:13:49,800 --> 00:13:52,750
夠我們看上好幾年了
Enough to keep us busy for years.

176
00:13:52,780 --> 00:13:54,780
好了　孩子們　該睡覺了
All right. Come on, kids, it's bedtime.

177
00:13:56,140 --> 00:13:58,590
寶貝兒　你們去睡前祈禱吧　我再看會書
Baby, go say your prayers. I'm gonna browse a bit.

178
00:13:58,620 --> 00:14:00,590
來吧
Come on.

179
00:14:00,620 --> 00:14:03,480
這是你們第一次能睡個好覺
This is the first night we might actually get some real sleep.

180
00:14:03,520 --> 00:14:05,630
真是奇跡　不是嗎
It's a miracle, isn't it?

181
00:14:29,640 --> 00:14:31,330
老天　你嚇死我了
Jesus, you scared me.

182
00:14:32,150 --> 00:14:33,670
我要跟你說些事
I'm gonna tell you a few things

183
00:14:33,700 --> 00:14:35,610
你給我好好聽著
And you're gonna listen to me.

184
00:14:35,640 --> 00:14:37,180
現在不行
Now is not the time.

185
00:14:37,730 --> 00:14:39,690
得了　那又該什麼時候說
Come on. When is it ever the time?

186
00:14:44,330 --> 00:14:45,860
你怎麼能這麼對我
How can you treat me like this?

187
00:14:45,900 --> 00:14:47,690
-你開玩笑吧　-不
- You're kidding, right? - No. Huh-uh.

188
00:14:47,720 --> 00:14:49,770
因為你告訴我　我丈夫死了
Because you told me my husband was dead.

189
00:14:49,800 --> 00:14:51,960
我沒有撒謊　好嗎　真的沒有
I didn't lie to you, all right? I didn't.

190
00:14:51,990 --> 00:14:54,330
你知道醫院裡的情況嗎
Do you know what it was like there?

191
00:14:55,400 --> 00:14:58,630
聽我說　一切都崩潰了
Stop. Things were falling apart.

192
00:14:58,660 --> 00:15:00,540
他們在過道裡殺人
They were slaughtering people in the hallways.

193
00:15:00,540 --> 00:15:03,460
就是場大屠殺　到處都有行屍
It was a massacre. There were walkers everywhere.

194
00:15:03,460 --> 00:15:05,560
-你就這麼扔下他了　-大家都跑了
- So you left him? - Everybody else ran.

195
00:15:05,560 --> 00:15:07,850
沒有醫生　只剩下我
There were no doctors there. It was just me.

196
00:15:07,850 --> 00:15:11,650
他身上連著儀器　我不知道該怎麼辦
He was hooked up to machines and I did not know what to do.

197
00:15:11,690 --> 00:15:14,280
我甚至貼著他的胸膛聽過
I even took my ear and I put it on his chest

198
00:15:14,310 --> 00:15:16,680
想聽聽有沒有心跳　結果沒有
And I listened for a heartbeat and I did not hear one.

199
00:15:16,730 --> 00:15:18,220
我也不知道為什麼
And I-I-I-I-- I don't know why.

200
00:15:18,250 --> 00:15:20,120
也許是此起彼伏的槍聲　我也不知道
Maybe it was gunfire. I don't know what it was,

201
00:15:20,150 --> 00:15:22,330
但他沒可能活下來　絕對沒可能
But there was no way he could've survived that. No way.

202
00:15:22,360 --> 00:15:25,690
-但他活下來了　-對　但我還得考慮你們
- He did. - Yeah, but then I had y'all to think about, didn't I?

203
00:15:25,740 --> 00:15:26,410
還有你和卡爾
I had you and Carl,

204
00:15:26,410 --> 00:15:27,830
-我得考慮你們的安危　-不
- and I needed to think about-- - okay. No no.

205
00:15:27,860 --> 00:15:29,370
我得把你們平安送到亞特蘭大
I had to get you guys safe to Atlanta.

206
00:15:29,400 --> 00:15:30,900
我必須這樣　別這樣
That's what I had to do. Just stop.

207
00:15:30,940 --> 00:15:32,500
你好好想想
If you thought for one second

208
00:15:32,540 --> 00:15:35,030
如果他還活著　你會離開嗎
that he was still alive, would you have come?

209
00:15:35,070 --> 00:15:37,000
這麼說我救了你
So I saved your life--

210
00:15:37,530 --> 00:15:39,550
你和你兒子　我救了你們
You and your little boy's. That's what I did.

211
00:15:39,580 --> 00:15:41,210
是吧
Right?

212
00:15:42,680 --> 00:15:43,780
好吧
Okay.

213
00:15:43,820 --> 00:15:47,080
如果要我和他交換　我也願意
And if I could've traded places with him, I would have.

214
00:15:48,280 --> 00:15:50,620
我現在就願意和他換
I would trade places with him right now because--

215
00:15:50,650 --> 00:15:52,960
不不不　你聽好
No no no, you--

216
00:15:52,960 --> 00:15:54,420
-我愛你　-不　你喝醉了
- I love you. Shh shh. - No. No, you're drunk.

217
00:15:54,460 --> 00:15:56,150
-我愛你　-你喝醉了
- I love you. - No, you're drunk.

218
00:15:56,200 --> 00:15:58,330
我知道你也愛我
And I know there were some things that say that you love me too.

219
00:15:58,360 --> 00:15:59,200
不然的話
Because there's no way that

220
00:15:59,200 --> 00:16:00,700
你不會對我這麼冷淡
you could've been with me the way that you were.

221
00:16:00,730 --> 00:16:02,830
肖恩　住手
Shane. Shane. Shane!

222
00:16:02,870 --> 00:16:03,920
聽著　你愛我
Listen. You love me.

223
00:16:03,920 --> 00:16:05,870
放開我　快放開我
Get your hands off me. Get your hands off me.

224
00:16:05,900 --> 00:16:07,870
-我愛你　這裡沒別人　-不要　快住手
- I love you. There's nobody here. - Please! No!

225
00:16:07,900 --> 00:16:10,230
別這樣　洛莉　沒關係的
Stop, Lori. It's all right. Just--

226
00:17:19,480 --> 00:17:22,210
我們不用再害怕了
We don't have to be afraid anymore.

227
00:17:25,010 --> 00:17:27,440
我們在這很安全
We're safe here.

228
00:17:28,090 --> 00:17:29,140
好嗎
All right?

229
00:17:44,020 --> 00:17:46,040
-早　-你宿醉了嗎
- Morning. - Are you hungover?

230
00:17:47,340 --> 00:17:51,060
-媽就說你會　-媽媽說得對
- Mom said you'd be. - Mom is right.

231
00:17:51,110 --> 00:17:53,770
媽媽總說得對
Mom has that annoying habit.

232
00:17:53,800 --> 00:17:58,380
糊狀的雞蛋　但還算美味
Eggs. Powdered, but-- but I do 'em good.

233
00:17:58,860 --> 00:18:00,300
我想你吃不出來
I bet you can't tell.

234
00:18:00,560 --> 00:18:05,050
蛋白質有助於治宿醉
Protein helps the hangover. -

235
00:18:05,120 --> 00:18:06,770
這都哪兒來的
Where'd all this come from?

236
00:18:06,800 --> 00:18:08,590
-詹納給的　-能幫我一下嗎
- Jenner. - could you help me, please?

237
00:18:08,630 --> 00:18:10,430
他覺得我們用得著
He thought we could use it.

238
00:18:10,470 --> 00:18:12,270
-謝了　-至少是少部分人
- Thank you. - Some of us, at least.

239
00:18:12,310 --> 00:18:15,170
再也不要讓我喝酒了
Don't ever ever ever let me drink again.

240
00:18:19,660 --> 00:18:21,340
感覺和我一樣糟糕嗎
Feel as bad as I do?

241
00:18:21,380 --> 00:18:23,140
比你更糟
Worse.

242
00:18:25,180 --> 00:18:27,770
你怎麼了
The hell happened to you?

243
00:18:27,810 --> 00:18:29,710
看你那脖子
Your neck?

244
00:18:29,740 --> 00:18:31,480
肯定是睡覺時弄到了
I must have done it in my sleep.

245
00:18:31,520 --> 00:18:33,150
以前睡覺可沒弄傷過啊
Never seen you do that before.

246
00:18:33,180 --> 00:18:35,120
我也不知道
Me neither.

247
00:18:35,520 --> 00:18:37,480
我不再是以前的我了
Not like me at all.

248
00:18:42,030 --> 00:18:44,950
-各位早　-博士早
- Morning.　- Hey, doc.

249
00:18:45,410 --> 00:18:48,790
博士　我不想一大早上來就問你問題
Doctor, I don't mean to slam you with questions first thing--

250
00:18:48,830 --> 00:18:50,700
但你還是會問
But you will anyway.

251
00:18:50,730 --> 00:18:52,820
我們可不是來蹭飯的
We didn't come here for the eggs.

252
00:19:02,860 --> 00:19:04,840
回放19號試驗
Give me playback of TS-19.

253
00:19:04,880 --> 00:19:06,960
回放19號試驗
Playback of TS-19.

254
00:19:09,290 --> 00:19:12,160
很少人看過這些資料
Few people ever got a chance to see this.

255
00:19:12,190 --> 00:19:14,130
沒幾個
Very few.

256
00:19:19,860 --> 00:19:23,660
-那是大腦嗎　-一個傑出的大腦
- Is that a brain?　- An extraordinary one.

257
00:19:25,370 --> 00:19:27,620
拋開結果不說的話
Not that it matters in the end.

258
00:19:27,620 --> 00:19:29,280
展示內部放大視圖
Take us in for E.I.V..

259
00:19:29,310 --> 00:19:31,800
內部放大視圖
Enhanced internal view.

260
00:19:48,560 --> 00:19:49,850
那些亮斑是什麼
What are those lights?

261
00:19:51,600 --> 00:19:53,760
那是一個人的生命
It's a person's life--

262
00:19:53,790 --> 00:19:55,260
經歷　還有記憶
experiences, memories.

263
00:19:55,260 --> 00:19:57,360
一切都在這裡
It's everything.

264
00:19:57,390 --> 00:20:00,000
所有的這些組織網絡
Somewhere in all that organic wiring,

265
00:20:00,030 --> 00:20:02,460
所有的這些亮斑
All those ripples of light,

266
00:20:03,180 --> 00:20:04,550
造就了你
is you--

267
00:20:05,000 --> 00:20:07,350
讓你變得獨一無二
The thing that makes you unique.

268
00:20:07,850 --> 00:20:09,710
變得有人性
And human.

269
00:20:10,200 --> 00:20:12,080
我還是聽不懂
You don't make sense ever?

270
00:20:12,110 --> 00:20:13,610
那些是神經突觸
Those are synapses,

271
00:20:13,650 --> 00:20:15,420
大腦中的電子脈衝
electric impulses in the brain

272
00:20:15,450 --> 00:20:17,420
運載著一切信息
that carry all the messages.

273
00:20:17,840 --> 00:20:20,220
從你剛出生開始　它就控制著
They determine everything a person says

274
00:20:20,250 --> 00:20:23,260
你的所說所做和所想
does or thinks from the moment of birth

275
00:20:24,000 --> 00:20:25,230
直到你死亡
to the moment of death.

276
00:20:25,260 --> 00:20:28,490
直到死亡　這是監測圖像嗎
Death? That's what this is, a vigil?

277
00:20:28,880 --> 00:20:30,190
沒錯
Yes.

278
00:20:31,330 --> 00:20:35,290
準確說是監測圖像的回放
Or rather the playback of the vigil.

279
00:20:36,430 --> 00:20:38,370
這人死了嗎
This person died?

280
00:20:40,120 --> 00:20:41,250
他是什麼人
Who?

281
00:20:42,060 --> 00:20:43,810
19號試驗品
Test subject 19.

282
00:20:44,940 --> 00:20:49,650
一個被咬　感染上病毒
Someone who was bitten and infected...

283
00:20:50,690 --> 00:20:55,180
還自願讓我們記錄下轉變過程的人
and volunteered to have us record the process.

284
00:20:57,980 --> 00:21:00,490
維　瀏覽項目一
Vi, scan forward to the first event.

285
00:21:00,530 --> 00:21:03,850
瀏覽項目一
Scanning to first event.

286
00:21:10,140 --> 00:21:11,740
那是怎麼回事
What is that?

287
00:21:13,470 --> 00:21:16,110
它就像腦膜炎一樣感染大腦
It invades the brain like meningitis.

288
00:21:17,920 --> 00:21:20,080
導致腎上腺出血
The adrenal glands hemorrhage,

289
00:21:20,120 --> 00:21:21,980
大腦停止運作
the brian goes into shutdown,

290
00:21:22,010 --> 00:21:23,980
然後到主要器官
then the major organs.

291
00:21:28,410 --> 00:21:29,640
最後死亡
Then death.

292
00:21:31,380 --> 00:21:34,080
你的過去與未來
Everything you ever were or ever will be...

293
00:21:35,890 --> 00:21:38,340
都消逝了
Gone.

294
00:21:38,370 --> 00:21:40,640
吉姆也會這樣嗎
Is that what happened to Jim?

295
00:21:41,150 --> 00:21:42,530
沒錯
Yes.

296
00:21:51,470 --> 00:21:53,710
兩天前她失去了一個親人
She lost somebody two days ago.

297
00:21:53,710 --> 00:21:55,120
她妹妹
Her sister.

298
00:21:56,750 --> 00:21:57,970
我也失去了親人
I lost somebody too.

299
00:21:57,970 --> 00:22:00,650
我知道這有多難受
I know how devastating it is.

300
00:22:06,200 --> 00:22:07,820
瀏覽項目二
Scan to the second event.

301
00:22:08,180 --> 00:22:09,970
瀏覽項目二
Scanning to second event.

302
00:22:11,900 --> 00:22:14,030
變異時間有長有短
The resurrection times vary wildly.

303
00:22:14,070 --> 00:22:18,060
報告說　短的有三分鐘
We had reports of it happening in as little as three minutes.

304
00:22:18,530 --> 00:22:21,010
最長有八小時
The longest we heard of was eight hours.

305
00:22:21,010 --> 00:22:22,270
至於這個病人
In the case of this patient,

306
00:22:22,270 --> 00:22:26,300
是兩小時一分
it was two hours, one minute...

307
00:22:27,020 --> 00:22:29,110
零七秒
Seven seconds.

308
00:22:39,320 --> 00:22:42,980
-它讓大腦重新運作嗎　-不　只是腦幹
- It restarts the brain?　- No, just the brain stem.

309
00:22:43,950 --> 00:22:46,530
原理上說　是讓行屍起來走動
Basically, it gets them up and moving.

310
00:22:46,530 --> 00:22:48,120
但他們不是活的嗎
But they're not alive?

311
00:22:50,310 --> 00:22:51,590
你說說
You tell me.

312
00:22:53,180 --> 00:22:54,970
和以前不同了
It's nothing like before.

313
00:22:55,000 --> 00:22:57,310
大腦大部分都是黑暗的
Most of that brain is dark.

314
00:22:57,340 --> 00:23:00,140
黑暗　毫無生機　說明死了
Dark, lifeless, dead.

315
00:23:00,170 --> 00:23:01,770
大腦額葉　腦皮層
The frontal lobe, the neocortex,

316
00:23:01,800 --> 00:23:03,140
屬於人的那部分　沒活過來
The human part-- that doesn't come back.

317
00:23:03,180 --> 00:23:05,000
讓你活著的那部分
The you part.

318
00:23:06,010 --> 00:23:10,480
只是一具沒有思想　只由本能控制的軀殼
Just a shell driven by mindless instinct.

319
00:23:13,180 --> 00:23:15,660
我的天啊　怎麼了
God. What was that?

320
00:23:17,200 --> 00:23:19,080
他朝那病人的頭射了一槍
He shot his patient in the head.

321
00:23:22,420 --> 00:23:23,320
是吧
Didn't you?

322
00:23:24,180 --> 00:23:26,890
維　關閉主屏和工作台
Vi, power down the main screen and the workstations.

323
00:23:26,940 --> 00:23:30,110
關閉主屏和工作台
Powering down main screen and workstations.

324
00:23:32,590 --> 00:23:34,940
你也弄不清那是什麼吧
You have no idea what it is, do you?

325
00:23:37,710 --> 00:23:42,730
可能是細菌　病毒　寄生菌　或真菌
It could be microbial, viral, parasitic, fungal.

326
00:23:42,730 --> 00:23:44,470
抑或是上帝的懲罰
Or the wrath of god?

327
00:23:44,890 --> 00:23:46,580
可能吧
There is that.

328
00:23:47,980 --> 00:23:49,940
一定有人知道些什麼
Somebody must know something.

329
00:23:49,980 --> 00:23:51,690
在某處的什麼人
Somebody somewhere.

330
00:23:51,720 --> 00:23:54,950
還有其他人　對吧　其他機構
There are others, right? Other facilities?

331
00:23:56,830 --> 00:23:58,360
可能有吧
There may be some.

332
00:23:59,920 --> 00:24:00,600
像我這樣的人
People like me.

333
00:24:00,600 --> 00:24:02,860
但你不知道　你怎麼可能什麼都不知道
But you don't know? How can you not know?

334
00:24:02,860 --> 00:24:04,360
什麼都沒了
Everything went down.

335
00:24:04,390 --> 00:24:06,440
通訊　上級指示　都沒了
Communications, directives-- all of it.

336
00:24:06,470 --> 00:24:09,470
我已經活在黑暗中快一個月了
I've been in the dark for almost a month.

337
00:24:09,500 --> 00:24:11,580
那麼說　不光是這裡
So it's not just here.

338
00:24:12,060 --> 00:24:15,380
不管在哪都是一無所有了
There's nothing left anywhere? Nothing?

339
00:24:15,840 --> 00:24:17,950
你其實是這個意思吧
That's what you're really saying, right?

340
00:24:27,730 --> 00:24:29,790
天啊
Jesus.

341
00:24:29,820 --> 00:24:32,000
哥們　我又想去大醉一場了
Man, I'm gonna get soon faced drunk again.

342
00:24:32,030 --> 00:24:34,830
詹納博士　我知道你已經很難做了
Dr. Jenner, I know this has been taxing for you

343
00:24:34,870 --> 00:24:38,030
我不想再問問題了　但是
And I hate to ask one more question, but...

344
00:24:39,240 --> 00:24:41,010
那個鐘
That clock--

345
00:24:41,860 --> 00:24:43,040
正在倒計時
It's counting down.

346
00:24:45,420 --> 00:24:47,090
數到零時會發生什麼
What happens at zero?

347
00:24:49,580 --> 00:24:54,010
地下室的發電機沒燃料了
The basement generators-- they run out of fuel.

348
00:24:56,010 --> 00:24:57,850
然後呢
And then?

349
00:25:00,860 --> 00:25:03,420
維　電力耗盡會發生什麼事
Vi, what happens when the power runs out?

350
00:25:04,070 --> 00:25:05,690
電力耗盡後
When the power runs out,

351
00:25:05,730 --> 00:25:09,540
將會進行全面消毒
facility-wide decontamination will occur.

352
00:25:13,950 --> 00:25:16,350
消毒　那意味著什麼
Decontamination-- what does that mean?

353
00:25:16,380 --> 00:25:18,500
我不太喜歡詹納他拒不開口
I don't like the way Jenner clammed up.

354
00:25:18,530 --> 00:25:20,800
他就那麼走開了
The way he just wandered off like that.

355
00:25:20,830 --> 00:25:23,530
他怎麼了　說真的　夥計
What's wrong with him? Seriously, man,

356
00:25:23,570 --> 00:25:25,170
他傻了　嗑藥了　還是怎麼了
Is he nuts, medicated, what?

357
00:25:26,750 --> 00:25:28,670
那邊
In there.

358
00:25:37,810 --> 00:25:39,580
去那邊看看
Check that way.

359
00:25:40,020 --> 00:25:41,150
肖恩
Shane.

360
00:26:06,640 --> 00:26:08,270
空的
It's empty.

361
00:26:10,980 --> 00:26:13,980
-開啟應急照明　-這怎麼回事
- Emergency lighting on. - What the hell is this?

362
00:26:17,310 --> 00:26:19,340
喂　你們關了燈嗎
Hey, you guys kill the lights?

363
00:26:19,390 --> 00:26:21,520
-不　它自己滅了　-有什麼發現嗎
- Nah, it just went ou. - Anything?

364
00:26:22,130 --> 00:26:25,150
有　一堆停止運轉的發電機
Yeah, a lot of dead generators

365
00:26:25,180 --> 00:26:27,630
和數不清的空燃料桶
and more empty fuel drums than I can count.

366
00:26:29,860 --> 00:26:31,970
肯定不會只剩這一個
It can't be down to just that one.

367
00:26:40,110 --> 00:26:43,770
媽媽　出什麼事了嗎
Mom? Something wrong?

368
00:26:45,240 --> 00:26:47,100
沒事　只不過
Nothing. It's just...

369
00:26:48,320 --> 00:26:50,280
空調停了
the air conditioning stopped.

370
00:27:08,060 --> 00:27:10,700
時間有限　但我已經盡最大努力了
I did the best I could in the time that I had.

371
00:27:13,470 --> 00:27:15,300
我希望你能以此為傲
I hope you'd be proud of that.

372
00:27:36,040 --> 00:27:38,390
我們總以為還有很長路要走
We always think there's gonna be more time...

373
00:27:44,240 --> 00:27:46,020
卻不知不覺已到盡頭
...then it runs out.

374
00:27:48,360 --> 00:27:49,370
空調怎麼停了
Why is the air off?

375
00:27:49,400 --> 00:27:51,900
-還有房間裡的燈也滅了　-怎麼回事
- and the lights in our room? - What's going on?

376
00:27:51,930 --> 00:27:53,500
為什麼所有電器都停了
Why is everything turned off?

377
00:27:53,530 --> 00:27:55,310
正在優先化能源耗用
Energy use is being prioritized.

378
00:27:55,340 --> 00:27:57,740
空調不是最重要的嗎　還有燈呢
Air isn't a priority? And lights?

379
00:27:57,770 --> 00:28:00,970
這不是我決定的　第五區在自行關閉
It's not up to me. Zone 5 is shutting itself down.

380
00:28:01,020 --> 00:28:03,180
喂　喂　這話是什麼意思
Hey! Hey, what the hell does that mean?

381
00:28:04,270 --> 00:28:05,690
兄弟　我問你話呢
Hey man, I'm talking to you.

382
00:28:06,290 --> 00:28:08,350
什麼叫自行關閉
What do you mean it's shutting itself down?

383
00:28:08,380 --> 00:28:10,120
一所建築怎麼有這能耐
How can a building do anything?

384
00:28:10,160 --> 00:28:11,660
-你不知道的事還多著呢　-瑞克
- You'd be surprised. - Rick?

385
00:28:16,640 --> 00:28:18,460
詹納　怎麼回事
Jenner, what's happening?

386
00:28:18,490 --> 00:28:21,800
系統正在終止一切非必需設備
The system is dropping all the nonessential uses of power.

387
00:28:22,300 --> 00:28:23,230
為了儘可能保證
It's designed to keep the

388
00:28:23,230 --> 00:28:25,310
電腦運行時間　直到最後一刻
computers running to the last possible second.

389
00:28:25,340 --> 00:28:27,610
當剩餘時間接近半小時　程序就會啟動
That started as we approached the half-hour mark.

390
00:28:27,830 --> 00:28:29,470
計劃之中
Right on schedule.

391
00:28:40,680 --> 00:28:43,660
-法國人　-什麼
- It was the French. - what?

392
00:28:43,690 --> 00:28:45,990
據我所知　他們堅持到了最後
They were the last ones to hold out as far as I know.

393
00:28:45,990 --> 00:28:47,550
當我們的人或奪門而去
While our people were bolting out the doors

394
00:28:47,550 --> 00:28:49,130
或在過道裡自殺時
and committing suicide in the hallways,

395
00:28:49,130 --> 00:28:51,250
他們一直留守在實驗室裡
they stayed in the labs till the end.

396
00:28:51,660 --> 00:28:54,290
他們自認為快要找出解決之道了
They thought they were close to a solution.

397
00:28:54,330 --> 00:28:56,200
然後呢
What happened?

398
00:28:56,230 --> 00:28:58,330
跟這裡情況一樣
The same thing that's happening here.

399
00:28:59,370 --> 00:29:00,840
電力耗盡
No power grid.

400
00:29:01,580 --> 00:29:03,180
彈盡糧絕
Ran out of juice.

401
00:29:04,600 --> 00:29:07,550
整個世界的運轉都依賴於礦物燃料
The world runs on fossil fuel.

402
00:29:07,580 --> 00:29:09,580
真是荒天下之大謬
I mean, how stupid is that?

403
00:29:10,030 --> 00:29:12,530
-我告訴你　-見鬼去吧　肖恩　我才不在乎
- Let me tell you-- - To hell with it, Shane. I don't even care.

404
00:29:12,560 --> 00:29:15,060
洛莉　去收拾東西　大家都收拾下東西
Lori, grab our things. Everybody, get your stuff.

405
00:29:15,090 --> 00:29:17,150
我們現在就走
We're getting out of here now!

406
00:29:17,190 --> 00:29:18,930
好
Oh, okay.

407
00:29:19,880 --> 00:29:20,740
什麼聲音
What's that?

408
00:29:23,510 --> 00:29:24,860
怎麼了
What's that?

409
00:29:25,400 --> 00:29:27,840
距消毒程序啟動還有三十分鐘
30 minutes to decontamination.

410
00:29:31,530 --> 00:29:33,310
博士　這是怎麼回事
Doc, what's going on here?

411
00:29:33,340 --> 00:29:35,040
你們大家都聽見瑞克說的了
Everybody, y'all heard Rick.

412
00:29:35,070 --> 00:29:36,780
收拾東西　咱們馬上離開　快
Get your stuff and let's go! Go now! Go!

413
00:29:36,820 --> 00:29:38,210
-我們走　-快點
- Let's go. - Come on!

414
00:29:41,730 --> 00:29:42,830
不
No.

415
00:29:44,200 --> 00:29:45,710
你是把我們鎖在裡面了嗎
Did you just lock us in?

416
00:29:46,260 --> 00:29:47,790
他把我們鎖在裡面了
He just locked us in!

417
00:29:48,450 --> 00:29:50,530
三十分鐘時限開始　我在記錄中
We've hit the 30-minute window. I am recording.

418
00:29:51,730 --> 00:29:54,220
-卡爾　-媽媽
- Carl. - Mom!

419
00:29:54,250 --> 00:29:55,990
-你個狗娘養的　-肖恩
- You son of a bitch. - Shane!

420
00:29:56,030 --> 00:29:57,990
-你快放我們出去　-不　停手　不要
- You let us out of here! - No, stop. Don't!

421
00:29:58,030 --> 00:30:00,830
-滿口胡言的　-不　不不
- You lying-- - No no no no!

422
00:30:00,860 --> 00:30:02,670
等等　別這樣
Wait, no! No, don't do it.

423
00:30:05,340 --> 00:30:07,740
詹納　立刻開門
Hey, Jenner, open that door now.

424
00:30:07,770 --> 00:30:10,170
沒用的　上面的出口全都關閉了
There's no point. Everything topside is locked down.

425
00:30:10,210 --> 00:30:11,680
緊急通道也封鎖了
The emergency exits are sealed.

426
00:30:11,710 --> 00:30:13,180
那他媽的就打開啊
Well, open the damn things.

427
00:30:13,210 --> 00:30:15,400
我無法控制　是電腦操控的
That's not something I control. The computers do.

428
00:30:15,450 --> 00:30:18,440
我告訴過你們　前門一旦關閉
I told you once that front door closed,

429
00:30:18,480 --> 00:30:20,620
就再也無法開啟了　你們當時都聽見了
it wouldn't open again. You heard me say that.

430
00:30:23,390 --> 00:30:25,550
-這樣更好一點　-怎樣
- It's better this way. - What is?

431
00:30:25,580 --> 00:30:27,960
28分鐘以後會怎樣
What happens in 28 minutes?

432
00:30:31,690 --> 00:30:33,100
-28分鐘以後會怎樣　-夠了
- What happens in 28 minutes??! - COME ON!

433
00:30:33,130 --> 00:30:35,630
你知道這是什麼地方嗎
You know what this place is?!

434
00:30:36,260 --> 00:30:38,140
這裡面存放的東西
We protected the public

435
00:30:38,180 --> 00:30:40,940
危害性相當強大
from very nasty stuff!

436
00:30:42,740 --> 00:30:45,130
生化武器　天花病毒
Weaponized smallpox!

437
00:30:45,180 --> 00:30:48,390
能奪去半數國民生命的埃博拉菌株
Ebola strains that could wipe out half the country!

438
00:30:48,420 --> 00:30:51,580
那可是你們死都不想洩露出去的東西
Stuff you don't want getting out! Ever!

439
00:31:04,430 --> 00:31:07,160
發生災難性電力故障時
In the event of a catastrophic power failure--

440
00:31:07,200 --> 00:31:09,800
比如在恐怖襲擊中
in a terrorist attack, for example--

441
00:31:09,840 --> 00:31:13,230
系統會啟動HIT　以禁止任何有機體離開
H.I.T.s are deployed to prevent any organisms from getting out.

442
00:31:13,260 --> 00:31:15,400
HIT
H.I.T.s?

443
00:31:17,070 --> 00:31:19,050
-維　解釋下　-HIT
- Vi, define. - HITs--

444
00:31:19,050 --> 00:31:21,930
指強脈衝溫壓油氣炸彈
high-impulse thermobaric fuel-air explosives

445
00:31:21,930 --> 00:31:24,910
包含兩階段氣溶膠點火裝置
cocoists of a two-stage aerosol ignition

446
00:31:24,940 --> 00:31:28,220
使其產生的衝擊波　破壞力與持久性
that produces a blast wave of significantly greater power

447
00:31:28,250 --> 00:31:31,640
均優於所有已知炸藥　僅次於核武器
and duration than any other known explosive except nuclear.

448
00:31:31,640 --> 00:31:34,440
在真空壓力下　於五千度至六千度間
The vacuum-pressure effect ignites the oxygen

449
00:31:34,440 --> 00:31:37,190
點燃氧氣　
between 5,000 and 6,000 degrees

450
00:31:37,190 --> 00:31:39,750
可導致極其慘重的人員傷亡
and is used when the greatest loss of life

451
00:31:39,750 --> 00:31:42,370
和財產損失
and damage to structures is desired.

452
00:31:42,890 --> 00:31:44,530
它會點燃空氣
It sets the air on fire.

453
00:31:48,400 --> 00:31:50,070
毫無痛苦
No pain.

454
00:31:51,610 --> 00:31:54,200
再無憂傷　悲痛
An end to sorrow, grief...

455
00:31:56,200 --> 00:31:57,770
懊悔
regret.

456
00:32:06,770 --> 00:32:07,980
一切到此為止
Everything.

457
00:32:15,230 --> 00:32:17,830
他媽的把門打開
Open the damn door!

458
00:32:18,810 --> 00:32:20,780
讓開
Out of my way!

459
00:32:21,610 --> 00:32:22,280
達裡爾
Daryl!

460
00:32:31,120 --> 00:32:32,630
順其自然吧
You should've left well enough alone.

461
00:32:32,630 --> 00:32:35,610
-會好過許多　-誰會好過
- it would've been so much easier. - Easier for who?

462
00:32:35,610 --> 00:32:38,120
所有人都會　你們清楚外面的情況
All of you. You know what's out there--

463
00:32:38,120 --> 00:32:41,350
生不能安寢　死不得安息
A short, brutal life and an agonizing death.

464
00:32:42,030 --> 00:32:45,890
你妹妹　叫什麼來著
Your-- your sister-- what was her name?

465
00:32:45,890 --> 00:32:47,930
-艾米　-艾米
- Amy. - Amy.

466
00:32:47,930 --> 00:32:50,160
你明白最終會是怎樣的下場
You know what this does.

467
00:32:50,190 --> 00:32:51,450
親眼所見
You've seen it.

468
00:32:51,480 --> 00:32:53,510
你想讓妻子和兒子落得那種下場嗎
Is that really what you want for your wife and son?

469
00:32:53,510 --> 00:32:56,090
我可不想這樣
I don't want this.

470
00:32:57,270 --> 00:32:58,340
毫無進展
Can't make a dent.

471
00:32:58,340 --> 00:33:01,070
那些門都能經受火箭襲擊
Those doors are designed to withstand a rocket launcher.

472
00:33:01,100 --> 00:33:03,130
但你的腦袋可受不了
Well, your head ain't!

473
00:33:03,160 --> 00:33:05,070
達裡爾　達裡爾
Daryl! Daryl!

474
00:33:05,100 --> 00:33:08,880
後退　住手
Just back up! Back up!

475
00:33:08,910 --> 00:33:10,920
你確實希望如此
You do want this.

476
00:33:10,920 --> 00:33:12,660
昨天晚上你說過
Last night you said

477
00:33:12,660 --> 00:33:13,860
你知道你心愛的人遲早會死
you knew it was just a matter of time

478
00:33:13,860 --> 00:33:16,280
不過是時間問題
before everybody you loved was dead.

479
00:33:16,310 --> 00:33:18,440
什麼
What?

480
00:33:20,490 --> 00:33:22,460
什麼　你真這麼說嗎
What? You really said that?

481
00:33:22,490 --> 00:33:24,090
那你之前說的大話算什麼
After all your big talk?

482
00:33:24,120 --> 00:33:25,820
我必須時刻保持希望
I had to keep hope alive, didn't I?

483
00:33:25,850 --> 00:33:27,590
沒有希望了
There is no hope.

484
00:33:27,620 --> 00:33:29,450
-從來就沒有希望　-希望總是存在
- there never was. - There's always hope.

485
00:33:29,450 --> 00:33:31,110
也許不是你　也許不在這
Maybe it won't be you, maybe not here,

486
00:33:31,110 --> 00:33:33,260
但在其他地方總會有人…
But somebody somewhere--

487
00:33:33,290 --> 00:33:35,960
所有的一切都完了　你還不明白嗎
What part of "Everything is gone" Do you not understand?

488
00:33:36,360 --> 00:33:38,360
聽你朋友的吧　她明白這道理
Listen to your friend. She gets it.

489
00:33:38,790 --> 00:33:41,040
這次我們經歷的浩劫
This is what takes us down.

490
00:33:41,690 --> 00:33:45,340
是滅絕之災
This is our extinction event.

491
00:33:49,680 --> 00:33:51,520
這樣不對
This isn't right.

492
00:33:51,550 --> 00:33:54,010
你不能把我們關在這
You can't just keep us here.

493
00:33:54,550 --> 00:33:56,820
就那麼一瞬間
One tiny moment--

494
00:33:56,860 --> 00:33:58,820
千分之一秒　毫無痛苦
A millisecond. No pain.

495
00:33:58,860 --> 00:34:02,390
我女兒不該這樣死去
My daughter doesn't deserve to die like this.

496
00:34:05,430 --> 00:34:07,990
這難道還不夠仁慈
Wouldn't it be kinder,

497
00:34:08,030 --> 00:34:11,000
不夠憐憫嗎　抱著你所愛的人
more compassionate to just hold your loved ones

498
00:34:11,000 --> 00:34:13,040
慢慢等待生命的終結
and wait for the clock to run down?

499
00:34:14,810 --> 00:34:16,510
-肖恩　住手　-閃開　瑞克
- Shane, no! - Out of the way, Rick!

500
00:34:16,540 --> 00:34:19,010
你給我閃開　快開門
Stay out of my way! Open that door

501
00:34:19,040 --> 00:34:20,820
不然我讓你腦袋開花　聽到了嗎
or I'm gonna blow your head off. Do you hear me?!

502
00:34:20,850 --> 00:34:23,920
哥們　你不能做這種事
Brother, brother, this is not the way you do this.

503
00:34:23,950 --> 00:34:26,420
-這樣我們出不去　-肖恩　你聽他一句
- We will never get out of here. - Shane, you listen to him.

504
00:34:26,450 --> 00:34:29,760
-太遲了　-要是他死了
- It's too late. - He dies, we all--

505
00:34:29,790 --> 00:34:31,890
我們都死定了　肖恩
we all die! Shane!

506
00:34:37,050 --> 00:34:39,370
肖恩
Shane!

507
00:34:48,270 --> 00:34:51,240
你夠了嗎　你鬧完了嗎
Are you done now? Are you done?

508
00:34:51,280 --> 00:34:53,280
是的　我想我們都完了
Yeah, I guess we all are.

509
00:35:15,410 --> 00:35:17,440
我覺得你在撒謊
I think you're lying.

510
00:35:19,370 --> 00:35:22,110
-什麼　-你在撒謊
- What? - You're lying.

511
00:35:22,140 --> 00:35:24,810
你說毫無希望
About no hope.

512
00:35:24,840 --> 00:35:27,340
如果真是這樣　你早和大家一起跑了
If that were true, you'd have bolted with the rest

513
00:35:27,370 --> 00:35:30,250
或者死了一了百了　但你沒有
or taken the easy way out. You didn't.

514
00:35:31,940 --> 00:35:34,010
你卻做了更艱難的選擇
You chose the hard path.

515
00:35:34,040 --> 00:35:35,920
-為什麼　-無所謂了
- Why? - It doesn't matter.

516
00:35:35,950 --> 00:35:38,660
有所謂　不可能無所謂
It does matter. It always matters.

517
00:35:38,690 --> 00:35:41,110
別人逃走你卻選擇留下來
You stayed when others ran.

518
00:35:41,110 --> 00:35:44,930
-到底為什麼　-不是我想留下
- Why? - Not because I wanted to.

519
00:35:44,960 --> 00:35:47,110
我做過承諾
I made a promise...

520
00:35:48,800 --> 00:35:50,460
對她
To her.

521
00:35:51,310 --> 00:35:52,700
我的妻子
My wife.

522
00:35:55,440 --> 00:35:58,480
19號試驗品是你妻子
Test subject 19 was your wife?

523
00:35:58,510 --> 00:36:01,710
她求我盡全力繼續研究
She begged me to keep going as long as I could.

524
00:36:02,720 --> 00:36:05,150
我怎麼拒絕得了
How could I say no? -

525
00:36:05,650 --> 00:36:07,860
她就快死了
She was dying.

526
00:36:08,460 --> 00:36:10,260
死的應該是我
It should've been me on that table.

527
00:36:10,290 --> 00:36:11,290
我根本毫無價值
I wouldn't have mattered to anybody.

528
00:36:11,290 --> 00:36:15,060
而她的死卻是全世界的損失
She was a loss to the world.

529
00:36:15,090 --> 00:36:17,930
見鬼　她是這兒的領導　而我只是下屬
Hell, she ran this place. I just worked here.

530
00:36:17,970 --> 00:36:20,400
她就是這個領域的奇才
In our field, she was an Einstein.

531
00:36:21,700 --> 00:36:25,070
我呢　我不過是個無名小卒
Me? I'm just... Edwin Jenner.

532
00:36:25,100 --> 00:36:28,140
她本可以有所作為
She could've done something about this.

533
00:36:28,430 --> 00:36:30,410
而我不行
Not me.

534
00:36:30,450 --> 00:36:33,180
你妻子沒有選擇
Your wife didn't have a choice.

535
00:36:33,220 --> 00:36:37,450
而你卻有　我們想要的
You do. That's-- that's all we want--

536
00:36:38,480 --> 00:36:41,420
只是一個選擇　去賭一把
A choice, a chance.

537
00:36:43,090 --> 00:36:45,950
讓我們盡全力去嘗試一下
Let us keep trying as long as we can.

538
00:36:53,390 --> 00:36:56,300
我說了外門已封鎖　我開不了
I told you topside's locked down. I can't open those.

539
00:37:08,840 --> 00:37:10,140
快來
Come on!

540
00:37:12,140 --> 00:37:14,110
-快走　-快點　快走
- Let's go! - Come on, let's go!

541
00:37:14,140 --> 00:37:17,250
-快點　-快走
- Come on! - Move it! Move it!

542
00:37:17,280 --> 00:37:19,890
-快點走　-我們離開這兒　索菲亞
- Come on, let's go! - We're gonna get out of here, Sophia.

543
00:37:19,920 --> 00:37:21,630
這是你的機會　去吧
There's your chance. Take it.

544
00:37:21,660 --> 00:37:24,030
我很感謝
I'm grateful.

545
00:37:24,060 --> 00:37:26,330
-你總有一天會改變主意　-快點
- The day will come when you won't be. - Let's go!

546
00:37:39,680 --> 00:37:43,400
我們只剩4分鐘了　快走
Hey, we've got four minutes left! Come on!

547
00:37:43,440 --> 00:37:46,140
-快走　-不　我要留下
- Let's go. Let's go. - No no, I'm staying.

548
00:37:46,170 --> 00:37:48,110
我要留下　親愛的
I'm staying, sweetie.

549
00:37:48,140 --> 00:37:50,680
-你這是瘋了　-不　我很理智
- But that's insane! - no, it's completely sane.

550
00:37:50,720 --> 00:37:52,310
這麼久以來從沒這麼理智過
For the first time in a long time.

551
00:37:53,120 --> 00:37:55,480
我不想變成吉姆和艾米那樣
I'm not ending up like Jim and Amy.

552
00:37:58,680 --> 00:37:59,960
沒時間爭論了
There's no time to argue

553
00:37:59,990 --> 00:38:02,790
也沒有意義　你們快出去
and no point, not if you want to get out.

554
00:38:02,820 --> 00:38:04,850
出去吧　快走
Just get out. Get out.

555
00:38:05,860 --> 00:38:08,360
T仔　快走　夥計
Dog. Come on, man.

556
00:38:08,390 --> 00:38:10,070
快點　快走了
Come on! Let's go! Let's go!

557
00:38:17,600 --> 00:38:19,700
我也要留下
I'm staying too.

558
00:38:20,750 --> 00:38:22,610
不　安德莉亞
Andrea, no.

559
00:38:25,320 --> 00:38:27,690
-你們先走　-快點
- Just go! Go! - Come on.

560
00:38:36,660 --> 00:38:38,420
安德莉亞
Andrea,

561
00:38:38,460 --> 00:38:41,530
艾米不希望你這樣
This isn't what Amy would want for you.

562
00:38:41,560 --> 00:38:44,700
她死了　你得快走
She's dead, and you need to leave.

563
00:38:51,210 --> 00:38:53,800
-快把門打開　-拜託
- Get them doors open! - Come on!

564
00:38:53,850 --> 00:38:57,150
-不行　-等一下
- It doesn't work! - Wait a minute! Wait a minute!

565
00:38:57,180 --> 00:38:59,910
快試試看
Try it! Try it! Try it now!

566
00:39:02,410 --> 00:39:05,150
-快開啊　-跟緊我　寶貝兒
- Come on! Come on! - Stay close, sweetheart.

567
00:39:09,530 --> 00:39:10,960
時間快到了
Time's almost up.

568
00:39:12,830 --> 00:39:15,290
達裡爾　小心
Daryl, look out!

569
00:39:22,530 --> 00:39:24,930
T仔　快下來
Dog, get down! Get down!

570
00:39:28,170 --> 00:39:30,010
-老天　-這玻璃打不碎嗎
- Jesus. - The glass won't break?

571
00:39:30,750 --> 00:39:33,480
瑞克　我這裡有東西可能有用
Rick, I have something that might help.

572
00:39:34,740 --> 00:39:36,650
卡蘿爾　指甲銼可派不上用處
Carol, I don't think a nail file's gonna do it.

573
00:39:36,680 --> 00:39:38,640
你剛到營地時
Your first morning at camp,

574
00:39:38,680 --> 00:39:42,120
我幫你洗制服時在口袋裡找到這個
when I washed your uniform I found this in your pocket.

575
00:39:45,460 --> 00:39:46,550
來吧
Come on.

576
00:39:46,580 --> 00:39:49,120
小心
Look out!

577
00:39:58,400 --> 00:40:00,000
-快趴下　-見鬼
- Get down! Get down! - Shit?

578
00:40:08,640 --> 00:40:10,340
好吧
Okay.

579
00:40:11,410 --> 00:40:13,210
你贏了
You win.

580
00:40:21,250 --> 00:40:24,350
-你在做什麼　-我說好吧
- What are you doing? - I said okay.

581
00:40:26,500 --> 00:40:29,760
-別開玩笑了　戴爾　-我沒開玩笑
- Don't pull this, Dale. - I'm not pulling anything.

582
00:40:29,790 --> 00:40:32,370
如果你留下　我也留下
If you're staying, I stay too.

583
00:40:32,400 --> 00:40:35,530
他說的沒錯　我們都知道出去會有什麼後果
He's right. We know what's waiting for us out there.

584
00:40:35,570 --> 00:40:37,630
我不想獨自去面對
I don't want to face it alone.

585
00:40:37,670 --> 00:40:40,610
戴爾　見鬼的　你快出去
Dale, get the hell out.

586
00:40:41,470 --> 00:40:43,010
我不想你留在這
I don't want you here.

587
00:40:43,040 --> 00:40:46,020
太糟糕了　你不能這樣
Too bad. See, you don't get to do that,

588
00:40:46,050 --> 00:40:48,060
走進某人的生活
to-- to come into somebody's life,

589
00:40:48,060 --> 00:40:50,850
讓他在乎你後又一走了之
make them care and then just check out.

590
00:40:56,630 --> 00:40:58,420
我要留下
I'm staying.

591
00:41:00,630 --> 00:41:02,360
這事就這麼定了
The matter is settled.

592
00:41:33,160 --> 00:41:34,790
等一下
Wait wait wait. Wait wait.

593
00:41:34,820 --> 00:41:36,320
他們來了
They're coming.

594
00:41:48,090 --> 00:41:49,900
他們出去了
They got out.

595
00:42:07,810 --> 00:42:09,720
快點
Come on.

596
00:42:09,760 --> 00:42:12,690
戴爾　臥倒　快臥倒
Dale, get down! Down!

597
00:42:12,720 --> 00:42:16,430
到裡面去　大家都臥倒
Get back! Everybody down! Down!

598
00:42:18,920 --> 00:42:20,240
臥倒
Get down!

599
00:43:15,760 --> 00:43:18,320
來吧　快來
Come on. Come on.

600
00:43:21,330 --> 00:43:23,140
快點　上車
Come on. Come on. Get in, get in, get in.

601
00:43:23,170 --> 00:43:24,890
快上車
Get in!

