1
00:00:18,030 --> 00:00:20,200
-怎麼了　-沒什麼
- What? - Nothing.

2
00:00:21,830 --> 00:00:24,400
別扯了　肯定有事
It's not nothing. It's always something.

3
00:00:25,960 --> 00:00:28,440
爸爸沒教過你怎麼打繩結嗎
Didn't dad teach you to tie nail knots?

4
00:00:28,580 --> 00:00:31,310
他幹嘛要這麼做　他只打過漁人結
Why would he do that? He only ever used a fisherman's knot.

5
00:00:35,820 --> 00:00:38,450
-就一個結　-不　沒有
- One knot. - No, he didn't.

6
00:00:38,480 --> 00:00:41,090
他至少打過三種結
No, he tied at least three.

7
00:00:41,120 --> 00:00:42,990
螺旋結嗎
Clinch knots?

8
00:00:43,500 --> 00:00:44,720
不可能
No way.

9
00:00:44,760 --> 00:00:46,860
好吧　算是我編的行了吧
Fine, I'm making it up.

10
00:00:58,200 --> 00:01:00,470
爸爸都教你用乾魚餌嗎
Did dad teach you mostly dry lures?

11
00:01:00,840 --> 00:01:02,710
是啊　你呢
Yeah. You?

12
00:01:02,740 --> 00:01:05,640
-濕的　-開玩笑吧
- Wet. - You're kidding.

13
00:01:06,610 --> 00:01:08,080
但他總是這麼固執
But he was always so adamant.

14
00:01:08,110 --> 00:01:10,180
你也知道爸爸對釣魚的態度
I mean, you know dad on the fishing thing.

15
00:01:10,220 --> 00:01:11,820
你覺得怎樣
Gee, you think?

16
00:01:11,850 --> 00:01:15,050
我整個童年都在船上度過
I only spent my entire childhood with my ass in a boat.

17
00:01:15,090 --> 00:01:18,290
但那個時候　都是端著魚鉤坐好
But in my day it was all about getting the hook seated.

18
00:01:18,320 --> 00:01:20,330
我們是為了吃而釣魚
We were fishing for the dinner table.

19
00:01:20,360 --> 00:01:22,930
我們不是　我們總把魚放回去
Not us. We always threw them back.

20
00:01:22,960 --> 00:01:25,100
-一直是這樣　-我想是他變了吧
- Always. - I guess he changed things up.

21
00:01:25,130 --> 00:01:28,400
但這感覺就像是讓他改變信仰之類
But that'd be like changing his religion or something.

22
00:01:28,430 --> 00:01:31,900
人是會變的　我們相差12歲　這又不能怪他
People change. It's not his fault we were born 12 years apart.

23
00:01:32,590 --> 00:01:34,340
的確
No.

24
00:01:34,370 --> 00:01:37,680
因為自從你上了大學
No, because the minute you went off to college

25
00:01:37,710 --> 00:01:38,740
就輪到我坐在船上
It was my ass in that

26
00:01:38,740 --> 00:01:40,950
由他來教我用乾魚餌釣魚了
boat and he taught me dry lures from day one.

27
00:01:42,450 --> 00:01:45,880
並不是時間改變的他
This was not behavior developed over time.

28
00:01:55,830 --> 00:01:57,530
你覺得他是為了我們嗎
You think he did it for us?

29
00:01:58,030 --> 00:02:00,070
因為他知道我們性格迥異
because he knew we were so different.

30
00:02:04,740 --> 00:02:08,340
他知道你想要釣上魚
He knew that you needed to catch the fish

31
00:02:08,370 --> 00:02:10,910
而我要把魚放回去
And I needed to throw them back.

32
00:02:14,330 --> 00:02:15,810
好吧　記住他教的規則
All right, remember his rule:

33
00:02:15,850 --> 00:02:17,330
在船上可不能哭
No crying in the boat.

34
00:02:19,050 --> 00:02:20,920
那會嚇跑了魚
It scares the fish.

35
00:02:22,730 --> 00:02:23,920
媽媽和爸爸
Mom and dad--

36
00:02:24,870 --> 00:02:26,560
我是說
I mean,

37
00:02:27,380 --> 00:02:29,930
也許弗羅裡達的情況沒這麼嚴重
Maybe Florida wasn't hit so bad.

38
00:02:30,250 --> 00:02:33,030
也許那裡比較好
Maybe it's better there.

39
00:02:33,070 --> 00:02:35,070
你覺得呢
Do you think?

40
00:02:41,000 --> 00:02:43,170
我覺得你有魚上鉤了
I think you have a bite.

41
00:02:43,880 --> 00:02:45,980
就算用的魚餌不對
Even with the wrong knots.

42
00:02:49,020 --> 00:02:50,980
天啊
Oh god.

43
00:02:52,720 --> 00:02:55,490
看來不准哭的規則不管用了
So much for the no crying rule.

44
00:02:55,940 --> 00:02:58,460
我想是爸爸比魚更重要
I think that was more for dad than the fish.

45
00:03:47,430 --> 00:03:49,090
YYeTs人人影視誠意奉獻

46
00:03:51,230 --> 00:03:52,900
翻譯 海因裡希 原子蛋

47
00:03:54,510 --> 00:03:56,330
翻譯 Tiberius 點點點

48
00:03:56,340 --> 00:03:58,200
翻譯 NaryKing

49
00:04:01,560 --> 00:04:02,760
時間軸 之間

50
00:04:02,760 --> 00:04:03,860
校對 海因裡希

51
00:04:03,860 --> 00:04:04,990
後期/特效 WiLL

52
00:04:04,990 --> 00:04:06,160
監製 海因裡希

53
00:04:06,170 --> 00:04:09,170
CHD版個人美化微修：字幕雷哥

54
00:04:17,760 --> 00:04:22,610
走

55
00:04:18,510 --> 00:04:22,610
肉

56
00:04:18,860 --> 00:04:22,610
行屍

57
00:04:18,860 --> 00:04:22,610
『第一季 第四集』

58
00:04:42,630 --> 00:04:43,930
我可不會猶豫
I won't hesitate.

59
00:04:43,930 --> 00:04:47,200
我不在乎槍聲引來城裡的行屍
I don't care if every walker in the city hears it.

60
00:05:01,950 --> 00:05:04,980
你有抹布什麼的麼
You got a do-rag or something?

61
00:05:21,230 --> 00:05:24,670
我想這鋸子太鈍了　鋸不斷手銬
I guess the saw blade was too dull for the handcuffs.

62
00:05:26,810 --> 00:05:29,210
真他媽見鬼
Ain't that a bitch.

63
00:05:53,270 --> 00:05:56,500
他肯定拿了東西止血　也許是他的皮帶
He must have used a tourniquet-- maybe his belt.

64
00:05:56,540 --> 00:05:58,640
不然不會只有這麼點血跡
Be much more blood if he didn't.

65
00:06:29,840 --> 00:06:32,670
莫爾　你在嗎
Merle? You in here?

66
00:06:50,120 --> 00:06:53,120
吉姆　你沒事吧
Jim? You okay?

67
00:06:59,000 --> 00:07:02,270
你再這麼下去會暈過去
You keep this up, you're gonna keel over out here.

68
00:07:07,610 --> 00:07:09,310
好歹喝點水吧
Drink some water at least.

69
00:07:46,580 --> 00:07:50,250
他一個人擺平兩隻醜八怪綽綽有餘
Had enough in him to take out these two sumbitchs.

70
00:07:51,450 --> 00:07:53,120
只用一隻手
One handed.

71
00:07:55,550 --> 00:07:57,920
我哥真是我見過的最牛逼的小強
Toughest asshole I ever met, my brother.

72
00:07:59,560 --> 00:08:01,860
他用起錘子能把個釘子砸爛
Feed him a hammer, he'd crap out nails.

73
00:08:01,890 --> 00:08:04,000
失這麼多血　是人都撐不過去
Any man can pass out from blood loss,

74
00:08:04,030 --> 00:08:06,300
不管他再怎麼強悍
No matter how tough he is.

75
00:08:11,470 --> 00:08:13,140
寶貝兒　看看那個
Oh, baby. Will you look at that?

76
00:08:13,170 --> 00:08:14,460
大家看啊
Hey, check it out.

77
00:08:18,010 --> 00:08:19,480
女士們
Ladies...

78
00:08:19,510 --> 00:08:22,850
多虧了你們　我的孩子晚上有的吃了
...Because of you my children will eat tonight.

79
00:08:22,880 --> 00:08:24,820
-謝了　-謝戴爾吧
- Thank you. - Thank Dale.

80
00:08:24,850 --> 00:08:26,880
他貢獻的船和裝備
It's his canoe and gear.

81
00:08:26,920 --> 00:08:29,020
媽媽　看呀　這麼多魚
Mom, look. Look at all the fish.

82
00:08:29,620 --> 00:08:31,020
謝了
Thank you.

83
00:08:33,030 --> 00:08:36,130
可不是　你倆從哪兒學的
Yeah, whoa. Where did you two learn to do that?

84
00:08:36,160 --> 00:08:38,800
-爸爸教的　-你們能教我嗎
- Our dad. - Can you teach me how to do that?

85
00:08:38,830 --> 00:08:42,030
當然　我會教你打繩結等等的本事
Sure. I'll teach you all about nail knots and stuff.

86
00:08:42,710 --> 00:08:44,970
-如果你同意　-我可沒什麼意見
- If that's okay. - You won't catch me arguing.

87
00:08:45,620 --> 00:08:48,940
戴爾　你多久沒給捲筒加油了
Hey, Dale. When's the last time you oiled those line reels?

88
00:08:48,970 --> 00:08:51,680
-都不管用了　-那個
- They are a disgrace. - I, uh,

89
00:08:51,710 --> 00:08:53,810
我不想嚇著大家
I don't want to alarm anyone,

90
00:08:53,850 --> 00:08:56,580
但我們好像有點麻煩
But we may have a bit of a problem.

91
00:09:11,960 --> 00:09:14,600
-莫爾　-這裡不光只有我們
- Merle! - We're not alone here.

92
00:09:14,630 --> 00:09:16,700
-記得嗎　-去他媽的
- Remember? - Screw that.

93
00:09:17,420 --> 00:09:19,570
他可能失血過多　你自己說的
He could be bleeding out. You said so yourself.

94
00:09:38,890 --> 00:09:41,230
這被燒焦的什麼玩意
What's that burned stuff?

95
00:09:41,930 --> 00:09:43,800
人的皮膚
Skin.

96
00:09:44,480 --> 00:09:45,960
他燒灼了殘肢
He cauterized the stump.

97
00:09:50,200 --> 00:09:52,170
我就說他很強悍
Told you he was tough.

98
00:09:52,200 --> 00:09:54,210
沒人能殺得死他
Nobody can kill Merle but Merle.

99
00:09:54,240 --> 00:09:57,140
別這麼想當然　他流了很多血
Don't take that on faith. He's lost a lot of blood.

100
00:09:57,180 --> 00:09:58,810
是嗎
Yeah?

101
00:09:59,210 --> 00:10:02,050
他還不是照樣從這絕境中逃了出去
Didn't stop him from busting out of this death trap.

102
00:10:03,180 --> 00:10:04,280
他從這幢樓逃走了嗎
He left the building?

103
00:10:04,320 --> 00:10:05,950
見鬼的他幹嘛這麼幹
Why the hell would he do that?

104
00:10:06,480 --> 00:10:07,420
不然還能怎樣
Why wouldn't he?

105
00:10:07,890 --> 00:10:10,110
在他看來　他被丟下一個人
He's out there alone as far as he knows,

106
00:10:11,260 --> 00:10:12,960
他不過是按本能行動
Doing what he's got to do.

107
00:10:13,290 --> 00:10:14,730
為了活下去
Surviving.

108
00:10:15,390 --> 00:10:17,730
你覺得這樣能活下去
You call that surviving?

109
00:10:17,760 --> 00:10:20,300
在大街上閒晃　昏過去了怎麼辦
Just wandering out in the streets, maybe passing out?

110
00:10:20,330 --> 00:10:21,800
他在外面有出路嗎
What are his odds out there?

111
00:10:21,800 --> 00:10:22,710
總比被你們幾個天殺的
No worse than being

112
00:10:22,710 --> 00:10:25,780
銬在屋頂上爛掉來的好
handcuffed and left to rot by you sorry pricks.

113
00:10:27,990 --> 00:10:29,390
你殺不了他
You couldn't kill him.

114
00:10:29,920 --> 00:10:32,740
外面那些個蠢蛋活死人能殺得了他嗎
Ain't so worried about some dumb dead bastard.

115
00:10:32,780 --> 00:10:34,650
那1000只活死人呢
What about 1,000 dead dumb bastards?

116
00:10:34,680 --> 00:10:37,120
-會怎麼樣　-你幹嘛不去算賬
- Different story? - Why don't you take a tally?

117
00:10:37,150 --> 00:10:39,480
隨你怎麼說　我要去找他
Do what you want. I'm gonna go get him.

118
00:10:39,520 --> 00:10:41,790
-達裡爾　等等　-拿開你的手
- Daryl, wait. - Get your hands off me!

119
00:10:41,820 --> 00:10:43,790
-你阻止不了我　-我不怪你
- You can't stop me. - I don't blame you.

120
00:10:43,820 --> 00:10:46,490
他是你家人　我能理解　我也歷經千辛才找到我的家人
He's family, I get that. I went through hell to find mine.

121
00:10:46,850 --> 00:10:48,290
我相當理解你的感受
I know exactly how you feel.

122
00:10:50,360 --> 00:10:52,030
受了這種傷　他走不了多遠
He can't get far with that injury.

123
00:10:52,060 --> 00:10:53,800
我們可以到附近找一找
We could help you check a few blocks around

124
00:10:53,830 --> 00:10:56,530
但我們必須保持清醒
but only if we keep a level head.

125
00:10:58,770 --> 00:11:00,740
這倒不難
I could do that.

126
00:11:04,030 --> 00:11:06,240
得先拿到槍才行
Only if we get those guns first.

127
00:11:06,280 --> 00:11:07,980
就算出於好心
I'm not strolling the streets of Atlanta

128
00:11:08,010 --> 00:11:10,210
我也不在街上亂串　明白嗎
with just my good intentions, okay?

129
00:11:30,870 --> 00:11:32,700
吉姆
Hey, Jim.

130
00:11:35,040 --> 00:11:36,740
吉姆　先停一下好嗎
Jim, why don't you hold up, all right?

131
00:11:36,780 --> 00:11:39,540
-跟你說幾句　-幹什麼
- Just give me a second here, please. - What do you want?

132
00:11:39,970 --> 00:11:42,310
大家都有點擔心你
We're all just a little concerned, that's all.

133
00:11:42,350 --> 00:11:44,850
戴爾說你挖了幾個鐘頭了
Dale says you've been out here for hours.

134
00:11:45,440 --> 00:11:47,790
-那又怎樣　-你幹嘛挖坑
- So? - So why are you digging?

135
00:11:49,720 --> 00:11:51,890
挖地道去中國嗎　吉姆
Are you heading to China, Jim?

136
00:11:51,920 --> 00:11:54,690
礙你什麼事　我又不傷人
What does it matter? I'm not hurting anyone.

137
00:11:54,730 --> 00:11:56,230
可你這樣會傷了自己
Yeah, except maybe yourself.

138
00:11:56,260 --> 00:11:59,660
今天三十七度高溫呢　你不能這麼一直挖
It's 100 degree today. You can't keep this up.

139
00:11:59,700 --> 00:12:01,730
我可以挖　挖給你看
Sure I can. Watch me.

140
00:12:01,770 --> 00:12:04,140
吉姆　他們不好直說　我來說吧
Jim, they're not gonna say it so I will.

141
00:12:04,550 --> 00:12:06,600
你嚇到別人了
You're scaring people.

142
00:12:06,640 --> 00:12:09,210
你嚇到我兒子和卡蘿爾的女兒
You're scaring my son and Carol's daughter.

143
00:12:10,100 --> 00:12:12,580
沒什麼好怕的
They got nothing to be scared of.

144
00:12:14,370 --> 00:12:15,610
我說你們到底怎麼了
I mean, what the hell, people?

145
00:12:15,650 --> 00:12:17,650
我自己要來這裡　你們走開
I'm out here by myself. Why don't you all just go

146
00:12:17,680 --> 00:12:20,850
讓我一個人待著行嗎
and leave me the hell alone?

147
00:12:21,460 --> 00:12:24,060
我們覺得你該休息一下
We think that you need to take a break, okay?

148
00:12:24,090 --> 00:12:26,560
去樹蔭下涼快一下
Why don't you go and get yourself in the shade?

149
00:12:26,590 --> 00:12:28,490
吃點東西什麼　說不定
Some food maybe. I'll tell you what--

150
00:12:28,530 --> 00:12:30,830
過會兒我也過來
Maybe in a little bit I'll come out here

151
00:12:31,480 --> 00:12:33,060
幫你一起挖
and help you myself.

152
00:12:33,100 --> 00:12:35,000
吉姆　說說到底怎麼了
Jim, just tell me what it's about.

153
00:12:35,030 --> 00:12:36,930
去休息吧　把鏟子給我
Why don't you just go ahead and give me that shovel?

154
00:12:36,970 --> 00:12:39,400
-不然什麼後果　-沒什麼後果
- Or what? - There is no or what.

155
00:12:39,440 --> 00:12:42,710
我在請求你　我是來請求你
I'm asking you. I'm coming to you and I'm asking you, please.

156
00:12:42,740 --> 00:12:44,410
我不想去搶你的鏟子
I don't want to have to take it from you.

157
00:12:44,440 --> 00:12:47,310
我要是不給呢
And if I don't, then what?

158
00:12:48,160 --> 00:12:50,010
你就過來揍我
Then you're gonna beat my face in

159
00:12:50,050 --> 00:12:52,250
就像揍愛德·佩爾蒂埃那樣
like Ed Peletier, aren't you?

160
00:12:52,280 --> 00:12:55,060
你們都瞧見他的臉了吧　被揍成啥樣了都
Y'all seen his face, huh? What's left of it.

161
00:12:56,320 --> 00:12:58,760
跟你過不去就是那個下場
See, now that's what happens when someone crosses you.

162
00:12:59,590 --> 00:13:00,730
情況不一樣　吉姆
That was different, Jim.

163
00:13:00,760 --> 00:13:02,880
你又不在場　當時愛德失控了
You weren't there. Ed was out of control.

164
00:13:02,890 --> 00:13:04,130
他在打他妻子
He was hurting his wife.

165
00:13:04,160 --> 00:13:06,170
那是別人的家事　關他屁事
That is their marriage. That is not his.

166
00:13:06,170 --> 00:13:09,230
他又不是法官　誰選你當老大了
He is not judge and jury. Who voted you king boss, huh?

167
00:13:09,270 --> 00:13:11,070
吉姆　我不是來跟你吵架
Jim, I'm not here to argue with you, all right?

168
00:13:11,100 --> 00:13:13,200
-把鏟子給我好嗎　-不行
- Just give me the shovel, okay? - No no no.

169
00:13:13,240 --> 00:13:14,810
給我　吉姆
Just give me the-- Jim! -

170
00:13:16,070 --> 00:13:18,010
-好了安靜　-你沒權利
- Okay, shh shh. - You got no right!

171
00:13:18,040 --> 00:13:19,740
-淡定　-你沒權利
- Stop. - You got no right!

172
00:13:19,780 --> 00:13:21,710
吉姆　淡定
Jim, just stop it.

173
00:13:21,750 --> 00:13:23,950
-放開我　-吉姆　沒人會傷害你
- Don't! - Jim. Jim, nobody's gonna hurt you.

174
00:13:23,980 --> 00:13:25,880
聽到嗎
You hear me?

175
00:13:25,920 --> 00:13:28,390
吉姆　沒人會傷害你　好嗎
Jim, nobody is gonna hurt you, okay?

176
00:13:28,420 --> 00:13:31,390
說謊　彌天大謊
That's a lie. That's the biggest lie there is.

177
00:13:31,420 --> 00:13:34,860
我對我妻子和兩個兒子也這麼說
I told that to my wife and my two boys.

178
00:13:34,890 --> 00:13:38,630
說了幾百次　不頂用
I said it 100 times. It didn't matter.

179
00:13:38,660 --> 00:13:41,970
不知從哪冒出了一大堆行屍
They came out of nowhere. There were dozens of'em.

180
00:13:44,140 --> 00:13:45,840
把他們從我身邊拉走了
Just pulled'em right out of my hands.

181
00:13:51,240 --> 00:13:53,040
我能逃走　只是因為
You know, the only reason I got away was

182
00:13:53,080 --> 00:13:55,710
那些行屍只顧著吃我的家人
'cause the dead were too busy eating my family.

183
00:14:03,920 --> 00:14:05,490
你不能單獨行動
You're not doing this alone.

184
00:14:05,520 --> 00:14:07,830
我不太爽你　連我都覺得這樣不好
Even I think it's a bad idea and I don't even like you much.

185
00:14:07,860 --> 00:14:11,460
這主意能行　你先聽我說完
It's a good idea, okay, if you just hear me out.

186
00:14:12,260 --> 00:14:14,030
如果我們一起走出去
If we go out there in a group,

187
00:14:14,070 --> 00:14:16,030
會走得很慢　還引起注意
we're slow, drawing attention.

188
00:14:16,070 --> 00:14:19,000
如果我單獨行動　反而更加靈活
If I'm alone, I can move fast.

189
00:14:20,220 --> 00:14:21,840
瞧
Look.

190
00:14:21,870 --> 00:14:24,910
坦克在這　離這有五個街區
That's the tank, five blocks from where we are now.

191
00:14:25,470 --> 00:14:26,780
裝槍的袋子在這
That's the bag of guns.

192
00:14:26,810 --> 00:14:29,180
這是第一次見面時　我拉你走進的巷子
Here's the alley I dragged you into when we first met.

193
00:14:29,210 --> 00:14:31,350
-我和達裡爾就去那裡　-怎麼是我
- That's where Daryl and I will go. - Why me?

194
00:14:31,380 --> 00:14:33,620
十字弩比槍聲音小些
Your crossbow is quieter than his gun.

195
00:14:37,590 --> 00:14:39,090
達裡爾在巷子裡等著
While Daryl waits here in the alley,

196
00:14:39,120 --> 00:14:40,890
我到街上去　把袋子拿來
I run up the street, grab the bag.

197
00:14:41,370 --> 00:14:42,530
我們去別的地方嗎
You got us elsewhere?

198
00:14:42,560 --> 00:14:43,890
是的　你和T仔
You and T-dog, right.

199
00:14:44,780 --> 00:14:45,930
你們到這個巷子來
You'll be in this alley here.

200
00:14:45,960 --> 00:14:47,600
隔兩個街區　為什麼
Two blocks away? Why?

201
00:14:47,630 --> 00:14:49,600
以防我不能按原路返回
I may not be able to come back the same way.

202
00:14:50,100 --> 00:14:51,570
行屍可能會阻斷我去路
Walkers might cut me off.

203
00:14:51,930 --> 00:14:54,110
這樣的話　我就不能回達裡爾那兒
If that happens, I won't go back to Daryl.

204
00:14:54,450 --> 00:14:56,140
只能繼續往前走
I'll go forward instead,

205
00:14:56,170 --> 00:14:58,540
走到你們所在的巷子
all the way around to that alley where you guys are.

206
00:14:59,180 --> 00:15:00,380
不管走哪邊
Whichever direction I go,

207
00:15:00,410 --> 00:15:03,380
你們都能掩護我
I got you in both places to cover me.

208
00:15:03,420 --> 00:15:05,050
完事之後　到這裡匯合
Afterwards, we'll all meet back here.

209
00:15:05,440 --> 00:15:07,520
小子　你之前是幹什麼的
Hey, kid, what'd you do before all this?

210
00:15:08,160 --> 00:15:11,290
送比薩的　怎麼了
Delivered pizzas. Why?

211
00:15:41,950 --> 00:15:43,990
你個中國人膽兒挺肥啊
You got some balls for a Chinaman.

212
00:15:44,020 --> 00:15:46,560
-我是韓國人　-無所謂
- I'm Korean. - Whatever.

213
00:16:16,120 --> 00:16:18,090
喂　別射　你想怎樣
Whoa, don't shoot me! What do you want?

214
00:16:18,120 --> 00:16:20,590
我在找我哥哥　他受了重傷　你見過他嗎
I'm looking for my brother. He's hurt real bad. You seen him?

215
00:16:20,630 --> 00:16:21,960
-救命[西班牙語]　-閉嘴
- Ayudame! - Shut up!

216
00:16:21,990 --> 00:16:24,030
你會把殭屍都招來　快說
You're gonna bring the geeks down on us. Answer me.

217
00:16:36,010 --> 00:16:38,810
-說　-救命
- Answer me. - Ayudame!

218
00:16:39,240 --> 00:16:40,590
救命
Ayudame!

219
00:16:42,600 --> 00:16:43,820
救命
Ayudame!

220
00:16:44,850 --> 00:16:47,150
閉嘴　別喊了
Shut up. Shut up.

221
00:16:47,190 --> 00:16:49,520
閉嘴
Shut up.

222
00:16:49,550 --> 00:16:51,190
閉嘴
Shut up.

223
00:16:58,300 --> 00:16:59,560
就是那個袋子　哥們
That's it. That's the bag, vato.

224
00:16:59,600 --> 00:17:01,770
搶過來　搶過來
Take it! Take it!

225
00:17:09,840 --> 00:17:13,140
放開我　放開我
Get off me! Get off me!

226
00:17:13,180 --> 00:17:15,680
達裡爾
Daryl!

227
00:17:15,710 --> 00:17:16,880
達裡爾
Daryl!

228
00:17:21,390 --> 00:17:22,120
回來
Come back here,

229
00:17:22,150 --> 00:17:23,950
狗雜種
you son of a bitch!

230
00:17:32,140 --> 00:17:33,660
快住手
Stop it.

231
00:17:33,700 --> 00:17:35,500
老子他媽的要搞死你
I'm gonna kick your nuts up in your throat!

232
00:17:35,530 --> 00:17:37,100
-放開我　-冷靜點
- Let me go. - Chill out.

233
00:17:37,140 --> 00:17:39,100
他們抓走了格倫　那個小混蛋
They took Glenn. That little bastard

234
00:17:39,140 --> 00:17:40,640
還有他那幫混賬同夥
and his little bastard homie friends.

235
00:17:40,670 --> 00:17:42,340
老子要你屁股開花
I'm gonna stomp your ass!

236
00:17:42,370 --> 00:17:44,140
夥計們　行屍把我們包圍了
Guys! Guys! We're cut off!

237
00:17:44,180 --> 00:17:46,840
回實驗室去　快
Get to the lab. Go.

238
00:17:49,880 --> 00:17:51,680
快點　見你鬼的　快走
Come on. Damn, let's go.

239
00:18:05,230 --> 00:18:07,870
吉姆　喝點水嗎
Jim, take some water?

240
00:18:08,330 --> 00:18:09,570
-好　-喝點嗎
- All right. - Yeah?

241
00:18:09,600 --> 00:18:11,600
好的
All right.

242
00:18:14,720 --> 00:18:16,510
給你　哥們
Here you go, bud.

243
00:18:21,930 --> 00:18:23,380
能往我頭上澆點嗎
Pour some on my head?

244
00:18:23,420 --> 00:18:25,050
好
Yeah.

245
00:18:31,920 --> 00:18:33,360
這下頭腦清醒點了吧
Cooling you down, huh?

246
00:18:33,390 --> 00:18:35,160
嗯
Yeah.

247
00:18:39,100 --> 00:18:41,200
你還得這樣綁我多久
How long you gonna keep me like this?

248
00:18:41,230 --> 00:18:43,270
這個嘛
Well, yeah.

249
00:18:43,300 --> 00:18:45,300
等到我覺得你於人於己都不再是威脅
Until I don't think that you're a danger to yourself

250
00:18:45,340 --> 00:18:47,710
到時再放了你
Or others.

251
00:18:54,450 --> 00:18:57,720
如果我嚇到了你們兒子和女兒　我很抱歉
Sorry if I scared your boy and your little girl.

252
00:18:59,280 --> 00:19:01,710
你中暑了　沒人怪你 
You had sunstroke. Nobody's blaming you.

253
00:19:01,750 --> 00:19:03,580
你現在不怕了吧
You're not scared now, are you?

254
00:19:04,500 --> 00:19:05,540
不怕了　先生
No sir.

255
00:19:13,690 --> 00:19:16,060
她說的沒錯　我只是被太陽曬昏了頭
Your mama's right. Sun just cooked my head is all.

256
00:19:16,090 --> 00:19:18,730
吉姆　知不知道你為什麼挖坑
Jim, do you know why you were digging?

257
00:19:21,530 --> 00:19:22,800
能說說嗎
Can you say?

258
00:19:22,830 --> 00:19:25,470
我有理由　就是記不得了
I had a reason. Don't remember.

259
00:19:28,320 --> 00:19:30,370
我昨晚做了個夢
Something I dreamt last night.

260
00:19:35,600 --> 00:19:37,340
也夢到了你爸爸　還有你
Your dad was in it. You were too.

261
00:19:37,370 --> 00:19:39,670
你很為他擔心　其它的就記不得了
You were worried about him. Can't remember the rest.

262
00:19:41,810 --> 00:19:43,340
你是不是很擔心你爸爸
You worried about your dad?

263
00:19:43,950 --> 00:19:46,310
他們還沒回來
They're not back yet.

264
00:19:46,350 --> 00:19:47,700
我們沒必要談這個
We don't need to talk about that.

265
00:19:47,700 --> 00:19:49,790
你爸爸是個警察　小子
Your dad's a police officer, son.

266
00:19:50,860 --> 00:19:51,950
他樂於助人
He helps people.

267
00:19:51,980 --> 00:19:54,850
沒準是路上拔刀相助了一下耽擱了　沒啥大不了
Probably just came across some folks needing help, that's all.

268
00:19:54,890 --> 00:19:57,590
這人吶　強得很
That man, he is tough as nails.

269
00:19:58,580 --> 00:20:00,590
我跟他不熟　但是…
I don't know him well but...

270
00:20:01,760 --> 00:20:03,560
我看得出來
I could see it in him.

271
00:20:03,600 --> 00:20:04,960
對不對
Am I right?

272
00:20:05,930 --> 00:20:07,170
絕對
Oh yeah.

273
00:20:10,470 --> 00:20:12,770
這世上沒有任何東西能阻止他回到
There ain't nothing gonna stop him from getting back here

274
00:20:12,800 --> 00:20:14,910
你還有你媽媽身邊　我向你保證
To you and your mom, I promise you that.

275
00:20:20,550 --> 00:20:22,280
很好
All right.

276
00:20:22,310 --> 00:20:24,680
誰想來幫我清理魚肉
Who wants to help me clean some fish, huh?

277
00:20:24,720 --> 00:20:26,620
好耶　來吧　索菲亞
Sweet. Come on, Sophia.

278
00:20:26,650 --> 00:20:29,190
跟緊卡蘿爾　好麼
Stay with Carol, all right?

279
00:20:48,840 --> 00:20:50,810
你好好看著你兒子
You keep your boy close.

280
00:20:50,840 --> 00:20:53,880
千萬別讓他離開你視線
You don't ever let him out of your sight.

281
00:21:03,620 --> 00:21:06,160
那些和你一起的人　快說他們去哪了
Those men you were with, we need to know where they went.

282
00:21:06,830 --> 00:21:08,230
我才不跟你說
I ain't telling you nothing.

283
00:21:08,260 --> 00:21:11,330
老天　當時到底怎麼回事
Jesus, man. What the hell happened back there?

284
00:21:11,360 --> 00:21:13,760
我說了　這小賤人和他的傻逼哥們
I told you, this little turd and his douche bag friends

285
00:21:13,800 --> 00:21:15,500
不知道從哪冒出來暴打我一頓
Came out of nowhere and jumped me.

286
00:21:15,530 --> 00:21:17,570
分明是你找我的碴　媽的
You're the one who jumped me, puto,

287
00:21:17,600 --> 00:21:18,540
吵著要找自己老哥
Screaming about trying

288
00:21:18,540 --> 00:21:20,400
還倒過來說是我的錯
to find his brother like it's my damn fault.

289
00:21:20,440 --> 00:21:22,710
他們抓走了格倫　也可能抓走了莫爾
They took Glenn. Could have taken Merle too.

290
00:21:22,740 --> 00:21:25,140
莫爾　這是啥鳥名字
Merle? What kind of hick name is that?

291
00:21:25,180 --> 00:21:27,210
我連自己的狗也不叫莫爾
I wouldn't name my dog Merle.

292
00:21:27,250 --> 00:21:29,610
-馬勒隔壁　-達裡爾　走開
- Damn it, - Daryl. Back off.

293
00:21:36,660 --> 00:21:39,420
想知道上個惹毛我的人最後怎麼了嗎
Want to see what happened to the last guy that pissed me off?

294
00:21:47,570 --> 00:21:50,570
這次從腳來
Start with the feet this time.

295
00:21:54,170 --> 00:21:56,110
你們抓走的那個人是我們朋友
The men you were with took our friend.

296
00:21:56,140 --> 00:21:57,580
我們只是想跟他們談談
All we want to do is talk to them,

297
00:21:57,610 --> 00:21:59,040
看我們能不能協商解決
See if we can work something out.

298
00:22:08,140 --> 00:22:09,390
你確定你準備好了嗎
You sure you're up for this?

299
00:22:09,800 --> 00:22:11,720
-好　-行
- Yeah.　- Okay.

300
00:22:15,060 --> 00:22:16,280
亂動一下
One wrong move,

301
00:22:16,280 --> 00:22:18,800
就讓你屁股上多枝箭　自己注意點
You get an arrow in the ass. Just so you know.

302
00:22:18,830 --> 00:22:20,970
阿吉會把那箭拔出來
G's gonna take that arrow out of my ass

303
00:22:21,000 --> 00:22:23,600
插到你屁股上去　你也給我注意點
And shove it up yours. Just so you know.

304
00:22:23,640 --> 00:22:26,270
-阿吉是誰　-吉列爾莫
- G? - Guillermo.

305
00:22:26,310 --> 00:22:27,870
他是這兒的老大
He's the man here.

306
00:22:28,310 --> 00:22:29,240
那好
Okay then.

307
00:22:29,960 --> 00:22:31,610
讓我們去會會吉列爾莫
Let's go see guillermo.

308
00:23:23,940 --> 00:23:25,160
你還好吧　小兄弟
You okay, little man?

309
00:23:25,480 --> 00:23:28,330
他們要剁了我的腳哇　老大
They're gonna cut off my feet, Carnal.

310
00:23:29,170 --> 00:23:30,000
條子也這麼狠
Cops do that?

311
00:23:30,600 --> 00:23:33,000
不是他　是這個傻逼鄉巴佬
Not him. This redneck puto here.

312
00:23:33,040 --> 00:23:35,110
他砍下了一個人的手　還拿給我看
He cut off some dude's hand, man. He showed it to me.

313
00:23:35,140 --> 00:23:37,980
-閉嘴　-就是那個男的　弟兄們
- Shut up. - Hey, that's that vato right there, homes.

314
00:23:38,010 --> 00:23:40,280
他給了我屁股一箭　想怎樣
He shot me in the ass with an arrow. What's up, homes, huh?

315
00:23:40,310 --> 00:23:42,480
冷靜　淡定　都冷靜
Chill, ease, chill. Chill.

316
00:23:44,450 --> 00:23:45,950
真有這事
This true?

317
00:23:46,450 --> 00:23:48,390
他要剁了小米蓋爾的腳
He wants Miguelito's feet?

318
00:23:48,420 --> 00:23:49,890
真變態　哥們
That's pretty sick, man.

319
00:23:49,920 --> 00:23:52,820
我們是想來和平地談談
We were hoping more for a calm discussion.

320
00:23:52,860 --> 00:23:54,690
那鄉巴佬欺負了菲利普的小表弟
That hillbilly jumps Felipe's little cousin,

321
00:23:54,730 --> 00:23:56,190
打了他　還威脅要剁了他腳
Beats on him, threatens to cut off his feet,

322
00:23:56,230 --> 00:23:57,760
菲利普屁股上還中了一箭
Felipe gets an arrow in the ass

323
00:23:58,260 --> 00:24:00,330
你還來搞和平談判
And you want a calm discussion?

324
00:24:01,700 --> 00:24:02,900
你真搞笑
You fascinate me.

325
00:24:02,930 --> 00:24:04,600
當時局勢緊張
Heat of the moment.

326
00:24:04,640 --> 00:24:07,570
雙方都有做錯的地方
Mistakes were made on both sides.

327
00:24:09,430 --> 00:24:11,880
那人到底是你的誰　你倆看著不像是親戚
Who's that dude to you anyway? You don't look related.

328
00:24:12,320 --> 00:24:14,780
不管怎麼說　他是我們自己人　
He's one of our group, more or less.

329
00:24:14,810 --> 00:24:17,010
我肯定你有一些像他那樣的人
I'm sure you have a few like him.

330
00:24:17,490 --> 00:24:19,280
我哥哥也在裡面麼
You got my brother in there?

331
00:24:19,320 --> 00:24:21,820
不好意思　我們這白人賣完了
Sorry, we're fresh out of white boys.

332
00:24:21,850 --> 00:24:24,160
不過亞洲人我還有　有興趣麼
But I've got asian. You interested?

333
00:24:24,190 --> 00:24:26,890
我有一個你們的人　你有一個我們的人
I have one of yours, you have one of mine.

334
00:24:27,570 --> 00:24:29,060
公平交易吧
Sounds like an even trade.

335
00:24:29,090 --> 00:24:32,260
-我怎麼沒覺得　-阿吉
- Don't sound even to me. - G.

336
00:24:32,300 --> 00:24:34,530
-不是吧　-我的人被打了
- Come on, man. - My people got attacked.

337
00:24:34,570 --> 00:24:36,700
他們的湯藥費我找誰要去
Where's the compensation for their pain and suffering?

338
00:24:36,740 --> 00:24:39,000
最關鍵的是　我那袋槍呢
More to the point, where's my bag of guns?

339
00:24:39,040 --> 00:24:41,810
-槍　-小米蓋爾在街上看見的那袋子
- Guns? - The bag Miguel saw in the street.

340
00:24:41,840 --> 00:24:43,710
菲利普和約格打算回去拿的那個
The bag Felipe and Jorge were going back to get.

341
00:24:43,740 --> 00:24:45,710
-那袋槍　-你弄錯了
- That bag of guns. - You're mistaken.

342
00:24:45,740 --> 00:24:48,010
-怎麼錯了　-你說是你的
- I don't think so. - About it being yours.

343
00:24:48,050 --> 00:24:50,510
那可是我的槍
It's my bag of guns.

344
00:24:50,980 --> 00:24:52,480
那袋子就在大街上
The bag was in the street.

345
00:24:52,520 --> 00:24:54,690
誰看見了都能說是自己的
Anybody could come around and say it was theirs.

346
00:24:55,090 --> 00:24:57,860
我難道聽你說啥就是啥
I'm supposed to take your word?

347
00:24:57,890 --> 00:24:59,760
何不讓我的人放下對著你們腦門的槍
What's to stop my people from unloading on you

348
00:24:59,790 --> 00:25:01,630
然後讓我拿走本就是我的東西
right here and now and I take what's mine?

349
00:25:04,200 --> 00:25:06,130
你大可以這麼做
You could do that.

350
00:25:08,730 --> 00:25:09,640
也未必
Or not.

351
00:25:12,300 --> 00:25:15,140
得了　快點交易啊
Come on, man. Make the trade.

352
00:25:15,170 --> 00:25:17,040
拜託了
Please.

353
00:25:18,740 --> 00:25:20,440
喂喂
Oye.

354
00:25:34,660 --> 00:25:36,260
二選一
I see two options.

355
00:25:36,580 --> 00:25:38,800
你帶著小米蓋爾和那袋槍回來
You come back with Miguel and my bag of guns,

356
00:25:38,830 --> 00:25:40,530
大家都沒事
Everybody walks.

357
00:25:40,570 --> 00:25:42,730
要麼你們全副武裝過來
Or you come back locked and loaded,

358
00:25:42,770 --> 00:25:45,000
來個一決雌雄看看誰比誰狠
We'll see which side spills more blood.

359
00:26:07,060 --> 00:26:08,650
槍可比金子還管用
Them guns are worth more than gold.

360
00:26:09,080 --> 00:26:11,870
金子保不了你全家小命或是給你吃的
Gold won't protect your family or put food on the table.

361
00:26:13,020 --> 00:26:15,080
你要為那小子放棄這些嗎
You're gonna give that up for that kid?

362
00:26:15,850 --> 00:26:17,980
如果這能換回格倫　我是贊成
If I knew we'd get Glenn back, I might agree.

363
00:26:18,370 --> 00:26:20,620
但你覺得那哥們會守信用嗎
But you think that vato across the way is just gonna hand him over?

364
00:26:20,650 --> 00:26:22,820
-你們說阿吉是騙子嗎　-關你屁事
- You calling G a liar?　- Are you a part of this?

365
00:26:22,860 --> 00:26:24,920
你想挨揍嗎
You want to hold onto your teeth?

366
00:26:27,590 --> 00:26:29,730
問題是　你信那傢伙嗎
Question is, do you trust that man's word?

367
00:26:29,760 --> 00:26:32,030
不　問題在於你願意拿啥去賭
No, question is what are you willing to bet on it?

368
00:26:32,070 --> 00:26:34,800
可能不止那些槍　還要搭上你的命
Could be more than them guns. Could be your life.

369
00:26:35,490 --> 00:26:36,870
格倫值得你這麼做嗎
Glenn worth that to you?

370
00:26:39,170 --> 00:26:41,810
我欠他一條命
What life I have I owe to him.

371
00:26:42,180 --> 00:26:43,540
格倫之前根本不認識我
I was nobody to Glenn,

372
00:26:43,580 --> 00:26:46,410
我只是個困在坦克裡的白癡
just some idiot stuck in a tank.

373
00:26:46,450 --> 00:26:48,650
他完全可以撒手不管　但他沒有
He could have walked away, but he didn't.

374
00:26:49,180 --> 00:26:50,180
我也不會丟下他
Neither will I.

375
00:26:50,220 --> 00:26:51,750
那你想把槍交出去嗎
So you're gonna hand the guns over?

376
00:26:53,300 --> 00:26:54,390
我可沒說
I didn't say that.

377
00:26:57,160 --> 00:26:58,820
這裡沒你們的事了
There's nothing keeping you two here.

378
00:26:58,860 --> 00:27:00,960
你們走吧　回營地去
You should get out, head back to camp.

379
00:27:00,990 --> 00:27:02,530
要我們怎麼跟你家人交代
And tell your family what?

380
00:27:15,210 --> 00:27:17,480
拜託　你們簡直瘋了
Come on, this is nuts.

381
00:27:21,880 --> 00:27:23,650
照阿吉說的去做
Just do like G says.

382
00:27:54,920 --> 00:27:58,280
槍我是看到了　但沒有都放在包裡
I see my guns but they're not all in the bag.

383
00:27:58,320 --> 00:28:00,190
因為這不是你的槍
That's because they're not yours.

384
00:28:00,220 --> 00:28:01,950
我說過吧
I thought I mentioned that.

385
00:28:01,990 --> 00:28:03,960
我們幹嘛不一槍斃了這些傻子
Let's just shoot these fools right now, ese. All right?

386
00:28:03,990 --> 00:28:05,620
打個他們屁股開花
Unload on their asses, ese.

387
00:28:05,660 --> 00:28:09,430
我看你們還沒搞清事情的嚴重性
I don't think you fully appreciate the gravity of the situation.

388
00:28:09,460 --> 00:28:11,360
清楚得很
No, I'm pretty clear.

389
00:28:14,070 --> 00:28:17,870
你的人還你了　我要我的人
You have your man. I want mine.

390
00:28:20,710 --> 00:28:23,980
我要把那小子切片　用來餵狗
I'm gonna chop up your boy. I'm gonna feed him to my dogs.

391
00:28:24,010 --> 00:28:27,080
那可是你見過的最凶狠的食人動物
They're the evilest, nastiest man-eating bitches you ever saw.

392
00:28:27,110 --> 00:28:29,080
一次大甩賣時我從惡魔手裡買的
I picked them up from Satan at a yard sale.

393
00:28:30,350 --> 00:28:32,550
我警告過你　你他媽是聾子嗎
I told you how it has to be. Are you woefully deaf?

394
00:28:32,590 --> 00:28:35,450
不　我聽力好得很　你說全副武裝地回來
No, my hearing's fine. You said come locked and loaded.

395
00:28:38,480 --> 00:28:40,090
如你所願　我們來了
Okay then, we're here.

396
00:28:46,480 --> 00:28:49,270
菲利普　菲利普
Felipe! Felipe!

397
00:28:50,910 --> 00:28:54,810
奶奶　快回去和其他人待在一起
Abuela, go back with the others-- now.

398
00:28:54,840 --> 00:28:56,140
快讓那老太婆離開這
Get that old lady out of the line of fire!

399
00:28:56,180 --> 00:28:58,640
奶奶　聽話　好嗎
Abuela, listen to your mijo, okay?

400
00:28:58,680 --> 00:29:00,310
你不應該來在這兒
This is the not the place for you right now.

401
00:29:00,350 --> 00:29:03,580
吉伯特先生呼吸困難
Mr. Gilbert is having trouble breathing.

402
00:29:03,620 --> 00:29:06,320
他要哮喘藥
He needs his asthma stuff.

403
00:29:06,350 --> 00:29:07,950
小卡爾找不到
Carlito didn't find it.

404
00:29:08,650 --> 00:29:10,290
他需要吃藥
He needs his medicine.

405
00:29:13,490 --> 00:29:15,060
菲利普　去把這事解決了
Felipe, go take care of it, okay?

406
00:29:15,100 --> 00:29:16,210
看好你奶奶
And take your grandmother with you.

407
00:29:18,810 --> 00:29:21,330
他們是什麼人
Who are those men?

408
00:29:21,370 --> 00:29:24,070
別把他帶走
Don't you take him.

409
00:29:24,100 --> 00:29:26,340
-老奶奶　-菲利普是個好孩子
- Ma'am? - Felipe's a good boy.

410
00:29:26,370 --> 00:29:29,580
他有他的缺點　但他已經很努力了
He have his trouble but he pull himself together.

411
00:29:29,970 --> 00:29:32,540
我們需要他
We need him here.

412
00:29:33,320 --> 00:29:34,950
老奶奶
Ma'am,

413
00:29:35,470 --> 00:29:37,350
我不是來逮捕他的
I'm not here to arrest your grandson.

414
00:29:37,380 --> 00:29:39,350
那你們找他幹什麼
Then what do you want him for?

415
00:29:40,250 --> 00:29:42,350
他在
He's...

416
00:29:42,840 --> 00:29:44,520
幫我們找一個失蹤的人
helping us find a missing person.

417
00:29:45,080 --> 00:29:46,060
一個叫格倫的小伙子
Fella named Glenn.

418
00:29:46,710 --> 00:29:48,660
那個亞裔小伙子嗎
The Asian boy?

419
00:29:49,160 --> 00:29:51,130
他和吉伯特先生在一起
He's with Mr. Gilbert.

420
00:29:51,160 --> 00:29:54,470
來　我帶你去見他
Come. Come, I show you.

421
00:29:54,500 --> 00:29:56,700
他需要吃藥
He needs his medicine.

422
00:29:58,620 --> 00:29:59,740
讓他們過去
Let 'em pass.

423
00:30:29,070 --> 00:30:31,470
奶奶　來吧　帶我去他那兒
Abuela, por favor. Take me to him.

424
00:31:03,740 --> 00:31:05,370
好了
All right.

425
00:31:05,410 --> 00:31:08,010
很簡單　呼吸
Nice and easy. Just breathe.

426
00:31:08,040 --> 00:31:10,240
呼吸　把氣呼出來　呼吸
Just breathe. Just let it out. Just breathe.

427
00:31:13,580 --> 00:31:14,950
放鬆
Just relax.

428
00:31:16,320 --> 00:31:18,920
-這到底是怎麼回事　-哮喘病
- What the hell is this?　- An asthma attack.

429
00:31:19,610 --> 00:31:21,020
會突然呼吸困難
Couldn't get his breath all of a sudden.

430
00:31:21,510 --> 00:31:23,620
我還以為你被拿去餵狗了
I thought you were being eaten by dogs, man.

431
00:31:28,800 --> 00:31:31,200
能跟你說幾句嗎
Could I have a word with you?

432
00:31:31,230 --> 00:31:33,930
你是我見過的最蠢的混蛋
You're the dumbest son of a bitch I ever met.

433
00:31:33,970 --> 00:31:36,900
我們來是準備殺光你們所有人
We walked in there ready to kill every last one of you.

434
00:31:37,350 --> 00:31:39,310
很高興你沒那麼做
Well, I'm glad it didn't go down that way.

435
00:31:39,610 --> 00:31:43,210
如果真的那樣　我要沾上怎樣的血債啊
If it had, that blood would be on my hands.

436
00:31:43,240 --> 00:31:45,440
我不也是嗎　我們會還擊
Mine too. We'd have fought back.

437
00:31:45,480 --> 00:31:47,310
這也不是第一次了
Wouldn't be the first time we've had to.

438
00:31:47,350 --> 00:31:51,080
保護食物　藥物　還有這裡的一切
Protect the food, the medicine-- what's left of it.

439
00:31:51,120 --> 00:31:53,120
這些人　這些老人
These people, the old ones--

440
00:31:53,150 --> 00:31:55,650
這的員工自己跑了　就把他們扔下等死
The staff took off, just left 'em here to die.

441
00:32:00,660 --> 00:32:03,760
只有我和菲利普留下了
Me and Felipe were the only ones who stayed.

442
00:32:04,830 --> 00:32:07,130
你們是什麼人　醫生嗎
What are you, doctors?

443
00:32:07,940 --> 00:32:10,800
菲利普是名護士　特別護理人員
Felipe's a nurse-- a special care provider.

444
00:32:11,820 --> 00:32:13,440
我呢
Me,

445
00:32:13,910 --> 00:32:16,140
我是一名保安
I'm the custodian.

446
00:32:27,920 --> 00:32:29,920
其他人呢
What about the rest of your crew?

447
00:32:30,540 --> 00:32:34,460
這些人都是來探望父母或祖父母
The vatos trickle in to check on their parents, their grandparents.

448
00:32:34,780 --> 00:32:37,560
他們看到這狀況　大多都決定留下來
They see how things are and most decide to stay.

449
00:32:37,600 --> 00:32:40,630
這樣也好　我們需要幫手
It's a good thing too. We need the muscle.

450
00:32:40,670 --> 00:32:44,070
災難降臨後　我們所遇到的人裡
The people we've encountered since things fell apart,

451
00:32:44,100 --> 00:32:46,910
最糟糕的就是掠奪者
The worst kind-- plunderers,

452
00:32:47,530 --> 00:32:48,970
用武力搶奪資源
The kind that take by force.

453
00:32:49,010 --> 00:32:51,840
-我們不是　-我怎麼知道
- That's not who we are.　- How was I to know?

454
00:32:51,880 --> 00:32:55,080
我的人受到攻擊　你還挾持了米蓋爾
My people got attacked and you show up with Miguel hostage--

455
00:32:56,190 --> 00:32:57,620
很明顯嘛
Appearances.

456
00:32:58,690 --> 00:33:00,250
世道變了
Guess the world changed.

457
00:33:00,650 --> 00:33:02,450
沒變
No.

458
00:33:02,490 --> 00:33:05,690
還是和以前一樣　弱肉強食
It's the same as it ever was. The weak get taken.

459
00:33:08,430 --> 00:33:10,030
在這裡我們盡己所能
So we do what we can here.

460
00:33:10,420 --> 00:33:12,200
我們本來想弄幾輛車
The vatos work on those cars,

461
00:33:12,230 --> 00:33:14,170
商量著把這些老人送出城
talk about getting the old people out of the city.

462
00:33:14,540 --> 00:33:16,290
但大部分人連自己上廁所都難
But most can't even get to the bathroom by themselves,

463
00:33:16,290 --> 00:33:17,640
所以這只是紙上談兵
so that is a dream

464
00:33:18,440 --> 00:33:20,570
但大伙還是很忙
Still, it keeps the crew busy,

465
00:33:20,610 --> 00:33:22,510
至少這裡有值得做的事
and that's worth something.

466
00:33:24,470 --> 00:33:25,740
我們把窗戶都封起來
So we barred all the windows,

467
00:33:25,780 --> 00:33:28,080
只留了一個出口　其他都焊死了
Welded all the doors shut except for one entrance.

468
00:33:28,110 --> 00:33:29,620
那些哥們　他們到外面去
The vatos, they go out,

469
00:33:30,140 --> 00:33:32,150
搜尋一些能維持生活的東西
scavenge what they can to keep us going.

470
00:33:33,030 --> 00:33:35,820
我們日夜監視著周邊　一邊等待
We watch the perimeter night and day and we wait.

471
00:33:38,990 --> 00:33:40,530
這裡的人
The people here,

472
00:33:41,430 --> 00:33:44,060
他們都指望我了
They all look to me now.

473
00:33:44,550 --> 00:33:46,630
不知道為什麼
I don't even know why.

474
00:33:48,640 --> 00:33:50,300
因為你靠得住
Because they can.

475
00:34:11,190 --> 00:34:13,990
好吧　回亞特蘭大一趟只撿回頂帽子
Admit it, you only came back to Atlanta for the hat.

476
00:34:14,030 --> 00:34:15,690
別告訴別人
Don't tell anybody.

477
00:34:15,730 --> 00:34:17,700
你把一半的槍支彈藥都給他們了
You've given away half our guns and ammo.

478
00:34:17,730 --> 00:34:19,900
-不到一半　-為了什麼
- Not nearly half.　- For what?

479
00:34:19,930 --> 00:34:22,070
一群隨時會進棺材的死老傢伙們嗎
Bunch of old farts who are gonna die off momentarily anyhow?

480
00:34:22,100 --> 00:34:24,300
說真的　你認為他們還能撐多久
Seriously, how long you think they got?

481
00:34:25,090 --> 00:34:27,140
我們自己又能熬多久
How long do any of us?

482
00:34:30,570 --> 00:34:32,910
-我的神啊　-咱們的貨車死哪去了
- Oh my god. - Where the hell's our van?

483
00:34:32,950 --> 00:34:35,350
-車就停在這　誰會開走　-莫爾
- We left it right there. Who would take it? - Merle.

484
00:34:37,950 --> 00:34:40,490
他肯定回營地報仇了
He's gonna be taking some vengeance back to camp.

485
00:34:51,530 --> 00:34:54,100
包裝紙　彩色紙巾都沒有嗎　　
Wrapping paper, color tissue, anything?

486
00:34:54,760 --> 00:34:55,600
有沒有搞錯
Seriously?

487
00:34:55,640 --> 00:34:57,300
你怎麼連這些都沒有
How can you not have any?

488
00:34:57,340 --> 00:34:59,730
要是有人提前通知會有大災難的話
Had I been informed of the impending apocalypse

489
00:34:59,740 --> 00:35:00,940
我會備些存活
I'd have stocked up.

490
00:35:01,640 --> 00:35:03,610
明天是艾米的生日
It's Amy's birthday tomorrow.

491
00:35:03,640 --> 00:35:06,750
我總會在日曆上標記重要日子以免記錯
I've been marking days on the calendar just to make sure.

492
00:35:09,920 --> 00:35:11,650
禮物不包裝可不行
You don't give a gift unwrapped.

493
00:35:13,220 --> 00:35:14,440
別急
Deep breath.

494
00:35:16,800 --> 00:35:18,420
應該能找到用得上的東西
I'm sure I'll find something here.

495
00:35:26,330 --> 00:35:28,970
我把石頭堆成了一圈
I, uh, built up the rocks all around.

496
00:35:29,000 --> 00:35:31,140
看見沒　這樣火苗就能燒得高一些
See? So the flames can be a little higher

497
00:35:31,720 --> 00:35:32,790
而不用擔心被發現
and have 'em be hidden.

498
00:35:36,140 --> 00:35:37,840
吉姆　現在感覺怎麼樣
Hey, Jim. How you feeling, man?

499
00:35:37,880 --> 00:35:41,080
好些了　恢復得差不多了　　
I'm better. More myself now.

500
00:35:41,110 --> 00:35:43,280
希望你能理解我這麼做的理由…
I hope you understand the need for this--

501
00:35:43,910 --> 00:35:45,550
讓你消停一會
This timeout.

502
00:35:45,590 --> 00:35:48,150
我必須考慮到其他人
I've got others I've got to think about.

503
00:35:48,890 --> 00:35:50,960
我只是想確保你不會有…
I just want to make sure there's no--

504
00:35:51,450 --> 00:35:52,860
有什麼怨恨情緒
There's no hard feelings.

505
00:35:52,890 --> 00:35:55,560
沒有　我完全理解
There's not. I do understand.

506
00:35:55,600 --> 00:35:56,460
那就好
Okay.

507
00:35:58,030 --> 00:36:00,570
過來加入大伙的行列吧
Why don't you come join in with the rest of us?

508
00:36:00,600 --> 00:36:02,600
油炸超級大魚呢
Big ol' fish fry.

509
00:36:04,960 --> 00:36:07,540
-我很樂意　-好
- I'd like that very much. - Okay.

510
00:36:10,910 --> 00:36:12,710
出來跟大伙待在一起吧
Why don't you come outside with everybody?

511
00:36:13,730 --> 00:36:15,350
那些人都給我去死吧
Hell with them people.

512
00:36:15,380 --> 00:36:17,650
他們頭上要是著火了　休想我撒尿滅火
Wouldn't piss on them if their heads were on fire.

513
00:36:19,050 --> 00:36:20,720
站住
Hey!

514
00:36:20,750 --> 00:36:22,990
你給我留在這
Why don't you stay here?

515
00:36:23,020 --> 00:36:24,850
陪著你老爸我
Keep your daddy company.

516
00:36:26,130 --> 00:36:29,690
愛德　她想跟大伙待在一起
Ed, she wants to join in.

517
00:36:29,730 --> 00:36:32,460
-走吧　-真有種
- Come on. - Fine.

518
00:36:32,500 --> 00:36:34,300
都給我滾
Hell with the both of you.

519
00:36:34,330 --> 00:36:36,670
這倒好　耳根清淨　我可以睡個好覺
Ain't no need to be bothering me no more the rest of the night.

520
00:36:47,760 --> 00:36:49,610
請把魚遞過來一下
Pass the fish, please.

521
00:36:49,650 --> 00:36:53,150
-接著　-哇噢　人間美味啊
- Here you go. - Man o man, that's good.

522
00:36:56,100 --> 00:36:57,590
真懷念這味
I miss this.

523
00:37:07,800 --> 00:37:10,770
我得問你個事　我憋得實在是辛苦
I've got to ask you, man. It's been driving me crazy.

524
00:37:10,800 --> 00:37:12,870
-啥事　-那塊表
- What? - That watch.

525
00:37:14,840 --> 00:37:15,960
我這表有啥問題嗎
What's wrong with my watch?

526
00:37:15,960 --> 00:37:21,540
我每天都看你給這玩意上發條
I see you every day, the same time, winding that thing

527
00:37:21,780 --> 00:37:24,150
就跟山村牧師作彌撒一樣堅持不懈
like a village priest saying mass.

528
00:37:24,180 --> 00:37:26,420
這事我私底下也尋思過
I've wondered this myself.

529
00:37:26,450 --> 00:37:27,460
這事有啥好奇怪的　
I'm missing the point.

530
00:37:27,460 --> 00:37:29,240
如果我沒弄錯的話
Unless I've misread the signs,

531
00:37:29,240 --> 00:37:32,660
世界末日貌似已經來臨了
the world seems to have come to an end.

532
00:37:33,110 --> 00:37:35,360
至少這世界已經處於瀕臨狀態很久了
At least hit a speed bump for a good long while.

533
00:37:35,390 --> 00:37:38,630
但你還每天給那破表上發條
But there's you every day winding that stupid watch.

534
00:37:38,660 --> 00:37:41,860
看時間啊　通曉事態很重要不是嗎
Time-- it's important to keep track, isn't it?

535
00:37:41,860 --> 00:37:43,800
至少得知道日期吧
The days at least.

536
00:37:44,970 --> 00:37:46,500
你不覺得嗎　安德莉亞　
Don't you think, Andrea?

537
00:37:46,540 --> 00:37:48,610
挺我一下吧
Back me up here.

538
00:37:53,350 --> 00:37:55,910
我很喜歡…　很喜歡
I like-- I like what, um,

539
00:37:56,910 --> 00:37:59,820
一位父親把傳家手錶傳給兒子時
a father said to son when he gave him a watch

540
00:38:00,430 --> 00:38:03,760
所說的一些話
that had been handed down through generations.

541
00:38:04,100 --> 00:38:05,230
他說
He said,

542
00:38:06,230 --> 00:38:10,400
這塊表是一切希望
"I give you the mausoleum

543
00:38:10,430 --> 00:38:12,770
和慾望的陵墓
of all hope and desire,

544
00:38:12,770 --> 00:38:16,670
它會滿足你的個人需求
which will fit your individual needs

545
00:38:16,700 --> 00:38:19,700
就同它曾經滿足我和我父親的需求一樣
no better than it did mine or my father's before me;

546
00:38:20,000 --> 00:38:22,740
我把表給你
I give it to you

547
00:38:22,780 --> 00:38:26,980
不是要你記住時間
not that you may remember time,

548
00:38:27,010 --> 00:38:30,950
而是讓你可以忘掉時間
but that you may forget it for a moment

549
00:38:31,760 --> 00:38:33,620
偶爾忘掉一次
now and then

550
00:38:33,650 --> 00:38:37,890
而不是費盡心機　想對抗時間流逝
and not spend all of your breath trying to conquer it."

551
00:38:47,270 --> 00:38:49,030
你太非主流了
You are so weird.

552
00:38:50,400 --> 00:38:52,600
這話可不是我說的　是福克納
It's not me. It's Faulkner.

553
00:38:50,400 --> 00:38:52,600
福克納　《喧嘩與騷動》的作者

554
00:38:52,640 --> 00:38:56,140
威廉·福克納　或許是我意譯得不好吧
William Faulkner. Maybe my bad paraphrasing.

555
00:39:02,820 --> 00:39:05,450
-你去哪　-我得去尿尿　
- Where are you going? - I have to pee.

556
00:39:06,010 --> 00:39:08,450
老天　你也太一驚一乍了吧
Jeez, you try to be discreet around here--

557
00:39:15,460 --> 00:39:17,500
我他媽的不是讓你們別來吵我嗎
Thought I told y'all to leave me the hell alone, didn't I?

558
00:39:20,300 --> 00:39:22,200
搞什麼
Hey!

559
00:39:24,750 --> 00:39:26,940
忘記我說什麼了嗎
What'd I say?

560
00:39:30,010 --> 00:39:31,780
廁紙用光了嗎
We're out of toilet paper?

561
00:39:47,330 --> 00:39:50,230
-媽媽　-卡爾
- Mom! - Carl!

562
00:39:52,000 --> 00:39:54,330
洛莉　拉他趴下
Lori, get him down!

563
00:39:59,970 --> 00:40:01,410
我的天吶
Oh my god.

564
00:40:01,440 --> 00:40:03,040
快　快點
Go! Go!

565
00:40:17,360 --> 00:40:19,220
我就在這　肖恩　我們該怎麼辦　
I'm right here. Shane, what do we do?

566
00:40:19,260 --> 00:40:21,730
-肖恩　-跟我來
- Shane? - Follow me!

567
00:40:26,670 --> 00:40:29,070
不　不
No! No!

568
00:40:34,570 --> 00:40:36,510
天吶　我的天吶
Oh god! Oh my god!

569
00:40:36,540 --> 00:40:39,510
救救我
Help me.

570
00:40:39,550 --> 00:40:41,810
天吶　我不知道該怎麼辦
Oh god, I don't know what to do.

571
00:40:41,850 --> 00:40:43,210
我不知道該做什麼
I don't know what to do.

572
00:40:46,320 --> 00:40:48,350
-過來　跟著　跟緊　-卡蘿爾　
- Come on. Come on, stay close. - Carol!

573
00:40:48,390 --> 00:40:49,950
跟緊
Stay close!

574
00:40:59,230 --> 00:41:01,970
大家快點　快到這邊來
Come on, y'all! Work your way up here!

575
00:41:02,000 --> 00:41:04,100
正前方有一個　肖恩
Right in front of you. Shane!

576
00:41:05,100 --> 00:41:07,840
快到房車上去　快
Get to the R.V.! Go!

577
00:41:07,870 --> 00:41:10,580
-肖恩　肖恩　-跟著我
- Shane! Shane! - Stay with me.

578
00:41:12,980 --> 00:41:16,080
跟在我後面　莫拉萊斯　到這邊來　
Stay behind me. Morales, work up here!

579
00:41:16,120 --> 00:41:19,080
-到我後面來　快點　-咱們走
- Get behind me! Come on! - Let's go!

580
00:41:19,120 --> 00:41:20,820
跟著我
Stay with me.

581
00:41:20,850 --> 00:41:23,320
快點　快到溫尼巴格車這邊來
Come on, make your way to the Winnebago!

582
00:41:45,180 --> 00:41:48,110
寶貝　卡爾
Baby! Carl!

583
00:41:48,150 --> 00:41:49,350
寶貝
Baby!

584
00:41:49,380 --> 00:41:51,220
-爸爸　-卡爾
- Dad! - Carl!

585
00:42:20,410 --> 00:42:21,880
艾米
Amy.

586
00:42:29,020 --> 00:42:33,530
我不知道該怎麼辦　艾米
I don't know what to do, Amy.

587
00:43:30,080 --> 00:43:31,750
艾米
Oh, Amy.

588
00:43:46,200 --> 00:43:49,270
不
Oh no no.

589
00:43:51,600 --> 00:43:53,770
艾米
Amy!

590
00:43:55,110 --> 00:43:56,910
艾米
Amy!

591
00:43:56,940 --> 00:43:59,440
艾米
Amy!

592
00:43:59,480 --> 00:44:01,780
我現在想起我做過的夢了
I remember my dream now,

593
00:44:02,930 --> 00:44:04,420
為什麼我要挖這些坑
Why I dug the holes.

